Menu

{NB\_PLAYERS\_CONNECTED} online players: {IN\_GAME} playing • {WAITING} available

If you see this message, it means that your browser failed to load [this file](https://x.boardgamearena.net/data/themereleases/241211-1628/css/mainsite.css).

You should try the following : check your connection, disable ad-blocker, clear your browser cache, try in private mode, try from another browser/computer/connection.

0

https://en.boardgamearena.com/

[Home](https://boardgamearena.com/welcome) » [Community](https://boardgamearena.com/community) » Legal information

 Legal information
------------------

Welcome to the well-known world of Legal Terms, with the very long texts that no-one is brave enough to read!

To help you to navigate, we organized the Legal Terms in sections, and we also introduced some explanations like this one:

This is not part of the Legal terms, but is here to explain something with words you can understand ;)

Legal information

Terms of Use

Terms of Services

Privacy

Cookies

### Legal information

#### 1\. SITE OWNERSHIP AND HOSTING

##### 1.1. Publishing

##### 

**This website is published** by AD2G Studio SAS, a company with a share capital of 100 euros, registered with the Trade and Companies Registry of Nanterre under the number 803 287 150, with its registered office at 18 Rue Jacqueline Auriol 78280 Guyancourt (France), represented by its Managing Director, Mister Alexandre Schlecht, hereinafter referred to as « AD2G Studio ».

Contact: [click here to contact us](https://boardgamearena.com/support)  
Phone number: +33134521970  
VAT number: FR58803287150  
APE / NAF code: 5829C  

**The publishing director** is Mister Alexandre Schlecht.

##### 1.2. Hosting

##### 

This website is hosted by OVH SAS, a company with a share capital of 10 069 020 €, registered with the RCS Lille Métropole 424 761 419 00045 with its registered office at 2 rue Kellermann, 59100 Roubaix (France).

VAT number: FR 22 424 761 419  
APE code: 2620Z  
Phone number: 1007  

##### 1.3. Credit

##### 

This website is developed by AD2G Studio.

Thanks to Hans im Glück for the use of the Meeple (picture), which originates from the game Carcassonne.

#### 2\. PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION

Personal data may be collected and processed via this website by AD2G Studio, acting as data controller within the meaning of the regulations on personal data, including by means of cookies. AD2G Studio's privacy policy can be accessed [by clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac). AD2G Studio's cookie policy is accessible at the same address.

#### 3\. CONTRACTUAL TERMS LINKS

[Confidentiality and cookies policy](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac).

#### 1\. PROPRIETE ET HEBERGEMENT DU SITE

##### 1.1. Edition

##### 

**Le présent site Internet est édité** par la société AD2G Studio SAS au capital de 100 Euros, inscrite au RCS de Nanterre sous le numéro 80 3287 150 00020, dont le siège social est situé 18 Rue Jacqueline Auriol 78280 Guyancourt (France) et représentée par Monsieur Alexandre Schlecht en tant que Directeur Général, ci-après dénommée « AD2G Studio ».

Contact : [cliquer ici pour nous contacter](https://boardgamearena.com/support)  
Numéro de téléphone : +33134521970  
Numéro de TVA : FR58803287150  
Code APE / NAF : 5829C  

**Le directeur de la publication** est Monsieur Alexandre Schlecht.

##### 1.2. Hébergement

##### 

Le présent site est hébergé par OVH SAS au capital de 10 069 020 €, immatriculée au RCS Lille Métropole 424 761 419 00045 dont le siège social est 2 rue Kellermann, 59100 Roubaix (France).

N° TVA : FR 22 424 761 419  
Code APE : 2620Z  
Numéro de téléphone : 1007  

##### 1.3. Crédit

##### 

Le présent site est développé par AD2G Studio.

Merci à Hans im Glück pour l'utilisation du Meeple (image), qui provient du jeu Carcassonne.

#### 2\. PROTECTION DES DONNEES PERSONNELLES

Des données à caractère personnel peuvent être collectées et traitées via le présent site Internet par AD2G Studio, agissant en qualité de responsable de traitement au sens de la règlementation sur les données à caractère personnel, y compris par voie de cookies. La politique de confidentialité de AD2G Studio est accessible [en cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac). La politique de cookies de AD2G Studio est accessible à la même addresse.

#### 3\. LIENS VERS LES CONDITIONS CONTRACTUELLES

[Politique de confidentialité et de cookies](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac).

### Inscription à la CNIL et protection des données personnelles

La société AD2G Studio SAS considère que vos coordonnées sont des données confidentielles, et s’engage à ne pas les divulguer. Vous disposez d’un droit d’accès, de modification, de rectification et de suppression des données qui vous concernent (article 34 de la loi Informatique et libertés n° 78-17 du 6 janvier 1978. Vous pouvez exercer ce droit en [nous contactant](https://boardgamearena.com/support).

Ces données ne sont pas communiquées à d’autres tiers, sous réserve d’une demande formulée par les autorités judiciaires ou administratives habilitées à formuler cette demande.

Le présent site internet est déclaré à la CNIL sous le numéro 2029549.

### Privacy policy

#### Preamble

This Privacy Policy is an integral part of the [General Terms of Use](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) and [Services](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos), so the definitions used in these documents are reused in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy contains the minimum rules that AD2G Studio (hereinafter "BGA", "We", "our") has established with respect to the protection of Personal Data to ensure that the collection, use, retention and communication of your Personal Data is conducted in a fair, transparent and secure manner.

This Privacy Policy sets out our approach to the processing of Personal Data about You that We collect from You or that third parties lawfully provide to Us and the purposes of such processing. It also describes your rights with respect to our processing of your Personal Data.

As data controller within the meaning of the Personal Data Regulations, we may collect Personal Data from You in connection with the use of your Account to access the Applications and use the Services.

#### Definitions

The following terms, whether used in the singular or in the plural in this Privacy Policy, shall have the following definition:

"Account": means the personal space of a User only accessible with Identification Details transmitted by BGA allowing them to access and benefit from the Services;

"Application(s)": means the games accessible from the Developer Site and/or the Player Site, and/or the games accessible only from the Developer Site because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes, published by BGA and/or its Subsidiaries as well as any accessory software which may be necessary, such as an Application update, an Application upgrade, its code (in whole or in part), the files it contains, the associated or generated images and the associated data but also the applications not accessible from the BGA Sites, because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes;

"BGA" / "We" / "us": means the company AD2G Studio SAS, a company with a share capital of 100 euros, registered with the Trade and Companies Registry of Nanterre under the number 803 287 150, with its registered office at 18 Rue Jacqueline Auriol 78280 Guyancourt (France), represented by its President, Mister Alexandre Schlecht and whose contact details are [available here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal);

"BGA Moderation Policy": means the BGA moderation policy, accessible by clicking here https://en.doc.boardgamearena.com/Moderationpolicy ;

"BGA Site(s)": means the Developer Site and/or the Player Site;

"Content": means content of any kind (including textual, visual, video, photographic data, chat rooms, opinions, etc.) published on the BGA Sites through the Services, by a User under their responsibility;

"Data" / "Personal Data": means the personal data of a User or Internet User collected and processed by BGA in the context of the consultation and use of the BGA Sites, such as, where applicable, the creation and management of their Account and the provision of the Services;

"Developer Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address https://studio.boardgamearena.com;

"Identifier": means the connection identifier ("login" or email address) and password defined and/or transmitted in part initially by BGA to the User, who is responsible for changing their password on their first connection and enabling them to access their Account;

"Internet User": refers to all Internet Users, visitors to the BGA Sites, whether or not they have an Account;

"Personal Data Regulations": means Law No. 78-17 of 6 January 1978 relating to data processing, files and freedoms, amended in application of the EU Regulation of 27 April 2016 published in the Official Journal of the European Union on 4 May 2016 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of Personal Data and the free movement of such data (known as "GDPR" for General Data Protection Regulation);

"Player Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address https://boardgamearena.com;

"Privacy Policy": means this privacy policy;

"Receiving medium(s)": means the computers, tablets, smartphones and televisions used to access the BGA Sites and to use the Applications, and which have at least a recent and up-to-date browser;

"Service(s)": means the free features and services made available to Internet Users and accessible from the BGA Sites without an Account, as well as the free or paying features and services, as determined in the Developer G.T.S. and Player G.T.S. accessible from the BGA Sites with an Account to Users and subject to subject to the purchase of a Premium Subscription for paid Services.

"Subsidiary(ies)": means any company or entity that directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by or under common control with BGA. Control of an entity means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or have directed the management or policies of any such entity, whether through ownership of voting securities, by contract or otherwise;

"T&Cs": means the [General Terms of Use](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) and [Services](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos) of the BGA Sites;

"Third Party Account": means an account to which the User has subscribed with a third party publisher and which may be linked to an Account (for example Google or Facebook);

"Username": means a series of characters allowing the User, associated with a password determined by them, to connect uniquely to their Account and to access the Services;

"User(s)" / "You": means any natural person at least fifteen (15) years old who is capable or has parental authorisation to do so, including the legal representative (manager, employee, etc.) of a legal entity acting on its behalf, who opens an Account, using a Receiving Medium, on the Player Site and/or Developer Site and who is not subject to any legal, regulatory or contractual prohibition and/or restriction preventing them from accessing and/or using, from a Receiving Medium, the Applications and/or developing developments and/or assigning developments to BGA and/or performing Translations and/or assigning Translations to BGA and/or distributing Content and having performed, if applicable, all legal, regulatory and contractual formalities to do so, with a view to using the Services;

#### 1\. Who is responsible for processing your Personal Data?

AD2G Studio SAS whose contact details are [available here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) is in charge of processing your Personal Data.

#### 2\. Minimum age

Preserving the safety and privacy of children is very important to Us. We do not voluntarily collect or use Personal Data from individuals under the age of 15 without the consent of both the child and the holder of parental responsibility.

Therefore, You confirm that You are at least 15 years old or older when You provide your Personal Data in connection with the use of our Services. If You are not at least 15 years old, You must request permission from Your parent or legal guardian to provide Us with Your Personal Data.

#### 3\. What Personal Data do we collect?

We collect the following Personal Data about You:

• Identification data such as your Username, if You are over or under 15 years old, your email address for logging into your Account as well as certain data from your third party Account(s) if you choose to associate it/them with your Account;

• Data relating to your personal life such as your first name, surname, and postal address in connection with the creation of your Account on the Developer Site and/or in the context of parental authorisation;

• Data relating to your profile created on the Player Site (avatar, genre, preferred colour, languages spoken and preferences in the sounds assigned to play);

• Connection data when You access the Applications and use the Services (time and location of your activities, username and IP address, browsers and devices used);

• Statistical data and game performance (Application history, preferences of your Applications, progress in Applications, time on Applications);

• Data of the Content that You communicate (in particular through chats, discussion areas, posts on forums, messages, contact forms or other features of the Sites);

• Data relating to your requests for assistance;

• Data relating to the behaviour and reputation of Users.

We do not collect any "sensitive" Personal Data within the meaning of the Personal Data Regulations, in particular data relating to your state of health or which would reveal your alleged racial or ethnic origin, your political opinions, your religious or philosophical beliefs or your trade union membership.

#### 4\. How do we process your Personal Data?

We process your Personal Data for the following purposes. Whenever We process your Personal Data, We do so on the basis of a legal "justification" (or legal basis) for processing, which We have identified in the table below.

|     | Purposes | Legal basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| 1.  | To identify Yourself via your Account | This processing is necessary for the execution of the contract concluded between You and BGA. |
| 2.  | To enable You to access the Services and the Applications | This processing is necessary for the execution of the contract concluded between You and BGA. |
| 3.  | To enable You to communicate on the Applications with other Users | This processing is based on the contract concluded between You and BGA. |
| 4.  | To ensure compliance with the GTC | This processing is based on the contract concluded between You and BGA. |
| 5.  | To enable Us to moderate and/or sanction the behaviour of a User in the context of the Applications | This processing is based on the contract concluded between You and BGA. |
| 6.  | To enable us to detect multi-accounts | This processing is based on BGA's legitimate interest. Indeed, the legitimate interest of the data controller is to ensure a friendly gaming environment by allowing an informational notice to be displayed when two players at the same game table have the same IP address. |
| 7.  | To provide You with commercial information about the Services and/or the Applications | We consider that it is in our legitimate interest to keep Users informed about our Services and Applications accessible from the BGA Sites, as this helps Us to ensure the continuity and development of our business. However, where the law requires BGA to obtain your consent before sending You such information, BGA will rely on your consent to process it. |
| 8.  | In connection with a restructuring operation and/or a merger-acquisition of BGA | We consider it to be in our interest to be able to make informed decisions about the future of our company in order to maintain and develop our business. |
| 9.  | The Content will remain associated with the Username even after deletion of your Account and/or your Personal Data | For the sake of consistency and comprehensibility of the Sites, We consider that it is in our legitimate interest to keep on the Sites your Content associated with the User Name that You have given to your profile during the legal retention periods. You may at any time request the specific deletion of Content that is harmful to a User's interest |
| 10. | For Us to comply with any applicable law, court order, legal process, or requirements of a regulatory body. | This processing is necessary to meet our legal obligations. |
| 11. | To assert our legal rights and obligations and for any legal proceedings involving You, initiated by or against You. | We consider it to be in our legitimate interest to protect our organisation against any breach of a legal obligation owed to it and to defend Ourselves in the event of litigation. |
| 12. | To protect the rights of third parties. | This processing is necessary to comply with the legal obligations to which BGA is subject. This processing is also necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by BGA. We consider that we have a legitimate interest in ensuring that our activities do not infringe the rights of third parties. |
| 13. | To respond to your requests to exercise your rights under the conditions of Article 8 | This processing is necessary to comply with the legal obligations to which BGA is subject. |
| 14. | To provide you with business information about (i) Asmodee's and/or Partners' similar Products and Services (ii) [Asmodee Group](https://cdn.svc.asmodee.net/corporate/uploads/Templates/Asmodee_group_companies_EN.pdf) and/or (iii) third-party partners. | We consider it in our legitimate interest to keep our customers informed about our Products and Services, but also the similar products and services offered by by the group to which we belong, its Partners or third-party partners, as this helps us ensure the sustainability and growth of our businesses. However, where the law requires BGA to obtain your consent before sending you such information, BGA will rely on your consent to proceed with the processing. |
| 15. | To provide you with personalized advertisements on social networks (using as a unique identifier the same email address you may have provided to create your user accounts on both BGA and the social network platforms). | If you are an existing customer and live in a relevant country (e.g., Canada, France, United Kingdom, United States), we consider that we have a legitimate interest in providing you with personalized advertisements about our Products and Services, as well as similar products and services offered by the Asmodee Group, as it helps us to sustain and develop our business.  <br>  <br>However, if you are not an existing customer or if you live in a country where the law requires BGA to obtain your consent before offering you personalized advertisements on social networks (for example, Germany), BGA will rely on your consent in order to proceed with the intended processing. |

In order to ensure compliance with the T&Cs and in particular with the rules of conduct, BGA has implemented a BGA Moderation Policy which allows it to sanction the behaviour of Users concerned

BGA uses automated tools to collect this Personal Data and to detect inappropriate behaviour by Users, in particular with a rating system (Karma score) based on a score of 100, which may vary according to the behaviour detected and, consequently, influence the User's reputation.

BGA also gives Users the opportunity to help it ensure compliance with the G.T. and the BGA Moderation Policy. In particular, on the Player Site, Users can "report" a User's behaviour by using the feature provided for this purpose on the User's profile or by clicking on the "Red Thumb" at the end of a game. These tools enable BGA to apply an automated decision to sanction the User concerned.

In this context, the User concerned receives an email informing them of the sanction taken by BGA against them.

In accordance with the BGA Moderation Policy, Users have the right to appeal the moderation decision that has been applied to them by contacting Us using BGA Contact page.

When You play Applications involving multiple Users, please note that some Personal Data will be made public and therefore accessible to other Users, such as your Username, statistical data and game performance data. The data of the Content published in the context of chats and forums may also be made public to Users and Internet Users.

#### 5\. Who do We share your Personal Data with?

We may share your Personal Data with different categories of recipients, in order to provide You with the Services:

| Internal recipients | External recipients |
| --- | --- |
| Authorized personnel from the marketing department, the departments responsible for customer relations and prospecting, the administrative and legal departments, the logistics and IT departments and their line managers. | \- other Asmodee Group companies;  <br>\- our Partners;  <br>\- social networks (Instagram and Facebook);  <br>\- court officers, if any;  <br>\- authorized personnel of subcontractors (data hosting/storage, software publishers, solutions allowing connection and access to our services, etc.). |

Please note that this list is not exhaustive and there may be other instances where We share your data with third parties where it is in BGA's legitimate interest, permitted by applicable law, or where it is necessary to comply with a legal obligation to which We are subject.

We may share your Personal Information with different categories of third parties, depending on our needs:

1\. Subsidiaries, a list of which is available [by clicking here](https://cdn.svc.asmodee.net/corporate/uploads/Templates/Asmodee_group_companies_EN.pdf),

2\. Third party service providers (maintenance, payment, marketing services, etc.),

3\. Our professional advisors such as lawyers and accountants, auditors,

4\. Government or regulatory authorities,

5\. Professional insurers or any other relevant type of insurer,

6\. Regulatory authorities / tax authorities / company registers, and banks.

In this context, your Personal Data may be transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA), to countries that do not offer a level of protection to your Personal Data equivalent to that which You enjoy within the EEA, such as China, the USA, Canada, etc. In the absence of an adequacy decision by the European Commission, the transfer of your Personal Data will be governed by the standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission or any other legal protection mechanism in accordance with applicable law.

#### 6\. How long do we keep your Personal Data?

As a matter of principle, your Personal Data is kept only for the time necessary to achieve the purposes for which it was collected.

Thus, when your Account is created, your identification data, your data relating to your personal life and your profile data are kept in an active database, until your Account is deleted.

Data relating to the behaviour and reputation of Users is kept in an active database, until the Account is deleted.

In the latter cases, your Personal Data will be archived and kept for a period of five (5) years from the date of your last connection, in accordance with the limitation period under ordinary law.

Statistical data of the Applications (history of games played on the Applications, preferences of your Applications, time spent playing on the Applications) is kept in an active database, until your Account is deleted.

However, in certain cases, Your Personal Data cannot be completely erased in order to ensure a consistent experience for Users of the BGA Sites. For example, games in the Applications that You have played that affect the data and scores of other Users will not be deleted. In this case, Your Personal Data will be kept for ten (10) years from the date of Your last connection and then anonymised.

Connection data (time and place of your activities, username and IP address) are kept for a period of one (1) year, in an active database, from your last connection. Other IP addresses are kept for a period of 30 days, in an active database.

Data of Content communicated on the Applications (in particular through chats) is kept for a period of three (3) months, in an active database, from the date of sending. Private messages are kept until they are expressly deleted.

However, in accordance with our General Terms of Service, the data of Content that You publish on the forums of the BGA Sites remains even after the deletion of your Account and/or of your Personal Data, it being understood that the Content remains associated with your Username and/or your avatar. You may at any time request the specific deletion of Content that would infringe your rights under the conditions of Article 8 of this Privacy Policy.

In addition, We may retain some of your data for a longer period of time, for example where We are required to do so by law or where the data is necessary to establish a right or contract. This is particularly the case for your data related to transactions, the amount of transactions you have made and the date and time of these transactions).

In this case, your Personal Data will be archived and kept for a period of ten (10) years in accordance with the statutory limitation period and/or in accordance with our tax and accounting obligations.

Once the retention periods have expired, we will ensure that your Personal Data is anonymised or deleted.

#### 7\. Security of your Personal Data

We are committed to ensuring the security of your Personal Data and have implemented information systems security policies and appropriate technical rules and measures to protect against unauthorised access, modification, use and disclosure, unlawful destruction or accidental loss of such data.

All of our employees, consultants, affiliates and subcontractors who have access to your Personal Data and are involved in its processing are required to maintain its confidentiality.

• Security of your password

We take every precaution to ensure the secure storage of your password associated with your Account. However, the security of this password also depends on its design. We therefore remind You that to be valid, your password must be composed of at least 8 characters, at least 3 of the following 4 types: upper case, lower case, numbers, special characters

The French Data Protection Authority (CNIL) recommends creating complex passwords, such as:

◦ Keep only the first few letters of words in a sentence; for example, the sentence "A Passwords needs to be remembered! " corresponds to the password "1p@ntbr!"

◦ By capitalizing the word if it is a noun

◦ By keeping punctuation marks (e.g.: !)

◦ By expressing the numbers using the digits from 0 to 9 (e.g.: One ->1)

• Security of transactions

In accordance with the T&Cs, the Player Site uses technology from third party service providers to secure Users' bank transactions.

Thus, during payment on the Player Site, Users' bank details are transmitted in encrypted form to third party service providers without BGA being able to access them or to know them in any way whatsoever.

BGA therefore does not collect the User's credit card number, its cryptogram or any other banking information.

Thus, to exercise their rights such as those identified in Article 8, relating to their credit card details, the User is therefore invited to contact payment service providers directly, if necessary.

#### 8\. What are your rights?

In accordance with the Personal Data Regulations, You have a number of rights in relation to Your Personal Data. Each of these rights is described in more detail below:

a) Withdrawal of consent. You may revoke your consent to any processing of your Personal Data at any time.

b) Access and copy. You may ask Us to confirm whether We process your Personal Data and, if so, ask Us to provide you with the following information:

a. the purposes of the processing;

b. the categories of Personal Data;

c. the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the Personal Data has been or will be communicated;

d. when possible, the intended Personal Data retention period or, when this is not possible, the criteria used to determine this period;

e. the existence of the right to request the rectification or deletion of Personal Data, or a limitation of the processing of Your Personal Data, or the right to object to such processing;

f. the right to lodge a complaint with the personal data control authority (in France, the CNIL);

g. when Personal Data is not collected from You, any available information as to its source;

h. the existence of automated decision-making and, at least in such cases, relevant information about the underlying logic and the significance and intended consequences of such processing for You.

When Personal Data is transferred to a third country or to an international organisation, You have the right to be informed of the appropriate guarantees, with regard to the transfer.

We provide You with a copy of the Personal Data subject to processing.

We may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs for any additional copies that You request from Us or for requests to provide Personal Data in hard copy and/or physical form.

When You make your request electronically, the information will be provided to You in a commonly used electronic form, unless You request otherwise.

Your right to obtain a copy of your Personal Data must not infringe the rights and freedoms of others.

c) Rectification. You have the possibility to obtain, as soon as possible, the rectification of your Personal Data if it is incorrect. You also have the possibility to have your incomplete Personal Data completed, including by providing an additional declaration.

d) Erasure. You can ask Us to erase your Personal Data, as soon as possible, in the following cases:

a. when it is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected;

b. You have revoked your consent and there is no other legal basis for the processing;

c. following the exercise of your right to object;

d. your Personal Data has been subject to unlawful processing;

e. or to comply with a legal obligation. We are not obliged to respond to your request for erasure of your Personal Data, in particular if its processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

e) Limitation. You can ask us to limit the processing of your Personal Data (i.e. to keep it without using it) when:

a. its accuracy is disputed;

b. its processing is unlawful but you do not want it to be deleted;

c. it is still necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims;

d. we check whether there are compelling reasons for exercising your right to object. We may continue to use your Personal Data following a request for restriction: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or to protect the rights of any other natural or legal person.

f) Portability. You may ask Us to provide You with your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, or You may request that it be transferred directly to another data controller, but only if:

a. the processing is based on your consent;

b. on the execution of a contract with You and the processing is automated, in particular in the context of profiling.

The right to portability of your Personal Data must not infringe the rights and freedoms of others.

g) Right to object. You may object at any time, for reasons relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your Personal Data based on our legitimate interest. We will then no longer process the Personal Data, unless we demonstrate that there are compelling and legitimate reasons for the processing which prevail over your interests and your rights and freedoms. We may retain it for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

You may object at any time to the processing of your Personal Data for prospecting purposes.

h) Digital will. You have the right to define instructions (general or specific) concerning the fate of your Personal Data after your death, notably concerning the retention, erasure and communication of your Personal Data. These instructions may also be registered with "a certified digital trusted third party. These instructions may designate a person responsible for their execution; otherwise, your heirs will be designated.

In the absence of any instructions, your heirs can contact Us in order to:

a. access the processing of Personal Data allowing "the organisation and settlement of the estate of the deceased";

b. receive communication of "digital assets" or "data akin to family souvenirs, transmissible to heirs";

c. to close your Account on the BGA Sites and oppose the further processing of your Personal Data.

In any case, You have the possibility to inform Us, at any time, that You do not wish, in the event of death, for your Personal Data to be communicated to a third party.

#### 9\. Exercise of your rights

For more information about your rights, to exercise your rights, or if you have any questions about the protection of your Personal Data, please contact Us via the "contact" page of the BGA Sites.

For the purpose of asserting your rights under the conditions referred to above and in the event that BGA has doubts about the author of the request, BGA may ask You to prove your identity by mentioning your surname, first name, email address or any other necessary proof and to accompany your request with a copy of a valid identity document.

You will receive a reply within a maximum period of one (1) month from the date of receipt of your request.

If necessary, this period may be extended by two (2) months by BGA, which will inform You, depending on the complexity and/or number of requests.

If you request the deletion of your Personal Data and/or exercise your right to request the erasure of your Personal Data, BGA may however archive it for the period necessary to meet its legal obligations or for evidential purposes during the applicable limitation period.

#### 10\. Data Protection Officer (DPO)

The contact details of our Data Protection Officer are as follows:

dpo@boardgamearena.com  
  
Délégué à la Protection des Données  
AD2G Studio  
18 rue Jacqueline Auriol - 78280 Guyancourt - France Tél: 01 34 52 19 70

Our Data Protection Officer is available to answer any questions you may have about this privacy policy.

#### 10\. Right to file a complaint with the CNIL

We inform You of your right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority, namely the CNIL in France, if You consider that a processing of personal data concerning You does not comply with the European data protection regulations, at the following address:

CNIL – Service des plaintes  
3 Place de Fontenoy - TSA 80715 - 75334 PARIS CEDEX 07  
Tél: 01 53 73 22 22

#### 12\. Updating of the Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, for example to take account of legal changes, technological advances and good business practice. We will inform You in the event of a substantial change.

This Privacy Policy has been drawn up in both English and French. However, the French version shall prevail in the event of any difficulty of interpretation.

### Privacy policy

#### Préambule

La présente Politique de confidentialité fait partie intégrante des [Conditions Générales d’Utilisation](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) et de [Services](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos), si bien que les définitions utilisées dans ces dernières sont réutilisées dans la présente Politique de confidentialité.

La présente Politique de confidentialité comporte les règles minimales que la société AD2G Studio (ci-après dénommée « BGA », « Nous », « notre ») a établi au regard de la protection des Données Personnelles afin que la collecte, l’utilisation, la conservation et la communication de vos Données Personnelles soient effectuées d’une façon juste, transparente et sécurisée.

Cette Politique de confidentialité définit notre approche en matière de traitement des Données Personnelles Vous concernant que Nous collectons auprès de Vous ou que des tiers Nous communiquent de manière licite ainsi que les finalités de ces traitements. Elle décrit également vos droits au regard de nos traitements de vos Données Personnelles.

Nous sommes amenés, en qualité de responsable de traitement au sens de la Règlementation sur les Données Personnelles, à collecter des Données Personnelles auprès de Vous dans le cadre de l’utilisation de votre Compte Vous permettant d’accéder aux Applications et d’utiliser les Services.

#### Définitions

Les termes suivants qu’ils soient employés au singulier ou au pluriel dans la présente Politique de confidentialité, auront la définition suivante :

« Application(s) » : désignent les jeux accessibles depuis le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur, et/ou les jeux accessibles seulement depuis le Site Développeur car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie des Codes des Utilisateurs, édités par BGA et/ou ses Filiales ainsi que tout logiciel accessoire qui serait par exemple nécessaires comme une mise à jour de l’Application, une mise à niveau de l’Application, son code (en tout ou partie), les fichiers la composant, les images associées ou générées et les données associées mais également les applications non accessibles depuis les Sites BGA, car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie de Codes d’Utilisateurs   ;

« BGA » / « Nous » / « notre » : désigne la société AD2G STUDIO, société par actions simplifiée (SAS), au capital social de 100,00 €, dont le siège social est situé au 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, immatriculée au Registre du Commerce et des Sociétés de Versailles sous le numéro 803 287 150 représentée par Monsieur Alexandre Schlecht agissant et ayant les pouvoirs nécessaires en tant que président et dont les [coordonnées sont disponibles](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) ;

« CG » : désigne les [Conditions Générales d’Utilisation](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) et de [Services](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos) des Sites BGA ;

« Compte » : désigne l’espace personnel d’un Utilisateur uniquement accessible avec des Eléments d’identification transmis par BGA lui permettant d’accéder et de bénéficier des Services ;

« Compte Tiers » : désigne un compte auquel l’Utilisateur a souscrit auprès d’un éditeur tiers et qui peut être lié à un Compte (par exemple Google ou Facebook) ;

« Contenus » : désigne(nt) le(s) contenu(s) de toute nature (notamment des données textuelles, visuelles, vidéos, photographiques, espace de discussion, avis, etc. publiés(s) sur les Sites BGA grâce aux Services, par un Utilisateur sous sa responsabilité ;

« Donnée(s) » / « Donnée(s) Personnelle(s) » : désigne (nt) les données à caractère personnel d’un Utilisateur ou d’un Internaute collectées et traitées par BGA dans le cadre de la consultation et l’utilisation des Sites BGA, comme, le cas échéant, la création et la gestion de son Compte et la réalisation des Services ;

« Elément d’identification » : désigne l’identifiant de connexion (« login » ou adresse de courrier électronique) et mot de passe (« password ») définis et/ou transmis pour partie initialement par BGA à l’Utilisateur, à charge pour lui de modifier son mot de passe lors de sa première connexion et lui permettant d’accéder à son Compte ;

« Filiale(s) » : désigne toute société ou entité qui contrôle directement ou indirectement ou qui est contrôlée par ou sous contrôle commun avec BGA. Le contrôle d’une entité signifie la possession, directement ou indirectement, du pouvoir de diriger ou de faire diriger la gestion ou les politiques d’une telle entité, que ce soit par la propriété des titres avec droit de vote, par contrat ou autrement ;

« Internaute » : désigne l’ensemble des internautes, visiteurs des Sites BGA, disposant ou non d’un Compte ;

« Nom d’Utilisateur » : désigne une série de caractères permettant à l’Utilisateur, associé un mot de passe déterminé par ses soins, de se connecter de manière unique à son Compte et d’accéder aux Services ;

« Politique de confidentialité » : désigne la présente politique de confidentialité ;

« Politique de Modération de BGA » : désigne la politique de modération de BGA, accessible en cliquant ici https://en.doc.boardgamearena.com/Moderationpolicy ;

« Règlementation sur les Données Personnelles » : désigne la Loi n°78-17 du 6 janvier 1978 relative à l'informatique, aux fichiers et aux libertés, modifiée en application du Règlement communautaire du 27 avril 2016 publié au Journal Officiel de l’Union Européenne le 4 mai 2016 relatif à la protection des personnes physiques à l'égard du traitement des Données Personnelles et à la libre circulation de ces données (dit « RGPD » pour Règlement Général pour la Protection des Données) ;

« Service(s) » : désignent les fonctionnalités et services gratuits mis à la disposition des Internautes et accessibles depuis les Sites BGA sans Compte ainsi que les fonctionnalités et services gratuits ou payants, tels que déterminés dans les C.G.S. Développeurs et les C.G.S. Joueurs et accessibles depuis les Sites BGA avec un Compte, aux Utilisateurs et sous réserve de la souscription à un Abonnement Premium pour les Services payants.

« Site(s) BGA » : désigne le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur ;

« Site Développeur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL https://studio.boardgamearena.com ;

« Site Joueur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL https://boardgamearena.com ;

« Utilisateur » / « Vous » : désigne toute personne physique de quinze (15) ans minimum et capable ou disposant d’une autorisation parentale pour ce faire, y compris représentant légal (dirigeant, préposé, etc.) d’une personne morale agissant pour son compte, souscrivant pour ce faire à l’aide d’un Support de Réception, à l’ouverture d’un Compte sur le Site Joueur et/ou sur le Site Développeur et n’étant soumise à aucune interdiction et/ou restriction légale, réglementaire ou conventionnelle l’empêchant d’accéder et/ou d’utiliser depuis un Support de Réception des Applications et/ou de développer des développements et/ou céder les développements à BGA et/ou de réaliser des Traductions et/ou céder les Traductions à BGA et/ou diffuser du Contenu et ayant rempli, le cas échéant, l’ensemble des formalités légales, réglementaires et conventionnelles pour ce faire, en vue d’utiliser les Services  ;

« Support(s) de Réception » : désigne(nt) les ordinateurs, tablettes, smartphones, télévision, utilisés pour accéder aux Sites BGA et pouvoir utiliser les Applications et bénéficiant a minima d’un navigateur récent et à jour.

#### 1\. Qui est responsable de traitement de vos Données Personnelles ?

La société AD2G Studio SAS [dont les coordonnées sont disponibles](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) est le responsable de traitement de vos Données Personnelles.

#### 2\. Age minimum

La préservation de la sécurité et de la vie privée des enfants est très importante pour Nous. Nous ne recueillons ni n’utilisons volontairement des Données Personnelles de personnes n’ayant pas atteint l’âge de 15 ans, sans le consentement à la fois de l’enfant et du titulaire de la responsabilité parentale.

Aussi, Vous confirmez que Vous avez au moins 15 ans ou plus lorsque Vous fournissez vos Données Personnelles en lien avec l’utilisation de nos Services. Si Vous n’avez pas au moins 15 ans, Vous devez demander l’autorisation de vos parents ou tuteur légal pour Nous fournir vos Données Personnelles.

#### 3\. Quelles Données Personnelles collectons-Nous ?

Nous collectons les Données Personnelles suivantes Vous concernant :

• Données d’identification telles que votre Nom d’Utilisateur, si Vous avez plus ou moins de 15 ans, votre adresse de courrier électronique pour Vous connecter à votre Compte ainsi que certaines données de votre/vos Comptes tiers si vous décidez de les /l’associer à votre Compte ;

• Données relatives à votre vie personnelle telles que votre prénom, nom, et adresse postale dans le cadre de la création de votre Compte sur le Site Développeur et/ou dans le cadre de l’autorisation parentale ;

• Données relatives à votre profil créé sur le Site Joueur (avatar, genre, couleur préférée, langues parlées et préférences dans les sons attribués pour jouer) ;

• Données de connexion lorsque Vous accédez aux Applications et utilisez les Services (temps et lieu de vos activités, identifiant et adresse IP, navigateurs et appareils utilisés) ;

• Données statistiques et performance de jeu (historique des Applications, préférences de vos Applications, les progrès dans les Applications, le temps sur les Applications) ;

• Données des Contenus que Vous communiquez (notamment à travers les chats, les espaces de discussion, posts sur les forums, messages, formulaires de contact ou autres fonctionnalités des Sites) ;

• Données relatives à vos demandes d’assistance ;

• Données relatives au comportement et la réputation des Utilisateurs.

Nous ne procédons à aucune collecte de Données Personnelles dites « sensibles » au sens de la Règlementation sur les Données Personnelles, notamment les données relatives à votre état de santé ou qui révèleraient votre prétendue origine raciale ou ethnique, vos opinions politiques, vos convictions religieuses ou philosophiques ou encore votre appartenance syndicale.

#### 4\. Comment traitons-Nous vos Données Personnelles ?

Nous traitons vos Données Personnelles pour les finalités suivantes. Chaque fois que Nous traitons vos Données Personnelles, Nous le faisons sur la base d’une « justification » légale (ou base légale) de traitement, que Nous avons identifiée dans le tableau ci-dessous.

|     | Finalités | Base juridique |
| --- | --- | --- |
| 1.  | Pour Vous identifier via votre Compte | Ce traitement est nécessaire à l’exécution du contrat conclu entre Vous et BGA. |
| 2.  | Pour Vous permettre d’accéder aux Services et aux Applications | Ce traitement est nécessaire à l’exécution du contrat conclu entre Vous et BGA. |
| 3.  | Pour Vous permettre de communiquer sur les Applications avec les autres Utilisateurs | Ce traitement repose sur le contrat conclu entre Vous et BGA. |
| 4.  | Pour veiller au respect des CG | Ce traitement repose sur le contrat conclu entre Vous et BGA. |
| 5.  | Pour Nous permettre de modérer et/ou sanctionner l’attitude d’un Utilisateur dans le cadre des Applications | Ce traitement repose sur le contrat conclu entre Vous et BGA. |
| 6.  | Pour Nous permettre de détecter les multicomptes | Ce traitement repose sur l’intérêt légitime de BGA. En effet, l’intérêt légitime du responsable du traitement est d’assurer une ambiance de jeu conviviale en permettant d’afficher une mention d’information lorsque deux joueurs d’une même Table de jeu ont la même adresse IP. |
| 7.  | Pour Vous communiquer des informations commerciales sur les Services et/ou les Applications | Nous considérons qu'il est dans notre intérêt légitime de tenir les Utilisateurs informés de nos Services et des Applications qui sont accessibles depuis les Sites BGA, car cela Nous aide à assurer la pérennité et le développement de nos activités. Cependant, lorsque la loi exige que BGA obtienne votre consentement avant de Vous envoyer de tels renseignements, BGA s’appuiera sur votre consentement afin de procéder au traitement. |
| 8.  | En relation avec une opération de restructuration et/ou d’une fusion-acquisition de BGA | Nous considérons qu’il est dans notre intérêt d’être en mesure de prendre des décisions concernant l’avenir de notre entreprise de manière informée, dans le but de préserver et de développer nos activités commerciales. |
| 9.  | Les Contenus demeureront associés au Nom d’Utilisateur y compris après effacement de votre Compte et/ou de vos Données Personnelles | Par soucis de cohérence et d’intelligibilité des Sites, Nous considérons qu’il est dans notre intérêt légitime de conserver sur les Sites votre Contenu associé au Nom d’Utilisateur que Vous avez donné à votre profil pendant la durée légale de conservation. Vous pouvez à tout moment demander la suppression spécifique du Contenu qui porterait atteinte à l'intérêt d'un Utilisateur |
| 10. | Pour Nous conformer à toute loi applicable, ordonnance judiciaire, procédure judiciaire, ou aux exigences d'un organisme de réglementation. | Ce traitement est nécessaire au respect de nos obligations légales. |
| 11. | Pour faire valoir nos droits et obligations juridiques et pour toute procédure judiciaire Vous impliquant, initiée par ou contre Vous. | Nous considérons qu'il est dans notre intérêt légitime de protéger notre organisation contre toute violation d'une obligation légale qui lui est due et de Nous défendre en cas de litige. |
| 12. | Pour protéger les droits des tiers. | Ce traitement est nécessaire au respect des obligations légales auxquelles BGA est soumise. Ce traitement est également nécessaire aux fins des intérêts légitimes poursuivis par BGA. Nous considérons que Nous avons un intérêt légitime à ce que nos activités ne violent pas les droits des tiers. |
| 13. | Pour répondre à vos demandes d’exercice de vos droits dans les conditions de l’article 8 | Ce traitement est nécessaire au respect des obligations légales auxquelles BGA est soumise. |
| 14. | Pour vous communiquer des informations commerciales concernant (i) les Produits et Services similaires d’Asmodee et/ou des Partenaires (ii) le [Groupe Asmodee](https://cdn.svc.asmodee.net/corporate/uploads/Templates/Asmodee_group_companies_EN.pdf) et/ou (iii) des partenaires tiers. | Nous considérons qu’il est dans notre intérêt légitime de tenir nos clients informés de nos Produits et Services, mais aussi des produits et services similaires proposés par le groupe dont nous faisons partie, ses Partenaires ou des partenaires tiers, car cela nous aide à assurer la pérennité et le développement de nos activités. Toutefois, lorsque la loi exige que BGA obtienne votre consentement avant de vous envoyer de telles informations, BGA s’appuiera sur votre consentement afin de procéder au traitement. |
| 15. | Pour vous proposer des publicités personnalisées sur les réseaux sociaux (en utilisant comme identifiant unique la même adresse électronique que vous avez peut-être fournie pour la création de vos comptes d’utilisateur à la fois sur Asmodee et sur les plateformes de réseaux sociaux). | Si vous êtes un client existant et que vous vivez dans un pays concerné (par exemple, le Canada, la France, le Royaume-Uni, les États-Unis), nous considérons que nous avons un intérêt légitime à vous proposer des publicités personnalisées concernant nos Produits et Services, mais aussi les produits et services similaires proposés par le Groupe Asmodee, car cela nous aide à assurer la pérennité et le développement de nos activités.  <br>  <br>Toutefois, si vous n’êtes pas un client existant ou si vous vivez dans un pays où la loi exige que BGA obtienne votre consentement avant de vous proposer des publicités personnalisées sur les réseaux sociaux (par exemple, l’Allemagne), BGA s’appuiera sur votre consentement afin de procéder au traitement envisagé. |

Pour permettre de veiller au respect des CG et notamment des règles de conduite, BGA a mis en place une Politique de Modération de BGA quia lui permet de sanctionner le comportement des Utilisateurs concernés

BGA utilise ainsi des outils automatisés afin de collecter ces Données Personnelles et détecter les comportements inappropriés des Utilisateurs avec notamment un système de notation (score de Karma) basé sur un score de 100, lequel est amené à varier en fonction des comportements détectés et, par conséquent, à influer la réputation de l’Utilisateur.

BGA donne également la possibilité aux Utilisateurs de l’aider à veiller au respect des CG et de la Politique de Modération de BGA. Par exemple, sur le Site Joueur, les Utilisateurs peuvent « signaler » le comportement d’un Utilisateur, notamment en utilisant la fonctionnalité prévue à cet effet sur le profil de l’Utilisateur ou en cliquant sur le « Pouce Rouge » à la fin d’une partie. Ces outils permettent à BGA d’appliquer, par une décision automatisée, une sanction à l’Utilisateur concerné.

Dans ce cadre, l’Utilisateur concerné reçoit un courrier électronique l'informant de la sanction qui a été prise par BGA à son encontre.

Conformément à la Politique de Modération de BGA, les Utilisateurs ont le droit de faire appel de la décision de modération qui leur a été appliquée en Nous contactant via le formulaire de Support”.

Lorsque Vous jouez à des Applications impliquant plusieurs Utilisateurs, notez que certaines Données Personnelles seront rendues publiques et donc accessibles aux autres Utilisateurs, telles que votre Nom d’Utilisateur, vos données de statistiques et performances de jeu. Les données des Contenus publiés dans le cadre de chats et forums pourront également être rendues publiques aux Utilisateurs et Internautes.

#### 5\. Avec qui partageons-Nous vos Données Personnelles ?

Nous sommes amenés à partager vos Données Personnelles avec différentes catégories de destinataires, afin de Vous faire bénéficier des Services :

| Destinataires internes | Destinataires externes |
| --- | --- |
| Le personnel habilité du service marketing, des services chargés de traiter la relation client et la prospection, des services administratifs et juridiques, des services logistiques et informatiques ainsi que leurs responsables hiérarchiques. | \- les autres sociétés du Groupe Asmodee ;  <br>\- nos Partenaires ;  <br>\- les réseaux sociaux (Instagram et Facebook) ;  <br>\- les auxiliaires de justice, le cas échéant ;  <br>\- le personnel habilité des sous-traitants (hébergement/stockage de données, éditeurs de logiciels, solutions permettant la connexion et l’accès nos services, etc.). |

Veuillez noter que cette liste est non exhaustive et qu'il peut y avoir d'autres cas où Nous partageons vos données avec des tiers, lorsque cela est dans l'intérêt légitime de BGA, permis par la loi applicable, ou encore lorsque cela est nécessaire au respect d’une obligation légale à laquelle Nous sommes soumis.

Nous pouvons être amenés à partager vos Données Personnelles avec différentes catégories de tiers, selon nos besoins :

1\. Filiales dont la liste est disponible en [cliquant ici](https://cdn.svc.asmodee.net/corporate/uploads/Templates/Asmodee_group_companies_FR.pdf),

2\. Prestataires de services tiers (maintenance, paiement, services marketing, etc.),

3\. Nos conseillers professionnels tels que les avocats, les comptables et les auditeurs,

4\. Les autorités gouvernementales ou réglementaires,

5\. Les assureurs professionnels ou tous les autres types d'assureurs pertinents,

6\. Autorités de régulation / autorités fiscales / registres des sociétés, et banques.

Dans ce contexte, vos Données Personnelles pourront être transférées en dehors de l’Espace économique européen (EEE), vers des pays n’offrant pas un niveau de protection à vos Données à caractère personnel équivalent à celui dont Vous bénéficiez au sein de l'EEE, tels que la Chine, les USA, le Canada, etc. En l’absence de décision d’adéquation de la Commission européenne, le transfert de vos Données Personnelles sera encadré par les clauses contractuelles types adoptées par la Commission européenne ou tout autre mécanisme juridique de protection conformément à la loi applicable.

#### 6\. Combien de temps conservons-Nous vos Données Personnelles ?

Vos Données Personnelles sont, par principe, conservées uniquement le temps nécessaire pour la réalisation des finalités pour lesquelles elles ont été collectées.

Ainsi, lors de la création de votre Compte, vos données d’identification, vos données relatives à votre vie personnelle et les données du profil sont conservées, en base dite active, jusqu’à la suppression de votre Compte. Les données relatives au comportement et la réputation des Utilisateurs sont conservées en base dite active, jusqu’à la suppression du Compte.

Dans ces derniers cas, vos Données Personnelles seront archivées et conservées pour une durée de cinq (5) années à compter de votre dernière connexion, conformément au délai commun de prescription.

Les données statistiques des Applications (historique des parties jouées sur les Applications, préférences de vos Applications, les progrès dans les Applications, le temps de jeu sur les Applications), sont conservées en base dite active, jusqu’à la suppression de votre Compte.

Cependant dans certains cas, Vos Données Personnelles ne peuvent pas être complètement effacées afin d'assurer la cohérence de l'expérience des Utilisateurs les Sites BGA. Par exemple, les parties des Applications que Vous avez jouées et qui affectent les données et les scores des autres Utilisateurs ne seront pas supprimées. Dans ce cas, Vos Données Personnelles seront conservées dix (10) ans à compter de Votre dernière connexion puis anonymisées.

Les données de connexion (temps et lieu de vos activités, identifiant et adresse IP) sont conservées pour une durée d’un (1) an, en base active, à compter de votre dernière connexion. Vos autres adresses IP sont également conservées pour une durée de 30 jours, en base active.

Les données de Contenus communiqués sur les Applications (notamment à travers les chats) sont conservées pour une durée de trois (3) mois, en base active, à compter de leur date d’envoi. Les messages privés sont conservés jusqu'à ce qu'ils soient expressément supprimés.

Toutefois, conformément à nos Conditions Générales de Services, les données des Contenus que Vous publiez sur les forums des Sites BGA persistent même après la suppression de votre Compte et/ou de vos Données Personnelles, étant entendu que les Contenus demeureront associés à son Nom d’Utilisateur et/ou son avatar. Vous pouvez à tout moment demander la suppression spécifique de Contenus qui porteraient atteinte à vos droits dans les conditions de l’article 8 de la présente Politique de confidentialité.

En outre, Nous pouvons conserver certaines de vos données pour une durée plus importante, notamment lorsque Nous y sommes tenus au titre d’une obligation légale ou encore lorsque ces données sont nécessaires pour établir la preuve d’un droit ou d’un contrat. C’est le cas notamment de vos données liées aux transactions), montant des transactions que Vous avez réalisées ainsi que date et heure de ces transactions).

Dans ce cas, vos Données Personnelles seront archivées et conservées pour une durée de dix (10) années conformément au délai légal de prescription et/ou conformément à nos obligations fiscales et comptables.

Dès lors que les délais de conservation auront expiré, Nous veillerons à ce que vos Données Personnelles soient anonymisées ou supprimées.

#### 7\. Sécurité de vos Données Personnelles

Nous nous engageons à assurer la sécurité de vos Données Personnelles et Nous avons mis en place des politiques de sécurité des systèmes d’information et des règles et mesures techniques appropriées pour les protéger contre les accès, les modifications, l’utilisation et la divulgation non autorisées, la destruction illicite ou la perte accidentelle de ces données.

Tous nos salariés, consultants, Filiales et sous-traitants, qui ont accès à Vos Données Personnelles et sont associés à leur traitement, sont tenus d’en respecter la confidentialité.

• Sécurité de votre mot de passe

Nous prenons toutes les précautions utiles pour assurer le stockage sécurisé de votre mot de passe associé à votre Compte. Toutefois, la sécurité de ce mot de passe dépend aussi de sa conception. Aussi, Nous Vous rappelons que votre mot de passe, pour être valide doit être composé, a minima de 8 caractères, au moins 3 des 4 types suivants : majuscules, minuscules, chiffres, caractères spéciaux La Cnil recommande de créer des mots de passe complexes, tels que : ◦ Ne conserver que les premières lettres des mots d’une phrase ; par exemple, la phrase « Un Mot de Passe se retient ! » correspond au mot de passe "1mdp@sr !" ◦ En mettant une majuscule si le mot est un nom ◦ En gardant des signes de ponctuation (ex : !) ◦ En exprimant les nombres à l’aide des chiffres de 0 à 9 (ex : Un ->1)

• Sécurité des transactions

Conformément aux CG, le Site Joueur utilise la technologie des sociétés tierces pour sécuriser les transactions bancaires des Utilisateurs.

Ainsi, lors du paiement sur le Site Joueur, les coordonnées bancaires des Utilisateurs sont transmises de manière chiffrée aux prestataires tiers sans que BGA ne soit en mesure d’y accéder et d’en prendre connaissance d’une quelconque manière que ce soit.

BGA ne collecte donc ni le numéro de la carte bancaire de l’Utilisateur, ni son cryptogramme, ni toute autre information de nature bancaire.

Ainsi, pour exercer ses droits tels que ceux identifiés à l’article 8, relatifs à ses coordonnées de carte bancaire, l’Utilisateur est donc invité à s’adresser directement aux sociétés de paiement le cas échéant.

#### 8\. Quels sont vos droits ?

Conformément à la Réglementation sur les Données Personnelles, Vous bénéficiez d’un certain nombre de droits sur vos Données Personnelles. Chacun de ces droits est plus amplement détaillé ci-dessous :

a) Retrait du consentement. Vous pouvez révoquer à tout moment, votre consentement à tout traitement de vos Données Personnelles fondé sur votre consentement.

b) Accès et copie. Vous pouvez Nous demander de confirmer si Nous traitons vos Données Personnelles et, le cas échéant, Nous demander de Vous fournir les informations suivantes :

a. les finalités du traitement ;

b. les catégories de Données Personnelles ;

c. les destinataires ou catégories de destinataires auxquels les Données Personnelles ont été ou seront communiquées ;

d. lorsque cela est possible, la durée de conservation des Données Personnelles envisagée ou, lorsque ce n’est pas possible, les critères utilisés pour déterminer cette durée ;

e. l’existence du droit de demander la rectification ou l’effacement de Données Personnelles, ou une limitation du traitement de ses Données Personnelles, ou du droit de s’opposer à ce traitement ;

f. le droit d’introduire une réclamation auprès de l’autorité de contrôle en matière de données personnelles (en France, la CNIL) ;

g. lorsque les Données Personnelles ne sont pas collectées auprès de Vous, toute information disponible quant à leur source ;

h. l’existence d’une prise de décision automatisée, et, au moins en pareil cas, des informations utiles concernant la logique sous-jacente, ainsi que l’importance et les conséquences prévues de ce traitement pour Vous.

Lorsque les Données Personnelles sont transférées vers un pays tiers ou à une organisation internationale, Vous avez le droit d’être informé des garanties appropriées, en ce qui concerne le transfert.

Nous Vous fournissons une copie des Données Personnelles faisant l’objet d’un traitement.

Nous pouvons exiger le paiement de frais raisonnables basés sur les coûts administratifs pour toute copie supplémentaire que Vous Nous demandez ou en cas de demande de transmission des Données personnelles sur support papier et/ou physique.

Lorsque Vous formulez votre demande par voie électronique, les informations Vous seront fournies sous une forme électronique d’usage courant, à moins que Vous demandiez qu’il en soit autrement.

Votre droit d’obtenir une copie de vos Données Personnelles ne doit pas porter atteinte aux droits et libertés d’autrui.

c) Rectification. Vous avez la possibilité d’obtenir, dans les meilleurs délais, la rectification de vos Données Personnelles si elles sont incorrectes. Vous avez aussi la possibilité d’obtenir que vos Données Personnelles incomplètes soient complétées, y compris en fournissant une déclaration complémentaire.

d) Effacement. Vous pouvez Nous demander d’effacer, dans les meilleurs délais, vos Données Personnelles dans les cas suivants :

a. lorsqu’elles ne sont plus nécessaires au regard des finalités pour lesquelles elles ont été collectées ;

b. Vous avez révoqué votre consentement et il n’existe pas d’autre fondement juridique au traitement ;

c. à la suite de l’exercice de votre droit d’opposition ;

d. vos Données Personnelles ont fait l’objet d’un traitement illicite ;

e. ou pour respecter une obligation légale. Nous ne sommes pas tenus de donner suite à votre demande d'effacement de vos Données Personnelles notamment si leur traitement est nécessaire au respect d’une obligation légale ou à la constatation, l’exercice ou la défense de droits en justice.

e) Limitation. Vous pouvez Nous demander de limiter le traitement de vos Données Personnelles (c’est-à-dire de les conserver sans les utiliser) lorsque :

a. leur exactitude est contestée ;

b. leur traitement est illicite mais que Vous ne voulez pas qu’elles soient supprimées ;

c. elles sont encore nécessaires pour la constatation, l’exercice ou la défense de droits en justice ;

d. nous vérifions l’existence de motifs impérieux dans le cadre de l'exercice de votre droit d'opposition. Nous pouvons continuer d’utiliser vos Données Personnelles à la suite d’une demande de restriction : avec votre consentement ; pour la constatation, l’exercice ou la défense de droits en justice ; ou pour protéger les droits de toute autre personne physique ou morale.

f) Portabilité. Vous pouvez Nous demander de Vous fournir vos Données Personnelles dans un format structuré, couramment utilisé et lisible par une machine, ou Vous pouvez demander qu’elles soient transmises directement à un autre responsable de traitement, mais uniquement si :

a. le traitement est fondé sur votre consentement ;

b. sur l’exécution d’un contrat conclu avec Vous et que le traitement est automatisé, notamment dans le cadre du profilage.

Le droit à la portabilité de vos Données Personnelles ne doit pas porter atteinte aux droits et libertés d’autrui.

g) Droit d’opposition. Vous pouvez Vous opposez à tout moment, pour des raisons tenant à votre situation particulière, à un traitement des Données Personnelles Vous concernant fondé sur notre intérêt légitime. Nous ne traiterons alors plus les Données Personnelles, à moins que Nous ne démontrions qu’il existe des motifs impérieux et légitimes pour le traitement qui prévalent sur vos intérêts et vos droits et libertés, Nous pourrons les conserver pour la constatation, l’exercice ou la défense de droits en justice.

Vous pouvez Vous opposer à tout moment au traitement de vos Données Personnelles à des fins de prospection.

h) Testament numérique. Vous avez le droit de définir des directives (générales ou spécifiques) relatives au sort de vos Données Personnelles après votre mort, notamment relatives à la conservation, à l’effacement et à la communication de vos Données Personnelles, lesquelles directives peuvent être enregistrées également auprès « d’un tiers de confiance numérique certifié ». Ces directives peuvent désigner une personne chargée de leur exécution ; à défaut, vos héritiers seront désignés.

En l’absence de toute directive, vos héritiers peuvent s’adresser à Nous afin de/d’ :

a. accéder aux traitements de Données Personnelles permettant « l’organisation et le règlement de la succession du défunt » ;

b. recevoir communication des « biens numériques » ou des « données s’apparentant à des souvenirs de famille, transmissibles aux héritiers » ;

c. faire procéder à la clôture de votre Compte sur les Sites BGA et s’opposer à la poursuite du traitement de vos Données Personnelles.

En tout état de cause, Vous avez la possibilité de Nous indiquer, à tout moment, que Vous ne souhaitez pas, en cas de décès, que vos Données Personnelles soient communiquées à un tiers.

#### 9\. Exercice de vos droits

Pour davantage d’informations concernant vos droits, pour exercer vos droits ou pour toute question concernant la protection de vos Données Personnelles, veuillez Nous contacter via la page "contact" des Sites BGA.

Aux fins de faire valoir vos droits suivant les conditions visées ci-dessus et dans l’hypothèse où BGA aurait des doutes sur l’auteur de la demande, BGA pourra Vous demander de justifier de votre identité en mentionnant vos nom, prénom, adresse de courrier électronique ou tout autre élément de preuve nécessaire et d’accompagner votre demande d’une copie d’une pièce d’identité en cours de validité.

Une réponse Vous sera adressée dans un délai maximum d’un (1) mois suivant la date de réception de la demande.

Au besoin ce délai pourra être prolongé de deux (2) mois par BGA qui Vous en informera et ce, compte tenu de la complexité et/ou du nombre de demandes.

En cas de demande de suppression de vos Données Personnelles et/ou en cas d’exercice de votre droit à solliciter l’effacement de vos Données Personnelles, BGA pourra toutefois les archiver, et ce pour la durée nécessaire à satisfaire à ses obligations légales, ou à des fins probatoires pendant le délai de prescription applicable.

#### 10\. Délégué à la Protection des Données (DPO)

Les coordonnées de notre Délégué à la Protection des Données sont les suivantes :

dpo@boardgamearena.com  
  
Délégué à la Protection des Données  
AD2G Studio  
18 rue Jacqueline Auriol - 78280 Guyancourt - France Tél: 01 34 52 19 70

Notre Délégué à la Protection des Données est à votre disposition pour toute question sur la présente politique de confidentialité.

#### 10\. Droit d’introduire une réclamation auprès de la CNIL

Nous Vous informons de votre droit d’introduire une plainte auprès d'une autorité de contrôle, à savoir la CNIL en France, si Vous estimez qu’un traitement de données à caractère personnel Vous concernant n'est pas conforme à la règlementation européenne de protection des données, à l’adresse suivante :

CNIL – Service des plaintes  
3 Place de Fontenoy - TSA 80715 - 75334 PARIS CEDEX 07  
Tél : 01 53 73 22 22

#### 12\. Mise à jour de la Politique de confidentialité

Nous pouvons modifier la présente Politique de confidentialité occasionnellement, par exemple pour prendre en compte les changements légaux, les avancées technologiques et les bonnes pratiques commerciales. Nous Vous informerons en cas de changement substantiel.

La présente Politique de confidentialité a été établie en français et en anglais, toutefois, seule la version française prévaudra en cas de difficulté d'interprétation.

### Cookie policy

This cookie policy ("Policy") is defined by AD2G Studio (hereafter "AD2G Studio" or "us") and governs how cookies are used on the website boardgamearena.com (the "Site").

The Policy informs you of the purposes for which we use these cookies and how you can manage them.

As a data controller, we may collect your personal data via the cookies that we install on the Site. For more information on how your personal data is processed in this context, please read our [Privacy Policy](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac).

**1\. What is a cookie?**

**2\. What cookies do we use, for what purposes and how can they be controlled**

**3\. Policy update**

**4\. Contact**

#### 1\. What is a cookie?

A "cookie" is a string of information that is usually small. It is identified by a name and can be transmitted to your browser by a website that you connect to. Your web browser will keep it for a period of time and return it to the webserver each time you reconnect to it.

There are different types of cookies:

• **Temporary cookies and permanent cookies**: temporary cookies are automatically deleted at the end of your browser session. Permanent cookies stay on your device for longer, for a time that is specific to each cookie, and remain valid until their expiry date (unless they are deleted before by the user).

• **Proprietary cookies and third-party cookies**: proprietary cookies are cookies that are installed by the Site domain (these cookies are installed by us). Third-party cookies are cookies that are placed on the user's computer by the server of a domain other than the Site domain (for example, it may be social network cookies or cookies from publishers of audience measurement solutions).

No cookie will be installed on your device without your prior consent, except for some cookies that are used uniquely to enable or facilitate electronic communications, or that are strictly required to provide an online communications service at your express request.

#### 2\. What cookies do we use, for what purposes and how can they be controlled?

The table below lists the different types of cookies used on the Site, along with their purpose(s) and lifetime.

##### a. Functional cookies

These cookies are used to make the Site run optimally. They are usually set up to respond to actions you have performed or to a request for services, such as your authentication to access your account or the online purchase of a Premium subscription.

| Cookie name | Purpose of the cookie | Cookie duration |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_stripe\_mid | We use Stripe to facilitate credit card payments without storing credit card information on Stripe's own servers. | 12 months |
| cC  | We use this cookie to store each user's cookie preferences | 6 months |
| G\_ENABLED\_IDPS | We use Google for single sign-on to its services | Permanent |
| fbm  <br>fbsr | We use Facebook for single sign-on to its services | Permanent |
| PHPSESSID | We use this cookie to keep you authenticated to your BGA account. | Session |
| TournoiEnLigneid  <br>TournoiEnLignetk | Used to keep you connected to your BGA account ("Rememeber me" feature) | 12 months |
| TournoiEnLigneidt  <br>TournoiEnLignetkt  <br>TournoiEnLigne\_sso\_id  <br>TournoiEnLigne\_sso\_user | Used to keep you connected during your current session | Session |

You can opt out of and delete them using your browser settings. However, you will no longer be able to access your account.

##### b. Analysis cookies

We use these cookies to measure and improve the performance of our Site. They help us to find out which pages are the most or least visited and to see how visitors browse on the Site. All information collected by these cookies is aggregated and therefore, is anonymous.

For more information on these cookies:

| Cookie name | Purpose of the cookie | Cookie duration |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_ga  <br>\_gat  <br>\_gid | We use Google Analytics to collect and analyse performance information. This information allows us to improve the interest, the ergonomics and the functioning of the services offered on the site (for example, the pages most often consulted, searches by Internet users in the site's engine, etc.). In order to comply with the regulations in force, the necessary measures have been taken to force the use of a secure exchange protocol (HTTPS) and to anonymise the IP addresses transiting through Google Analytics, thus making it impossible to pinpoint your precise geolocation via your IP address. These provisions allow us to measure the frequentation while preserving the anonymity of the collected data. These cookies are used only if you give your consent through our cookie banner; you can reset your choice to re-display the authorization banner at any time by clicking on [this link](#). | 13 months |

#### 3\. Policy update

We may change this Policy from time to time, for example, to take into account legal changes, technological progress and best business practices. We will inform you if there are any substantial changes.

#### 4\. Contact

For any questions on the cookies used on our Site, you can [contact us](https://boardgamearena.com/support).

Policy updated on July 21st 2022.

### Politique relative aux cookies

Cette politique relative aux cookies (« Politique ») est définie par AD2G (ci-après « AD2G Studio » ou « nous ») et régit l’utilisation des cookies sur le site boardgamearena.com (le « Site »).

La Politique vous informe des finalités pour lesquelles nous utilisons ces cookies et la manière dont vous pouvez les gérer.

Nous pouvons collecter, en qualité de responsable de traitement, des données personnelles vous concernant grâce aux cookies que nous installons sur le Site. Pour davantage d’informations sur la manière dont vos données personnelles sont traitées dans ce cadre, veuillez lire notre politique relative à la [protection des données personnelles.](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac)

**1\. Qu’est-ce qu’un cookie ?**

**2\. Quels cookies utilisons-nous, pour quelles finalités et comment les contrôler ?**

**3\. Mise à jour de la Politique**

**4\. Contact**

#### 1\. Qu’est-ce qu’un cookie ?

Un « cookie » est une suite d'informations, généralement de petite taille et identifié par un nom, qui peut être transmis à votre navigateur par un site web sur lequel vous vous connectez. Votre navigateur web le conservera pendant une certaine durée, et le renverra au serveur web chaque fois que vous vous y reconnecterez.

Il existe différents types de cookies :

• **Cookies temporaires et cookies permanents** : les cookies temporaires sont automatiquement supprimés à la fin de votre session de navigation. Les cookies permanents restent plus longtemps sur votre appareil, pendant la durée spécifique à chaque cookie, et restent valables jusqu’à leur date d’expiration (à moins qu’ils ne soient supprimés par l’utilisateur avant).

• **Cookies propriétaires et cookies tiers** : les cookies propriétaires sont les cookies installés par le domaine du Site (ces cookies sont ceux installés par AD2G). Les cookies tiers sont ceux placés sur l’ordinateur de l’internaute par le serveur d’un domaine distinct de celui du Site (il peut s’agir par exemple de cookies de réseaux sociaux ou d’éditeurs de solutions de mesure d’audience).

En l’occurrence, les cookies installés sur votre terminal ne nécessitent pas votre consentement préalable. En effet, ils ont pour finalité exclusive de permettre ou faciliter la communication par voie électronique, ou sont strictement nécessaires à la fourniture d'un service de communication en ligne à votre demande expresse.

#### 2\. Quels cookies utilisons-nous, pour quelles finalités et comment les contrôler ?

Le tableau ci-dessous répertorie les différents types de cookies utilisés sur le Site, ainsi que leur(s) finalité(s) et leur durée de vie.

##### a. Cookies fonctionnels

Ces cookies permettent au Site de fonctionner de manière optimale. Ils sont généralement installés pour répondre à des actions que vous avez effectuées ou à une demande de services, comme votre authentification pour accéder à votre compte ou l’achat en ligne d’un abonnement Premium.

| Nom du cookie | Finalité du cookie | Durée du cookie |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_stripe\_mid | Nous utilisons Stripe pour faciliter le paiement par carte bancaire sans stocker d’informations sur les cartes de crédit sur les propres serveurs de stripe. | 12 mois |
| cC  | Nous utilisons ce cookie pour enregistrer les préférences de chaque utilisateur en matière de cookies | 6 mois |
| G\_ENABLED\_IDPS | Nous utilisons Google pour l’authentification unique auprès de ses services | Persistant |
| fbm  <br>fbsr | Nous utilisons Facebook pour l’authentification unique auprès de ses services | Persistant |
| PHPSESSID | Nous utilisons ce cookie pour vous garder authentifié à votre compte BGA. | Session |
| TournoiEnLigneid  <br>TournoiEnLignetk | Utilisé pour vous garder connecté à votre compte BGA (fonction "Se souvenir de moi") | 12 months |
| TournoiEnLigneidt  <br>TournoiEnLignetkt  <br>TournoiEnLigne\_sso\_id  <br>TournoiEnLigne\_sso\_user | Utilisé pour vous garder connecté lors de votre session courante | Session |

Vous pouvez vous y opposer et les supprimer en utilisant les paramètres de votre navigateur, cependant vous ne serez plus à même d’accéder à votre compte.

##### b. Cookies d’analyse

Ces cookies nous permettent de mesurer et améliorer les performances de notre Site. Ils nous aident à savoir quelles pages sont les plus ou moins consultées et à voir comment les visiteurs naviguent sur le Site. Toutes les informations collectées par ces cookies sont agrégées et donc anonymes.

Pour plus d’information sur ces cookies :

| Nom du cookie | Finalité du cookie | Durée du cookie |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_ga  <br>\_gat  <br>\_gid | Nous utilisons Google Analytics pour la collecte et l'analyse d'informations de performance. Ces informations nous permettent d’améliorer l’intérêt, l’ergonomie et le fonctionnement des services proposés sur le site (par exemple, les pages le plus souvent consultées, recherches des internautes dans le moteur du site...). Afin de rester en conformité avec la réglementation en vigueur, les dispositions nécessaires ont été prise afin de forcer l'utilisation d'un protocole d'échange sécurisé (HTTPS) et d'anonymiser les adresses IPs transitant sur Google Analytics, ceci permettant de rendre impossible votre géolocalisation précise via votre adresse IP. Ces dispositions nous autorisent à mesurer la fréquentation tout en préservant l'anonymat des données récoltées. Ces cookies sont uniquement utilisés si vous donnez votre consentement via notre bannière d'autorisation des cookies ; vous pouvez réinitialiser votre choix pour ré-afficher la bannière d'autorisation à n'importe quel moment en cliquant sur [ce lien](#). | 13 mois |

#### 3\. Mise à jour de la Politique

Nous pouvons modifier la présente Politique occasionnellement, par exemple pour prendre en compte les changements légaux, les avancées technologiques et les bonnes pratiques commerciales. Nous vous informerons en cas de changement substantiel.

#### 4\. Contact

Pour toute question concernant les cookies utilisés sur notre Site, vous pouvez [nous contacter](https://boardgamearena.com/support)  

Politique mise à jour le 21 juillet 2022.

### Conditions Générales d’Utilisation

Bienvenue sur BGA :)

Le site Internet boardgamearena.com (ci-après le « Site Joueurs »), le site Internet studio.boardgamearena.com (ci-après le « Site Développeurs ») (ensemble les « Sites BGA ») et les services décrits dans les présentes Conditions Générales d’Utilisation sont édités, exploités et fournis par la société AD2G Studio dont les coordonnées complètes sont disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) pour le Site Joueur et [ici](https://studio.boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) pour le Site Développeurs (ci-après « BGA »).

Les Sites BGA sont hébergés par la société OVH, dont les coordonnées sont disponibles [sur leur site internet](https://www.ovh.com/).

#### I. Objet des présentes Conditions Générales d’Utilisation

Les présentes Conditions Générales d’Utilisation (C.G.U.) ont pour objet de définir les conditions d’utilisation des Sites BGA et des Services y accessibles gratuitement et sans création préalable d’un Compte.

Les Services accessibles gratuitement sous réserve de la création préalable d’un Compte depuis le Site Développeurs, leurs conditions et modalités, sont détaillés dans les C.G.S. Développeurs disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://studio.boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos).

Les Services accessibles, gratuitement ou non, sous réserve de la création préalable d’un Compte depuis le Site Joueurs, leurs conditions et modalités, sont détaillés dans les C.G.S. Joueurs disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos).

#### II. Réclamation – Assistance technique

Le service client de BGA peut être contacté via le formulaire de contact.

#### III. Définitions

Pour les besoins des présentes C.G.U., les termes en majuscules, qu’ils soient employés au singulier ou au pluriel, ont la signification suivante :

« Application(s) » : désignent les jeux accessibles depuis le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur, et/ou les jeux accessibles seulement depuis le Site Développeur car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie des Codes des Utilisateurs, édités par BGA et/ou ses Filiales ainsi que tout logiciel accessoire qui serait par exemple nécessaires comme une mise à jour de l’Application, une mise à niveau de l’Application, son code (en tout ou partie), les fichiers la composant, les images associées ou générées et les données associées mais également les applications non accessibles depuis les Sites BGA, car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie de Codes d’Utilisateurs ;

« BGA » : désigne la société AD2G STUDIO, société par actions simplifiée, au capital social de 100,00 €, dont le siège social est situé au 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, immatriculée au Registre du Commerce et des Sociétés de Nanterre sous le numéro 803 287 150 représentée par Monsieur Alexandre Schlecht agissant et ayant les pouvoirs nécessaires en tant que président.

« C.G.U. » : désigne les présentes Conditions Générales d’Utilisation ;

« C.G.S. Développeurs » : désigne les Conditions Générales de Services accessibles relatives aux Services accessibles depuis le Site Développeurs ;

« C.G.S. Joueurs » : désigne les Conditions Générales de Services relatives aux Services accessibles depuis le Site Joueurs ;

« Compte » : désigne l’espace personnel d’un Utilisateur uniquement accessible avec des Eléments d’identification transmis par BGA lui permettant d’accéder et de bénéficier des Services ;

« Compte Tiers » : désigne un compte auquel l’Utilisateur a souscrit auprès d’un éditeur tiers et qui peut être lié à un Compte (par exemple Google ou Facebook) ;

« Contenu(s) » : désigne(nt) le(s) contenu(s) de toute nature (notamment des données textuelles, visuelles, vidéos, photographiques, espace de discussion, avis, etc. publiés(s) sur les Sites BGA grâce aux Services, par un Utilisateur sous sa responsabilité ;

« Données d’Identification » : désignent toute information renseignée par l’Utilisateur permettant à ce dernier de créer un Compte (adresse email, âge, localisation, etc.);

« Donnée(s) Personnelle(s) » : désigne(nt) les données à caractère personnel d’un Utilisateur ou d’un Internaute et collectées et traitées par BGA dans le cadre de la consultation des Sites BGA, comme, le cas échéant, la création et la gestion de son Compte et la réalisation des Services, et ce dans les conditions et modalités telles que définies dans la Politique de Confidentialité ;

« Elément d’identification » : désigne l’identifiant de connexion (« login » ou adresse de courrier électronique) et mot de passe (« password ») définis et/ou transmis pour partie initialement par BGA à l’Utilisateur, à charge pour lui de modifier son mot de passe lors de sa première connexion et lui permettant d’accéder à son Compte ;

« Filiale(s) » : désigne toute société ou entité qui contrôle directement ou indirectement ou qui est contrôlée par ou sous contrôle commun avec BGA. Le contrôle d’une entité signifie la possession, directement ou indirectement, du pouvoir de diriger ou de faire diriger la gestion ou les politiques d’une telle entité, que ce soit par la propriété des titres avec droit de vote, par contrat ou autrement ;

« Internaute » : désigne l’ensemble des internautes, visiteurs des Sites BGA, disposant ou non d’un Compte ;

« Nom d’Utilisateur » : désigne une série de caractères permettant à l’Utilisateur, avec un mot de passe déterminé par ses soins, de se connecter de manière unique à son Compte et d’accéder aux Services ;

« Politique de confidentialité »: désigne la politique de confidentialité et de protection des Données Personnelles des Utilisateurs mise en œuvre par BGA et accessible en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac), laquelle fait partie intégrante des présentes C.G.U. ;

« Services » : désignent les fonctionnalités et services gratuits mis à la disposition des Internautes et accessibles, à l’aide d’un Support de Réception, depuis les Sites BGA sans Compte ainsi que les fonctionnalités et services gratuits ou payants, tels que déterminés dans les C.G.S. Développeurs et les C.G.S. Joueurs et accessibles depuis les Sites BGA avec un Compte, aux Utilisateurs.

« Site(s) BGA » : désigne indistinctement le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur ;

« Site Développeur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL studio.boardgamearena.com ;

« Site Joueur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL boardgamearena.com ;

« Support(s) de Réception » : désigne(nt) les ordinateurs, tablettes, smartphones, télévision, utilisés pour accéder aux Sites BGA et pouvoir utiliser les Applications et bénéficiant a minima d’un navigateur récent et à jour ;

« Traduction » : désigne les éléments littéraires et/ou textuels d’une Application et/ou des Sites BGA et faisant l’objet d’une traduction dans une langue différente par l’Utilisateur ;

« Utilisateur(s) » : désigne toute personne physique de quinze (15) ans minimum et capable ou disposant d’une autorisation parentale pour ce faire, y compris représentant légal (dirigeant, préposé, etc.) d’une personne morale agissant pour son compte, souscrivant pour ce faire, à l’aide d’un Support de Réception, l’ouverture d’un Compte sur le Site Développeur et/ou sur le Site Développeur et n’étant soumise à aucune interdiction et/ou restriction légale, réglementaire ou conventionnelle l’empêchant d’accéder et/ou d’utiliser depuis un Support de Réception des Applications et/ou de développer des Développements et/ou céder les Développements à BGA et/ou de réaliser des Traductions et/ou céder les Traductions à BGA et/ou diffuser du Contenu et ayant rempli, le cas échéant, l’ensemble des formalités légales, réglementaires et conventionnelles pour ce faire, en vue d’utiliser les Services ;

#### IV. Champ d’application, acceptation et modification des C.G.U.

L'accès ou l'utilisation de tout ou partie des Sites BGA implique(nt) l'acceptation sans restriction ni réserves des présentes C.G.U. par l’Internaute.

Les présentes C.G.U. pouvant faire l'objet de modifications, les conditions applicables sont celles en vigueur et accessibles sur les Sites BGA à la date d'accès aux Sites BGA par l’Internaute. A cet égard, BGA peut faire évoluer librement à tout moment les C.G.U. afin de les adapter aux évolutions des Services et/ou des Applications et/ou des Sites BGA et/ou de leur exploitation. Ces modifications sont portées à la connaissance des Internautes par leur simple mise en ligne et sont réputées acceptées sans réserve.

#### V. Description des Services

BGA met à la disposition des Internautes, au travers des Sites BGA, l’accès à un certain nombre de Services visant à lui permettre en particulier de prendre connaissance du contenu éditorial édité par BGA et du Contenu partagés par les Utilisateurs.

Les Sites BGA permettent également aux Utilisateurs d’accéder à d’autres services détaillés dans les C.G.S. Développeurs et/ou les C.G.S. Joueurs après création d’un Compte sur le Site BGA concerné et sous réserve d’acceptation préalable desdites C.G.S.

L'ensemble des Services fournis par BGA et mis à disposition de l’Internaute est détaillé sur les Sites BGA concernés.

BGA propose comme Service la mise à disposition d’un système de chat audio/vidéo optionnel pouvant être utilisé pendant l’utilisation des Applications.

Toute interaction entre Utilisateurs dans un salon de discussion audio/vidéo en temps réel est privée et relève de la seule responsabilité de ces derniers.

BGA n'enregistre pas l'activité de ce système de chat audio/vidéo mais tout Utilisateur a la capacité technique de le faire bien que BGA l’interdise formellement. Par conséquent, les Utilisateurs ne doivent rien faire ou dire qu’ils ne souhaiteraient pas voir enregistré.

BGA ne pourra être tenue responsable de tout inconvénient ou dommage directement ou indirectement lié à l'utilisation de ce Service.

#### VI. Accès et disponibilité des Services

BGA fait ses meilleurs efforts afin de rendre ses Services disponibles 24 heures sur 24 et 7 jours sur 7, indépendamment des opérations de maintenance desdits Services et/ou des Sites BGA.

Toutefois, c'est en toute connaissance de cause que l’Internaute se rend sur les Sites, et/ou utilise les Services qui offrent des Contenus accessibles selon la qualité du réseau Internet.

Notamment, BGA se réserve le droit d'interrompre l’accès à tout ou partie des Services pour des travaux de maintenance et/ou d'amélioration. Ces interruptions des Services et/ou des Sites BGA seront, dans la mesure des possibilités de BGA, préalablement notifiées à l’Internaute, en particulier par la diffusion d’un message d’alerte sur le Site BGA concerné. En cas d'urgence, BGA se réserve néanmoins le droit de suspendre partiellement ou totalement, pendant une durée raisonnable, tout ou partie des Services et/ou du Site BGA concerné pour conduire toute opération technique requise. Ces interruptions des Services et/ou des Sites BGA ne pourront donner lieu à une quelconque indemnisation en faveur de l’Internaute.

L'accès aux Sites BGA peut également être interrompu pour toutes autres raisons, notamment techniques, sans aucune obligation d'information préalable.

La modification des Sites BGA peut également être réalisée par BGA, pour des raisons qui lui sont propres, notamment techniques, et entrainer notamment des modifications de Services ou de fonctionnalités, sans aucune obligation d'information préalable.

BGA ne pourra être tenue responsable des interruptions ou de la non-réception des Services dues à une quelconque défaillance des Supports de Réception ainsi qu’en cas de mauvais fonctionnement, défaillance ou prestation insuffisante des opérateurs utilisés par l’Utilisateur pour accéder aux Services.

A ce titre, BGA est tenue d’une obligation de moyens.

#### VII. Garanties – Responsabilités

##### A. Garanties de l’Internaute

##### 

En accédant aux Sites BGA, l’Internaute déclare, garantit et s'engage à :

• accéder et utiliser les Sites BGA et/ou les Applications et/ou les Services en toute bonne foi, de manière raisonnable, non contraire aux termes des présentes C.G.U. ;

• ne pas utiliser de dispositifs ou logiciels autres que ceux fournis par BGA destinés à i) affecter ou tenter d'affecter le bon fonctionnement des Sites BGA et/ou des Applications et/ou des Services ii) ou encore d'extraire, modifier, consulter, même en mémoire tampon ou temporaire, ou encore pour une utilisation individualisée, tout ou partie des Sites BGA et/ou des Services ;

• ne pas accéder et/ou utiliser les Sites BGA et/ou les Applications et/ou les Services à des fins illicites et/ou dans le but de causer un préjudice à la réputation et/ou à l'image de BGA, des Filiales et/ou des Internautes, ou plus généralement à porter atteinte aux droits, notamment de propriété intellectuelle, de BGA et/ou de tiers, en ce compris les Internautes ;

• ne pas commercialiser directement ou indirectement les Services et/ou les Applications et/ou les Contenus et/ou l'accès aux Services et/ou aux Sites BGA et/ou aux Applications et/ou aux Contenus ;

• ne pas limiter l'accès et l’utilisation des Sites BGA et/ou des Services et/ou des Applications ;

• ne pas modifier, y compris en mémoire tampon ou temporaire, aucune mention ou élément des Sites BGA et/ou des Services et/ou des Applications autrement que dans les conditions des présentes C.G.U. et/ou des C.G.S. Joueurs et/ou des C.G.S. Développeurs ;

We are happy when you modify the website while respecting its rules (ex: for translations), this \`do not modify\` above address what may be done outside the rules ;)

• s’assurer que l’utilisation des Sites BGA et/ou des Services et/ou des Applications n’affecte, ni ne compromette la stabilité, la sécurité et la qualité des Sites BGA et/ou des Applications et/ou des Services, des réseaux, de la bande passante, ou des infrastructures de BGA, des autres Internautes et/ou des tiers.

• ne pas contrevenir aux dispositions des articles 323-1 à 323-7 du Code pénal français réprimant les pratiques dites de "hacking" ;

• ne pas utiliser et/ou exploiter les coordonnées électroniques et/ou postales des autres Internautes à d’autres fins que l’utilisation des Services et/ou des Sites BGA, en particulier en vue de l'envoi en masse de sollicitations et de se livrer à une pratique de "spamming".

• ne pas réutiliser, ni exploiter tout ou partie des Sites BGA et/ou des Services et/ou des Applications qu’ils contiennent, en particulier à des fins commerciales et/ou collectives et/ou à des fins personnelles sous une forme et/ou un média non autorisé par BGA et/ou les propriétaires du/des Contenu(s) et/ou des Applications en question ;

About \`re-using\`: we are obviously happy when you share your experience on BGA on medias :) The previous statement is more about re-using pieces of BGA for another service.

• ne pas utiliser son Compte et/ou les Services, afin de se livrer à des actes, de quelle que nature que ce soit, comme l'émission, l'édition, la mise en ligne de données ou Contenus contraires à la loi, portant atteinte à l'ordre public, aux droits de BGA, d’autres Utilisateurs ou des tiers ;

• ne pas diffuser du Contenu, sur le Site Joueur et/ou les Applications et/ou à l’aide des Services, illicites, en particulier qui porterait atteinte aux droits de tiers, violerait une loi applicable, en particulier la Loi du 29 juillet 1881 sur la liberté de la presse, et/ou constituerait la contrefaçon ou la violation de tout droit de propriété intellectuelle, savoir-faire, secret d’affaires, ou droit de la personnalité d’un tiers (vie privée, droit à l’image, etc.), comme susceptible de faire l’objet de toute action en concurrence déloyale et/ou parasitisme comme plus généralement une action en responsabilité ;

• ne pas diffuser du Contenu sur le Site Joueur et/ou les Applications et/ou à l’aide des Services incitant à la haine ou à la violence, menaçants, qui aurait un caractère agressif, à caractère pornographique, à des fins de proxénétisme, pédophilie, obscène, vulgaire, raciste, sexuellement explicite, violent, contraire aux bonnes mœurs xénophobe piratage informatique ou prosélytisme ou contenant de la nudité ou de la violence gratuite, comme plus généralement une action en responsabilité ;

• ne pas collecter ou intercepter par tout moyen qui ne serait pas expressément permis par BGA des données échangées par les autres Utilisateurs dans le cadre des Services, ou les Eléments d’Identification de tout autre Utilisateur ;

• ne pas diffuser du Contenu qui serait contraire aux intérêts légitimes de BGA ;

• ne pas obtenir des informations concernant des Utilisateurs, les Contenus qu'ils publient à l'aide de méthodes automatisées (telles que robots, araignées, etc.) ;ne pas utiliser les Services et/ou les Sites BGA à l'aide de méthodes automatisées (telles que robots, araignées, requêtes multiples, etc.) ;

• ne pas télécharger vers le Site Joueur et/ou les Applications des virus ou autres codes malveillants ;

• ne pas remplacer toute fonctionnalité de sécurité ou contourner ou éviter tout contrôle d’accès aux Services ;

• ne pas intimider et harceler d'autres Utilisateurs, le cas échéant à l’aide des Services ;

• ne pas publier des documents officiels ou informations financières concernant autrui ;

• ne pas faire la promotion ou publier de Contenus liés aux boissons alcoolisées ou pour adultes sans restriction d'accès liée à l'âge ou encore d’autres sites Internet de jeux en ligne quels qu’ils soient sous réserve des dispositions relatives à la liberté d’expression ;

• ne pas proposer des concours ou loteries ("promotions"), sans le consentement écrit préalable de BGA ;

The statement above is obviously not related to the competitions that are part of the BGA service offer, like tournaments.

• ne pas créer plusieurs Comptes : l’Utilisateur s'engage à ne créer qu'un seul Compte lui correspondant. Si BGA supprime le Compte d’un Utilisateur en cas de non-respect des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, l’Utilisateur s’engage à ne pas créer un autre Compte sans autorisation préalable de BGA ;

• ne pas communiquer ses Eléments d’identification à un tiers et laisser quelqu'un accéder à son Compte ou faire quoi que ce soit qui puisse compromettre la sécurité de son Compte ;

• ne pas utiliser le Site Joueur et/ou les Services et/ou les Applications en usurpant l’identité d’un tiers, y compris une personne morale (comme BGA) ou en affirmant, à tort, représenter légalement ou non un tiers y compris une personne morale (comme BGA) ;

• ne pas faire un usage inapproprié du service d'assistance aux Applications ou des boutons de réclamation ou envoyer des rapports mensongers aux membres du personnel de BGA et/ou de ses partenaires ;

• ne pas communiquer de Contenu ne relevant pas du sujet ou du thème de l’espace de discussion ;

• ne pas mettre en place de liens hypertextes à destination de pages profondes du Site Joueur, permettant l’accès aux Services et ce, par quelconque procédé technique destinés à passer outre le champ d’identification des Utilisateurs ou à procéder à l’aspiration de tout ou partie du contenu des Services mis à disposition par BGA.

• ne pas permettre et encourager le non-respect de l’une quelconque des dispositions des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs ;

En cas de manquement à l'une ou l'autre de ces obligations, sans que cette liste ne soit limitative, l’Internaute est informé que BGA aura la faculté de lui refuser ou lui suspendre, unilatéralement et sans notification préalable, l'accès à tout ou partie des Services et/ou des Sites BGA et à suspendre, le cas échéant, l’accès à son Compte.

L’Utilisateur garantit et indemnise BGA, ainsi que les Filiales, leurs représentants, leurs salariés, leurs partenaires, et/ou tous tiers, contre tout dommage, plainte ou demande émanant de tiers suite une utilisation ne respectant pas les présentes C.G.U. Cette garantie couvre les indemnités qui seraient éventuellement dues ainsi que les honoraires d'avocats et frais de justice dans une limite raisonnable.

L’Internaute accepte et reconnaît que BGA ne peut notamment garantir :

• que les contenus des Sites BGA mais également les Contenus sont conformes à ses attentes et à ses recherches ;

• la véracité, la complétude, la conformité et/ou l’adéquation des Contenus qui sont diffusés par les Utilisateurs sur les Sites BGA sous leur responsabilité et hébergés par BGA ;

• la qualité des interactions avec les autres Internautes et/ou Utilisateurs, ni même de la rapidité avec laquelle elles lui sont apportées par ces derniers ;

• et plus généralement aux besoins particuliers de l’Internaute.

BGA est également un tiers aux correspondances et relations entre les Utilisateurs et les Internautes et/ou Utilisateurs, et exclut de ce fait toute responsabilité à cet égard.

Aussi, l’Internaute accepte sans réserve que si la responsabilité de BGA devait être engagée directement ou indirectement en sa qualité d'intermédiaire technique, par quelque personne ou entité que ce soit, BGA se réserve le droit de prendre, promptement et de plein droit, toute mesure administrative et/ou technique, en ce compris à l’égard de l’Internaute permettant de sauvegarder ses intérêts et/ou de se conformer aux obligations qui lui incombent.

##### B. Garanties de BGA

BGA met à la disposition de l’Internaute, au travers de ses Sites BGA, l'accès à un certain nombre de Services visant à l'accompagner dans le cadre de ses interactions avec les Utilisateurs.

BGA ne garantit pas la pérennité du Contenu que l’Utilisateur publie sur les Services, et/ou des Applications qui peut/peuvent disparaître pour n'importe quelle raison. C'est pourquoi l’Utilisateur doit faire lui-même ses propres sauvegardes des Contenus. L'accès au Site Joueur, aux Applications et aux Services requiert une connexion Internet dont l’Utilisateur assure complètement la charge et la responsabilité.

BGA n’intervient pas dans les relations, en particulier juridiques, entre les Internautes et les Utilisateurs ou entre les Utilisateurs eux-mêmes. Ils leur incombent donc de réaliser les vérifications d’usage, notamment d’ordre légal, avant de conclure tout accord avec un Utilisateur qui n’engage qu’eux.

En toute hypothèse, BGA ne garantit pas :

• la mise à jour permanente des Services, des Sites BGA et des Applications ;

• l’absence d’interruption des fonctionnalités des Services, de la présence de virus ou tout autre composant nuisible dans les Services ou les serveurs qui les font fonctionner et que les défauts dans le fonctionnement ou les fonctionnalités du Site Joueur, des Applications et des Services seront corrigés ;

• que l'utilisation des Sites BGA, des Applications et des Services répondra à ses besoins ;

• que toute information que l’Utilisateur aura obtenue en utilisant les Sites BGA, les Applications et/ou les Services (s) sera exacte ou fiable.

Les Services, les Sites BGA et les Applications sont fournis en l'état et BGA n'accorde aucune garantie à cet égard.

L’Internaute reconnait être seul responsable des dommages causés à BGA et/ou aux autres Utilisateurs ou à toute personne physique ou morale tierce, le cas-échéant, du fait d’une utilisation des Services et/ou des Sites BGA et/ou des Applications.

Dans cette hypothèse BGA se réserve le droit de supprimer son Compte, ainsi que d’agir en justice sur les fondements de la responsabilité civile et/ou pénale pour mettre fin à la violation et réparer son préjudice.

#### VIII. Fair-Play

BGA ne tolérera aucune tricherie et/ou aucun manque de fair-play, que ce soit par l’utilisation de logiciels de triche, l’analyse des protocoles de communication ou du code, l’utilisation de plusieurs Comptes, la complicité d’autres Utilisateurs, toute sortie du jeu avant sa fin normale, l’utilisation de tactiques de blocage du jeu dans le but de forcer les autres Utilisateurs à abandonner ou l’utilisation d’un langage obscène ou grossier, etc.

Tout Utilisateur pris à tricher ou à manquer à ses obligations de fair-play recevra un avertissement, puis sera passible de l’une des sanctions suivantes à la discrétion de BGA :

◦ gel du Compte,

◦ remise à zéro de ses scores et classements,

◦ suspension des Services,

◦ voire de la suppression pure et simple de son Compte.

L’atteinte par l’Utilisateur aux règles de conduite ou aux règles essentielles du fair play peuvent avoir des conséquences sur sa réputation sur le Site Joueur, dans les conditions et modalités précisées dans la Politique de confidentialité.

#### IX. Publicité

BGA se réserve la possibilité de diffuser des messages publicitaires ou promotionnels sur les Sites BGA, en ce compris dans le cadre des Services.

#### X. Limitation de responsabilité

BGA n’est responsable que des dommages directs causés par les Services, sauf en cas de fraude, de faute lourde ou intentionnelle, de force majeure, de décès ou dommage corporel et toute autre exclusion prévue par des dispositions législatives et réglementaires d’ordre public.

BGA ne saurait être responsable de :

• tout dommage indirect qui pourrait être causé à l’Internaute, y compris toute perte de profit (qu'elle soit directe ou indirecte), toute perte de chance ou de réputation qu’il pourrait subir ;

• dans le cadre d’une procédure introduite à l’encontre résultant de l’utilisation non-conforme des Services et/ou des Sites BGA et/ou des Applications par l’Internaute. L’Internaute reconnait et accepte à cet égard que l’Internaute fera son affaire personnelle de toute réclamation ou procédure formée contre BGA, du fait de l’utilisation non-conforme par lui des Services et/ou du Site Joueur et/ou des Applications.

• toute perte ou tout dommage que l’Internaute pourrit subir du fait de :

◦ l'inexactitude, l’illicéité, ou l’inadéquation des Contenus fournis par l’Internaute ou en cas de dommages consécutifs à l'utilisation d’un Contenu fourni par un Utilisateur tiers ;

◦ la confiance accordée à l'exhaustivité, l'exactitude ou l'existence de toute publicité ou résultant de toute relation ou transaction entre l’Internaute et l'un quelconque des annonceurs ou sponsors dont la publicité figure sur le Site Joueur et/ou sur les Applications ;

◦ tout changement que BGA pourrait apporter aux Sites BGA et/ou aux Applications et /ou aux Services ou toute suppression temporaire ou définitive d’un ou plusieurs Services ;

◦ la suppression, l’endommagement ou le défaut de stockage du Contenu et de toute autre donnée de communication conservée ou transmise dans le cadre des Services ;

◦ en cas d'indisponibilité des Services et/ou des Sites BGA et/ou des Applications pour des raisons telles que la défaillance du réseau public d'électricité, la défaillance des réseaux câblés de télécommunications, la perte de connectivité au réseau Internet due aux opérateurs publics ou privés, notamment de l’Utilisateur, dont les causes proviennent notamment de grèves, de tempêtes, de tremblements de terre ou de toute autre cause ayant les caractéristiques de la force majeure ;

◦ en cas d’utilisation des Services par un Utilisateur dans des conditions non-conformes aux C.G.U. et/ou aux C.G.S. Joueurs et/ou aux C.G.S. Développeurs ;

◦ le défaut de communication par l’Internaute à BGA des Données d’Identification ;

◦ l’incapacité de l’Internaute à conserver en toute sécurité et confidentialité ses Données d’Identification ou les informations de son Compte ;

◦ de non-respect de la législation d’un pays étranger où l’utilisation des Services et/ou les Applications et/ou le Site Joueur serait réalisé.

Les limitations de responsabilité de BGA à l’égard de l’Internaute s'appliqueront, que BGA ait été averti ou non de l'éventualité de la survenance de telles pertes et qu'il ait dû en avoir ou non connaissance.

#### XI. Contenu illicite

L’Utilisateur reconnait que BGA, en sa qualité d’hébergeur, au sens des dispositions de l’article 6-I-7 de la Loi n°2004-575 du 21 juin 2004, des Contenus que l’Utilisateur publie, n’exerce pas de contrôle a priori sur lesdits Contenus transmis via les Services et n’a pas d’obligation générale de surveillance des Contenus publiés.

N’ayant donc que le rôle d’hébergeur desdits Contenus diffusés sous la responsabilité exclusive des Utilisateurs, BGA ne peut donc intervenir sur les Contenus publiés dans le cadre des Services que dans le cas où un Contenu manifestement illicite lui serait signalé par un Utilisateur.

L’Utilisateur peut contacter BGA dont les coordonnées sont disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) pour le Site Joueur ou depuis un bouton dédié sur le Site « signaler ce Joueur ».

BGA se réservera le droit d’agir à son entière discrétion : à ce titre, BGA peut notamment demander l’arrêt de l’utilisation du Contenu et/ou retirer le Contenu des Services.

Si BGA supprime ou désactive un Contenu crée par un Utilisateur et qui est considéré comme étant manifestement illicite ou non conforme aux présentes aux C.G.U. et/ou aux C.G.S. Joueurs et/ou aux C.G.S. Développeurs, BGA se réserve le droit de suspendre ou de supprimer le Compte de l’Utilisateur.

Enfin, l’Utilisateur reconnaît et accepte que le fait, pour lui, de présenter un Contenu diffusé par un Utilisateur comme étant illicite dans le seul but d’en obtenir le retrait ou d’en faire cesser la diffusion, alors qu’il est conscient que cette information est inexacte, peut être poursuivi pénalement.

#### XII. Force majeure

La responsabilité de BGA ne pourra pas être recherchée si l'exécution de l'une de ses obligations est empêchée ou retardée en raison d'un cas de force majeure tel que définie à l’article 1218 du code civil et par la jurisprudence des Tribunaux français, et notamment les catastrophes naturelles, incendies, dysfonctionnement ou interruption du réseau de télécommunications ou du réseau électrique.

#### XIII. Propriété intellectuelle

La technique du "framing" qui consiste notamment à afficher en incrustation sur la page d’un site internet celle d’un autre site internet, est interdite en ce qui concerne les Sites BGA, sauf autorisation expresse et préalable de BGA.

##### A. Droits d’auteur sur les Sites BGA

BGA est le titulaire ou le concessionnaire des droits de propriété intellectuelle tant de la structure générale des Sites BGA que leur contenu (textes, slogans, graphiques, images, vidéos, photos, programmes et autres contenus), à l’exclusion de tout Contenu publié par l’Utilisateur. Dès lors, sans préjudice des dispositions de l’article XIII D, toute représentation, reproduction, modification, dénaturation et/ou exploitation totale ou partielle des Sites BGA et/ou des Services, par quelque procédé que ce soit et sur quelque support que ce soit, sans l’autorisation expresse et préalable de BGA, est prohibée et constitue des actes de contrefaçon de droits d’auteur.

About \`re-using\`: we are obviously happy when you share your experience on BGA on medias :) The previous statement is more about re-using pieces of BGA for another service.

De même, toute exploitation non autorisée des Sites BGA et/ou des Services engage la responsabilité pénale et civile de l’Internaute sur le fondement de la contrefaçon de droits d’auteur.

L’Internaute reconnaît et accepte que l’accès aux Sites BGA et/ou aux Services mis à disposition par BGA ne saurait emporter quelconque cession ou concession des droits de propriété intellectuelle (droits d’auteurs notamment) et autres droits de la personnalité (droit à l’image, au respect de la vie privée) au bénéfice de l’Internaute.

L’accès aux Sites BGA et aux Services est exclusivement limité à l’usage privé et personnel de l’Internaute dans les conditions et limites définies dans les présentes C.G.U.

##### B. Signes distinctifs

Les marques, logos, dénominations sociales, sigles, noms commerciaux, enseignes et/ou nom de domaine de BGA et/ou de ses partenaires mentionnés sur les Sites BGA, permettant l’accès aux Services mis à disposition par BGA, constituent des signes distinctifs insusceptibles d’utilisation sans l’autorisation expresse et préalable de leur titulaire.

Toute représentation et/ou reproduction et/ou exploitation partielle ou totale de ces signes distinctifs est donc prohibée et constitutif de contrefaçon de marque, d’usurpation de dénomination sociale, nom commercial et de nom de domaine engageant la responsabilité civile délictuelle de son auteur.

##### C. Publicité et liens hypertexte

Les liens hypertextes accessibles sur les Sites BGA et/ou dans le cadre des Services, en direction d’autres sites Internet et d’une manière générale vers toutes ressources existantes sur Internet ne sauraient engager la responsabilité de BGA.

L’Internaute ne pourra en aucun cas permettre ou utiliser des liens hypertextes à destination de pages profondes des Sites BGA, permettant l’accès aux Services et ce, par quelconque procédé technique destiné à passer outre le champ d’identification de l’Internaute ou à procéder à l’aspiration de tout ou partie du contenu des Services mis à disposition par BGA.

Les Services, les Applications et les Sites BGA et le cas échéant le Contenu peuvent contenir des hyperliens pointant vers d'autres sites Internet qui n'appartiennent pas à BGA. BGA n'exerce aucun contrôle sur les contenus, les conditions particulières de chaque offre de tiers de même que les conditions générales de vente, d’utilisation et les chartes de protection des données personnelles ou les pratiques des sites tiers et décline toute responsabilité à cet égard.

L’Internaute reconnait et accepte que BGA n'est pas responsable de la disponibilité de ces sites et ressources externes et ne cautionne ni la publicité, ni les produits ou autres liens ou données figurant sur ces sites Internet ou ressources externes, ou accessibles depuis ceux-ci.

L’Internaute reconnait et accepte que BGA ne peut être tenu responsable des pertes ou dommages que l’Internaute pourrait subir du fait de l’existence de ces sites ou ressources externes ou du fait de la confiance qu’il accorde quant à l'exhaustivité, l'exactitude ou l'existence de toute publicité, tout produit ou autres données sur ces sites Internet ou ressources externes, ou accessibles depuis ceux-ci.

Dans l’hypothèse où, selon l’Internaute, une offre de tiers référencée renfermerait des contenus illicites ou inappropriés, il peut le signaler à BGA dont les coordonnées sont disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/support) pour le Site Joueur.

##### D. Bases de données

L’Internaute reconnaît irrévocablement que les Sites BGA et les Services, en ce compris la structure et/ou l’ordonnancement des Contenus et/ou des Applications, sont constitués d'une ou plusieurs bases de données mis à la disposition des Internautes par BGA en qualité de producteur desdites bases de données au sens des dispositions des articles L.341-1 et suivants du Code de la propriété intellectuelle.

Dès lors, conformément aux dispositions de l'article L. 342-1 du même Code, l’Internaute s'interdit de procéder à :

• l'extraction par transfert permanent ou temporaire de la totalité ou d'une partie qualitativement ou quantitativement substantielle du contenu d'une ou plusieurs des bases des données accessibles sur les Sites BGA et/ou les Applications et/ou les Services, en ce compris la structure et/ou l’ordonnancement des Contenus, sur un autre support, par tout moyen et sous toute forme que ce soit, en ce compris à des fins d'utilisation ou de consultation par un média et/ou un procédé(s) non autorisé(s) par BGA ;

• la réutilisation, par la mise à la disposition du public de la totalité ou d'une partie qualitativement ou quantitativement substantielle du contenu d'une ou plusieurs des bases des données accessibles sur les Sites BGA et/ou les Services, en ce compris la structure et/ou l’ordonnancement des Contenus et/ou des Applications, quelle qu'en soit la forme, y compris par un lien hypertexte, un média et/ou un procédé(s) non autorisé(s) par BGA ;

• la constitution, l'édition, la maintenance, la mise à jour, l'importation, l'exportation, la mise à disposition de tiers, à titre gracieux ou onéreux, et la participation aux actes précités, d'une base de données concurrente issue de tout ou partie d'une ou plusieurs des bases de données de BGA ;

• la visualisation sur un écran par un autre procédé ou média que ceux par lesquels BGA entend divulguer les Sites BGA et les Services, les Applications, en ce compris la structure et/ou l’ordonnancement des Contenus et/ou des Applications ;

• d'une manière générale, toute extraction, utilisation, stockage, reproduction, représentation ou conservation, directe ou indirecte, partielle ou totale, y compris en mémoire tampon ou temporaire, qualitativement ou quantitativement substantielle du contenu d'une ou plusieurs des bases de données de BGA, commise par l'un des procédés visés ci-dessus est strictement prohibée, y compris par un média non autorisé par BGA.

##### E. Contenu des Services

L’Internaute reconnaît et accepte que l’accès aux Sites BGA et aux Services mis à sa disposition par BGA ne saurait emporter une quelconque cession ou concession des droits de propriété intellectuelle (droits d'auteurs notamment) et autres droits à son bénéfice. L’Internaute reconnaît et accepte que l'usage privé et personnel qui lui est concédé par BGA, au titre de l'accès à ses Services, exclut notamment l'accès aux Services en vue d'une utilisation collective de son contenu, la reproduction, la représentation, la revente, l'échange, la location, le transfert à un tiers, la modification, l'adaptation, la correction, et ce tant à titre gracieux qu'onéreux, de tout ou partie des Sites BGA, des Services, et de leurs contenus.

#### XIV. Protection des Données Personnelles

Les Données Personnelles de l’Internaute sont collectées et traitées par BGA, conformément à la Politique de confidentialité, accessible [ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac) et qui fait partie intégrante des présentes C.G.U.

#### XV. Dispositions diverses

##### A. Notifications

L’Internaute accepte que BGA lui adresse des notifications, y compris le cas échéant celles modifiant les présentes C.G.U., par courriel, ou par diffusion sur les Sites BGA, les Applications et, le cas échéant sur son Compte.

##### B. Correspondance – Preuve

Sauf disposition particulière des présentes C.G.U., les correspondances échangées entre l’Internaute et BGA sont principalement assurées par courrier électronique. En application des articles 1366 et suivants du Code civil, l’Utilisateur reconnait et accepte que les informations délivrées par BGA par courrier électronique et sur les Sites BGA fassent foi entre l’Internaute et BGA. Les éléments tels que le moment de la réception ou de l’émission, ainsi que la qualité des données reçues feront foi par priorité telles que figurant sur les Sites BGA, ou telles qu’authentifiées par les procédures informatisées de BGA, sauf à en apporter la preuve écrite et contraire par l’Internaute. La portée de la preuve des informations délivrées par les Sites BGA et/ou les Applications les procédures informatisées de BGA est celle accordée à un original au sens d’un document écrit papier, signé de manière manuscrite. Et si vous faites partie des 0.01% qui lisent les CGU entièrement, vous pouvez cliquer [ici](#).

##### C. Non renonciation.

L’Internaute reconnait que si BGA n'exerce pas ou ne fait pas valoir tout droit ou recours prévu aux présentes C.G.U. (ou dont BGA peut bénéficier en vertu de toute loi applicable), cela ne constitue pas une renonciation formelle de BGA ses droits, et ces droits et recours resteront valables et applicables pour BGA.

##### D. Non validité partielle

Si l'un des termes de ces C.G.U. est jugé nul par toute décision d'un tribunal compétent, celui-ci sera supprimé sans affecter les autres termes des C.G.U. Les termes restants demeureront valables et applicables.

##### E. Titres

En cas de difficultés d'interprétation entre l'un des titres figurant en tête des clauses des présentes C.G.U., et l'une des clauses, les titres seront déclarés inexistants.

##### F. Bénéficiaire des C.G.U.

L’Internaute reconnait et accepte que les Filiales soient considérées comme bénéficiaires des C.G.U.et que ces autres sociétés soient autorisées à faire valoir directement et à se fonder sur les termes de ces C.G.U. A l'exception de ce qui est précisé ici, aucune autre personne ou société ne sera considérée comme un tiers bénéficiaire des présentes C.G.U.

#### XVI. Droit applicable et règlement des litiges

Les présentes C.G.U ont été rédigées en français et en anglais, toutefois, seule la version française prévaudra en cas de difficulté d'interprétation.

Les présentes C.G.U. seront exécutées et interprétées conformément au droit français.

En cas de litige susceptible de survenir en rapport avec les présentes C.G.U., leur interprétation et leurs conséquences ou avec les actes les complétant ou les modifiant, l’Utilisateur se rapprochera de BGA aux fins de tenter d’obtenir une solution amiable.

Toute réclamation auprès de BGA doit être formulée de manière écrite.

A défaut de règlement amiable, l’Utilisateur peut choisir :

1) De recourir à une solution de médiation amiable dans un délai maximal d’un (1) an à compter de la réclamation écrite de l’Internaute l’attention de BGA :

(i) soit en saisissant un médiateur de la consommation en vue de la résolution amiable du litige. À cet effet, le différend sera soumis à la médiation conformément au règlement de médiation du CMAP - Centre de médiation et d’arbitrage de Paris - près la Chambre de commerce et d’industrie de Paris Ile-de-France ;

(ii) soit en ayant recours au système de règlement en ligne des litiges accessible à l’adresse suivante :https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/odr/main/index.cfm?event=main.home.chooseLanguageétant précisé que le processus de médiation proposé ne saurait être une condition préalable à une saisie des tribunaux compétents par l’Internaute.

2) De porter sa réclamation devant les juridictions françaises compétentes.

### General Terms of Use

The website boardgamearena.com (hereinafter the "Player Site"), the website studio.boardgamearena.com (hereinafter the "Developer Site") (together the "BGA Sites") and the services described in these General Conditions of User are published, operated and provided by AD2G Studio, the full contact details of which are available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) for the Player Site and [here](https://studio.boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) for the Developer Site (hereinafter "BGA").

The BGA websites are hosted by OVH, whose contact details are available by [clicking here](https://www.ovh.com/).

#### I. Purpose of these General Terms of Use

The purpose of these General Terms of Use (G.T.U.) is to define the conditions of use of the BGA Sites and the Services accessible there free of charge and without prior creation of an Account.

The Services accessible free of charge subject to the prior creation of an Account from the Developer Site, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the Developer G.T.S.

The Services accessible, free of charge or not, subject to the prior creation of an Account from the Player Site, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the Player G.T.S.

#### II. Claims - Technical assistance

BGA's customer service can be contacted using the contact details available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/support).

#### III. Definitions

For the purposes of these G.T.U., capitalised terms, whether in the singular or plural, have the following meaning:

"Account": means the personal space of a User that is only accessible with identification details transmitted by BGA allowing them to access and benefit from the Services;

"Application(s)": means the games accessible from the Developer Site and/or the Player Site, and/or the games accessible only from the Developer Site because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes, published by BGA and/or its Subsidiaries as well as any accessory software which may be necessary, such as an Application update, an Application upgrade, its code (in whole or in part), the files it contains, the associated or generated images and the associated data but also the applications not accessible from the BGA Sites, because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes;

"BGA" means the company AD2G STUDIO, a simplified joint-stock company with a share capital of €100.00, whose registered office is located at 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, registered with the Nanterre Trade and Companies Register under number 803 287 150, represented by Mr. Alexandre Schlecht acting and having the necessary powers as Chairman.

"BGA Site(s): means the Developer Site and/or the Player Site;

"Content(s)": means content of any kind (including textual, visual, video, photographic data, chat rooms, opinions, etc.) published on the BGA Sites through the Services, by a User under their responsibility;

"Developer G.T.S.": means the General Terms of Service and relating to the Services accessible from the Developer Site;

"Developer Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address studio.boardgamearena.com;

"G.T.U. ": means these General Terms of Use;

"Identification Data": means any information provided by the User to create an Account (email address, age, location, etc.);

"Identifier": means the connection identifier ("login" or email address) and password defined and/or transmitted in part initially by BGA to the User, who is responsible for changing their password on their first connection and enabling them to access their Account;

"Internet user": refers to all Internet users, visitors to the BGA Sites, whether or not they have an Account;

"Personal Data": means the personal data of a User or Internet user collected and processed by BGA in the context of consulting the BGA Sites, such as, where applicable, the creation and management of their Account and the provision of the Services, under the terms and conditions defined in the Privacy Policy;

"Player G.T.S.": means the General Terms of Service relating to the Services accessible from the Player Site;

"Player Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address boardgamearena.com;

"Privacy Policy": means the privacy and protection of Users' Personal Data policy implemented by BGA and accessible by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac) which form an integral part of these G.T.U.;

"Receiving medium(s)": means the computers, tablets, smartphones and televisions used to access the BGA Sites and to use the Applications, and which have at least a recent and up-to-date browser;

"Services": means the free features and services made available to Internet Users and accessible, using a Receiving Medium, from the BGA Sites without an Account as well as the free or paying features and services, as determined in the Developer G.T.S. and Player G.T.S. accessible from the BGA Sites with an Account, to Users.

"Subsidiary(ies)": means any company or entity that directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by or under common control with BGA. Control of an entity means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or have directed the management or policies of any such entity, whether through ownership of voting securities, by contract or otherwise;

"Third Party Account": means an account to which the User has subscribed with a third party publisher and which may be linked to an Account (for example Google or Facebook);

"Translation": means the literary and/or textual elements of an Application and/or the BGA Sites that are translated into a different language by the User;

"User(s)": means any natural person at least fifteen (15) years old who is capable or has parental authorisation to do so, including the legal representative (manager, employee, etc.) of a legal entity acting on its behalf, who opens an Account, using a Receiving Medium, on the Player Site and/or Developer Site and who is not subject to any legal, regulatory or contractual prohibition and/or restriction preventing them from accessing and/or using, from a Receiving Medium, the Applications and/or developing Developments and/or assigning Developments to BGA and/or performing Translations and/or assigning Translations to BGA and/or distributing Content and having performed, if applicable, all legal, regulatory and contractual formalities to do so, with a view to using the Services;

"Username": means a series of characters allowing the User, with a password determined by them, to connect uniquely to their Account and to access the Services;

#### IV. Scope, acceptance and modification of the G.T.U.

Access to or use of all or part of the BGA Sites implies acceptance without restriction or reservation of these G.T.U. by the Internet user.

As these G.T.U. may be subject to modifications, the applicable conditions are those in force and accessible on the BGA Sites on the date of access to the BGA Sites by the Internet User. In this respect, BGA may freely change the G.T.U. at any time in order to adapt them to changes in the Services and/or the Applications and/or the BGA Sites and/or their operation. These modifications are brought to the attention of Internet Users by simply putting them online and are deemed to be accepted without reservation.

#### V. Description of Services

BGA provides Internet Users, through the BGA Sites, with access to a certain number of Services aimed at enabling them in particular to become aware of the editorial content published by BGA and the Content shared by Users.

The BGA Sites also allow Users to access other services detailed in the Developer G.T.S. and/or Player G.T.S. after creation of an Account on the relevant BGA Site and subject to prior acceptance of said G.T.S.

All the services provided by BGA and made available to the Internet User is detailed on the relevant BGA Sites.

BGA offers as a Service the provision of an optional audio/video chat system that can be used while using the Applications.

Any interaction between Users in a real-time audio/video chat room is private and is their sole responsibility.

BGA does not record the activity of this audio/video chat system but any User has the technical capacity to do so, although BGA expressly prohibits it. Therefore, Users should not do anything or say that they do not wish to be recorded.

BGA cannot be held responsible for any inconvenience or damage directly or indirectly related to the use of this Service.

#### VI. Access and availability of Services

BGA makes its best efforts to make its Services available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, regardless of the maintenance operations of said Services and/or BGA Sites.

However, it is with full knowledge of the facts that the Internet User visits the Sites and/or uses the Services which offer Content accessible according to the quality of the Internet network.

In particular, BGA reserves the right to interrupt access to all or part of the Services for maintenance and/or improvement work. The Internet User will be notified in advance of any such interruptions to the Services and/or the BGA Sites, insofar as BGA is able to do so, in particular by posting an alert message on the BGA Site concerned. In the event of an emergency, BGA nevertheless reserves the right to suspend all or part of the Services and/or the BGA Site concerned for a reasonable period of time in order to carry out any technical operations required. These interruptions to the Services and/or the BGA Sites shall not give rise to any compensation in favour of the Internet User.

Access to the BGA Sites may also be interrupted for any other reason, in particular technical reasons, without any obligation to provide prior information.

The BGA Sites may also be modified by BGA for its own reasons, in particular technical reasons, and may result in changes to the Services or functionalities, without any obligation to provide prior information.

BGA cannot be held responsible for interruptions or non-reception of the Services due to any failure of the Receiving Media as well as in the event of malfunction, failure or inadequate performance of the operators used by the User to access the Services.

As such, BGA is bound by a best-efforts obligation.

#### VII. Guarantees - Liability

##### A. Guarantees of the Internet User

By accessing the BGA Sites, the Internet User declares, guarantees and undertakes:

• to access and use the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and/or the Services in good faith, in a reasonable manner, not contrary to the terms of these G.T.U. ;

• not use any devices or software other than those provided by BGA intended to (i) affect or attempt to affect the proper operation of the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and/or the Services ii) or to extract, modify, consult, even in buffer or temporary memory, or for individual use, all or part of the BGA Sites and/or Services;

• not to access and/or use the BGA Sites and Applications and/or Services for illegal purposes and/or with the aim of damaging the reputation and/or image of BGA, the Subsidiaries and/or Internet Users, or more generally to infringe the rights, in particular intellectual property rights, of BGA and/or third parties, including Internet Users;

• not to directly or indirectly market the Services and/or the Applications and/or the Content and/or access to the Services and/or the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and/or the Content;

• not to restrict access to and use of the BGA Sites and/or the Services and/or the Applications;

• not to modify, including in buffer or temporary memory, any mention or element of the BGA Sites and/or the Services and/or the Applications other than in accordance with the conditions of these G.T.U. and/or the Player G.T.S. and/or Developer G.T.S.;

We are happy when you modify the website while respecting its rules (ex: for translations), this \`do not modify\` above address what may be done outside the rules ;)

• to ensure that the use of BGA Sites and/or Services and/or the Applications does not affect or compromise the stability, security and quality of the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and/or Services, networks, bandwidth, or infrastructure of BGA, other Internet Users and/or third parties.

• not to violate the provisions of Articles 323-1 to 323-7 of the Penal Code, which punish so-called "hacking" practices;

• not to use and/or exploit the electronic and/or postal details of other Internet Users for any purpose other than the use of the Services and/or the BGA Sites, in particular to send mass mailings and to engage in "spamming".

• not to reuse or exploit all or part of the BGA Sites and/or Services and/or the Applications which they contain, in particular for commercial and/or collective and/or personal use in a form and/or media not authorised by BGA and/or the owners of the Content(s) and/or Applications in question;

About \`re-using\`: we are obviously happy when you share your experience on BGA on medias :) The previous statement is more about re-using pieces of BGA for another service.

• not to use their Account and/or the Services to engage in acts of any nature whatsoever, such as the transmission, publication, or posting of data or Content contrary to the law, infringing public order, or the rights of BGA, other Users or third parties;

• not to disseminate Content, on the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or using the Services, that is unlawful, in particular that would infringe the rights of third parties, violate an applicable law, in particular the Law of 29 July 1881 on the freedom of the press, and/or constitute the infringement or violation of any intellectual property right, know-how, business secret, or personality right of a third party (privacy, image rights, etc.), as likely to be the subject of any action for unfair competition and/or parasitism as well as, more generally, a liability action;

• not to disseminate Content on the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or using the Services that incites hatred or violence, is threatening, aggressive, pornographic, for the purposes of pimping, or paedophilic, obscene, vulgar, racist, sexually explicit, violent, contrary to good morals, xenophobic, hacking or proselytizing, or containing gratuitous nudity or violence, as well as more generally a liability action;

• not to collect or intercept by any means not expressly permitted by BGA any data exchanged by other Users in the context of the Services, or the Identification Elements of any other User;

• not to disseminate Content that is contrary to the legitimate interests of BGA;

• not to obtain information about Users and the Content they publish using automated methods (such as robots, spiders, etc.); not to use the Services and/or the BGA Sites using automated methods (such as robots, spiders, multiple queries, etc.);

• not to upload viruses or other malicious code to the Player Site and/or the Applications;

• not to override any security feature or circumvent or avoid any control of access to the Services;

• not to intimidate or harass other Users, where applicable using the Services;

• not to publish official documents or financial information about others;

• not to promote or publish Content related to alcoholic beverages or adult content without age restrictions or any other online gaming websites subject to the provisions of freedom of expression;

• not to offer competitions or sweepstakes ("promotions") without the prior written consent of BGA;

The statement above is obviously not related to the competitions that are part of the BGA service offer, like tournaments.

• not to create several Accounts: the User undertakes to create only one Account corresponding to them. If BGA deletes a User's Account in the event of non-compliance with these Player G.T.S., the User undertakes not to create another Account without prior authorisation from BGA;

• not to communicate their Identification Elements to a third party and not to let anyone access their Account or do anything that could compromise the security of their Account;

• not to use the Player Site and/or the Services and/or the Applications by impersonating a third party, including a legal entity (such as BGA), or by falsely claiming to represent a third party, including a legal entity (such as BGA), legally or otherwise;

• not to make improper use of the Application support service or the complaint buttons or to send false reports to BGA and/or its partners' staff; • not to communicate Content that is not relevant to the topic or theme of the discussion area;

• not to set up hyperlinks to deep pages of the Player Site, allowing access to the Services, by any technical means intended to bypass the User's identification field or to extract all or part of the content of the Services made available by BGA.

• not to permit or encourage non-compliance with any provision of these Player G.T.S.;

In the event of a breach of any of these obligations, without this list being exhaustive, the Internet User is informed that BGA will have the right to deny or suspend, unilaterally and without prior notice, the Internet User's access to all or part of the Services and/or BGA Sites and to suspend, if necessary, access to their Account.

The User guarantees and shall hold BGA, as well as its Subsidiaries, their representatives, their employees, their partners, and/or any third parties, harmless against any damage, claim or demand from third parties as a result of use that does not comply with these G.T.U. This guarantee covers any compensation that may be due as well as lawyers' fees and legal costs within a reasonable limit.

The Internet User accepts and acknowledges that BGA cannot guarantee:

• that the contents of the BGA Sites, as well as the Content, are in conformity with their expectations and their research;

• the truthfulness, completeness, conformity and/or appropriateness of the Content published by Users on the BGA Sites under their responsibility and hosted by BGA;

• the quality of interactions with other Internet Users and/or Users, or even the speed with which they are brought to them by the latter;

• and more generally to the particular needs of the Internet User.

BGA is also a third party to the correspondence and relations between Users and Internet Users and/or Users, and therefore declines any liability in this respect.

Therefore, the Internet User accepts without reservation that if BGA's liability were to be incurred directly or indirectly in its capacity as technical intermediary, by any person or entity whatsoever, BGA reserves the right to take, promptly and as of right, any administrative and/or technical measure, including with regard to the Internet User, to safeguard its interests and/or comply with its obligations.

##### B. Guarantees of BGA

BGA provides the Internet User, through its BGA Sites, with access to a certain number of Services designed to assist them in their interactions with Users.

BGA does not guarantee the continuity of the Content that the User publishes on the Services, and/or of the Applications which may disappear for any reason. Therefore, the User must make their own backups of the Content. Access to the Player Site, the Applications and the Services requires an Internet connection for which the User is fully responsible.

BGA does not intervene in the relations, in particular legal relations, between Internet Users and Users or between Users themselves. They are therefore responsible for carrying out the usual checks, particularly of a legal nature, before entering into any agreement with a User which is only binding on them.

In any case, BGA does not guarantee:

• the permanent updating of the Services, the BGA Sites and the Applications;

• that the functionality of the Services will not be interrupted, that there are no viruses or other harmful components in the Services or the servers that run them and that defects in the operation or functionality of the Player Site, the Applications and the Services will be corrected;

• that the use of the BGA Sites, Applications and Services will meet their needs;

• that any information obtained by the User through the use of the BGA Sites, the Applications and/or the Service(s) is accurate or reliable.

The Services, the BGA Sites and the Applications are provided "as is" and BGA makes no warranties in this regard.

The Internet User acknowledges that they alone is responsible for any damage caused to BGA and/or other Users or to any third party, whether natural or legal, as a result of using the Services and/or the BGA Sites and/or the Applications.

In this case, BGA reserves the right to delete their Account, as well as to take legal action on the basis of civil and/or criminal liability in order to put an end to the violation and to compensate for its damage.

#### VIII. Fair Play

BGA will not tolerate any cheating and/or lack of fair play, whether through the use of cheating software, analysis of communication protocols or code, use of multiple Accounts, collusion with other Users, leaving the game before its normal end, use of game blocking tactics in order to force other Users to quit, or the use of obscene or foul language, etc.

Any User caught cheating or failing to meet their fair play obligations will receive a warning and then be subject to one of the following sanctions at the discretion of BGA:

◦ freezing of the Account,

◦ resetting of scores and rankings,

◦ suspension of Services,

◦ or even the outright deletion of their Account.

Violation by the User of the rules of conduct or the essential rules of fair play may have consequences for the User's reputation on the Player Site, under the terms and conditions specified in the Privacy Policy.

#### IX. Advertising

BGA reserves the right to broadcast advertising or promotional messages on the BGA Sites, including in the context of the Services.

#### X. Limitation of liability

BGA is only liable for direct damage caused by the Services, except in the case of fraud, gross negligence or intentional misconduct, force majeure, death or bodily injury and any other exclusion provided for by public policy legal and regulatory provisions.

BGA shall not be liable for:

• any indirect damage that may be caused to the Internet User, including any loss of profit (whether direct or indirect), loss of opportunity or loss of reputation that they may suffer;

• in the context of proceedings brought against the Internet User as a result of non-compliant use of the Services and/or the BGA Sites and/or the Applications. The Internet user acknowledges and accepts in this respect that they shall be personally responsible for any claim or proceedings brought against BGA as a result of their non-compliant use of the Services and/or the Player Site and/or the Applications.

• any loss or damage that the Internet User may suffer as a result of:

◦ the inaccuracy, illegality or inadequacy of the Content provided by the Internet User or in the event of damage resulting from the use of the Content provided by a third party User;

◦ reliance on the completeness, accuracy or existence of any advertisement or resulting from any relationship or transaction between the Internet User and any of the advertisers or sponsors whose advertising appears on the Player Site and/or the Applications;

◦ any changes that BGA may make to the BGA Sites and/or Applications and/or Services or any temporary or permanent withdrawal of one or more Services;

◦ the deletion, damage or failure to store Content and any other communications data maintained or transmitted as part of the Services;

◦ in the event of unavailability of the Services and/or BGA Sites and/or Applications for reasons such as the failure of the public electricity network, the failure of the cable telecommunications networks, the loss of connectivity to the Internet network due to public or private operators, including the User, caused in particular by strikes, storms, earthquakes or any other cause having the characteristics of force majeure;

◦ in the event of use of the Services by a User under conditions that do not comply with the G.T.U. and/or Player G.T.S. and/or Developer G.T.S.;

◦ the failure of the Internet User to communicate Identification Data;

◦ the inability of the Internet User to keep their Identification Data or their Account information secure and confidential;

◦ non-compliance with the legislation of a foreign country where the Services and/or the Applications and/or the Player Site are used.

The limitations of BGA's liability towards the Internet user will apply, whether or not BGA has been warned of the possibility of such losses and whether or not it should have been aware of them.

#### XI. Illegal content

The User acknowledges that BGA, in its capacity as host, within the meaning of the provisions of Article 6-I-7 of Law No. 2004-575 of 21 June 2004, of the Content that the User publishes, does not exercise any a priori control on said Content transmitted via the Services and has no general obligation to monitor the Content published.

Having therefore only the role of host of said Contents disseminated under the exclusive responsibility of Users, BGA can only intervene on Content published within the framework of the Services in the event that clearly illegal Content is reported to it by a User.

The User may contact BGA whose contact details are available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/support) for the Player Site or from a dedicated "report this Player" button on the Site.

BGA reserves the right to act at its sole discretion: as such, BGA may, in particular, request that the use of the Content be stopped and/or remove the Content from the Services.

If BGA deletes or deactivates Content created by a User and which is considered to be manifestly illegal or not in conformity with the G.T.U. and/or Player G.T.S. and/or Developer G.T.S., BGA reserves the right to suspend or delete the User's Account.

Finally, the User acknowledges and accepts that presenting Content disseminated by a User as illegal with the sole aim of obtaining its removal or stopping its dissemination, when the User is aware that this information is inaccurate, may be prosecuted.

#### XII. Force majeure

BGA cannot be held liable if the performance of one of its obligations is prevented or delayed due to a case of force majeure as defined in Article 1218 of the Civil Code and by the case law of the French Courts, and in particular natural disasters, fires, malfunction or interruption of the telecommunications network or the electricity network.

#### XIII. Intellectual property

The technique of "framing" which consists in particular in embedding on the page of a website that of another website, is prohibited with regard to the BGA Sites, except with the express prior authorisation of BGA.

##### A. Copyright on BGA Sites

BGA is the owner or licensee of the intellectual property rights of both the general structure of the BGA Sites and their content (texts, slogans, graphics, images, videos, photos, programs and other content), excluding any Content published by the User. Therefore, without prejudice to the provisions of Article XIII D, any representation, reproduction, modification, distortion and/or exploitation of all or part of the BGA Sites and/or Services, by any process whatsoever and on any medium whatsoever, without the express prior authorisation of BGA, is prohibited and constitutes an infringement of copyright.

About \`re-using\`: we are obviously happy when you share your experience on BGA on medias :) The previous statement is more about re-using pieces of BGA for another service.

Likewise, any unauthorised use of the BGA Sites and/or Services shall render the Internet user criminally and civilly liable on the basis of copyright infringement.

The Internet user acknowledges and accepts that access to the BGA Sites and/or the Services made available by BGA does not imply any assignment or grant of intellectual property rights (in particular copyright) and other personal rights (image rights, privacy) to the Internet user.

Access to the BGA Sites and Services is exclusively limited to the private and personal use of the Internet user under the conditions and within the limits defined in these G.T.U.

##### B. Distinctive signs

The trademarks, logos, corporate names, acronyms, commercial names, signs and/or domain names of BGA and/or its partners mentioned on the BGA Sites, allowing access to the Services made available by BGA, constitute distinctive signs that cannot be used without the express prior authorisation of their owner.

Any partial or total representation and/or reproduction and/or exploitation of these distinctive signs is prohibited and constitutes trademark infringement, usurpation of a corporate name, trade name and domain name incurring the tort liability of the perpetrator.

##### C. Advertising and hyperlinks

BGA cannot be held liable for the hyperlinks accessible on the BGA Sites and/or within the framework of the Services, to other websites and generally to all existing resources on the Internet.

Under no circumstances may the Internet User allow or use hyperlinks to deep pages of the BGA Sites, allowing access to the Services, by any technical means intended to bypass the Internet User's identification field or to extract all or part of the content of the Services made available by BGA.

The Services, the Applications and the BGA Sites and, where applicable, the Content may contain hyperlinks to other websites that do not belong to BGA. BGA has no control over the content, the special conditions of each third party offer as well as the general terms and conditions of sale, use and privacy policies or practices of third party sites and accepts no responsibility in this respect.

The Internet User acknowledges and accepts that BGA is not responsible for the availability of these external sites and resources and does not endorse any advertising, products or other links or data on or available from them.

The Internet User acknowledges and accepts that BGA cannot be held responsible for any loss or damage that the Internet User may suffer as a result of the existence of these external sites or resources or as a result of their reliance on the completeness, accuracy or existence of any advertising, products or other data on or accessible from them.

In the event that, in the opinion of the Internet user, a listed third party offer contains illegal or inappropriate content, they may report this to BGA, whose contact details are available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/support) for the Player Site.

##### D. Database

The Internet User irrevocably acknowledges that the BGA Sites and Services, including the structure and/or layout of the Content and/or Applications, consist of one or more databases made available to Internet Users by BGA in its capacity as producer of said databases within the meaning of Articles L.341-1 et seq. of the Intellectual Property Code.

Therefore, in accordance with the provisions of Article L. 342-1 of the same Code, the Internet User is prohibited from proceeding with:

• the extraction by permanent or temporary transfer of all or a qualitatively or quantitatively substantial part of the content of one or more of the databases accessible on the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and/or the Services, including the structure and/or layout of Content, onto another medium, by any means and in any form whatsoever, including for the purpose of use or consultation by a medium and/or process(es) not authorised by BGA;

• the re-use, by making available to the public all or a qualitatively or quantitatively substantial part of the content of one or more of the databases accessible on the BGA Sites and/or Services, including the structure and/or layout of the Content and/or Applications, in any form whatsoever, including by means of a hyperlink, a medium and/or process(es) not authorised by BGA;

• the creation, publication, maintenance, updating, importing, exporting, making available to third parties, whether free of charge or against payment, and participation in the aforementioned acts, of a competing database derived from all or part of one or more of the BGA databases;

• viewing on a screen by a process or media other than those by which BGA intends to disclose the BGA Sites and the Services, the Applications, including the structure and/or layout of the Content and/or the Applications;

• in general, any extraction, use, storage, reproduction, representation or conservation, direct or indirect, partial or total, including in buffer or temporary memory, qualitatively or quantitatively substantial of the content of one or more of BGA's databases, committed by one of the processes mentioned above, is strictly prohibited, including by a medium not authorised by BGA

##### E. Content of Services

The Internet User acknowledges and accepts that access to the BGA Sites and the Services made available by BGA does not imply any assignment or grant of intellectual property rights (in particular copyright) and other rights to the Internet User. The Internet User acknowledges and accepts that the private and personal use granted by BGA for access to its Services excludes, in particular, access to the Services with a view to collective use of its content, reproduction, representation, resale, exchange, rental, transfer to a third party, modification, adaptation and correction, whether free of charge or against payment, of all or part of the BGA Sites, Services and their content.

#### XIV. Protection of Personal Data

The Personal Data of the Internet User is collected and processed by BGA, in accordance with the Privacy Policy, [accessible here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac) and which is an integral part of these G.T.U.

#### XV. Miscellaneous provisions

##### A. Notifications

The Internet User accepts that BGA may send them notifications, including those modifying these G.T.U., by email or by posting on the BGA Sites, the Applications and, if applicable, on their Account.

##### B. Correspondence - Evidence

Unless otherwise specified in these G.T.U., correspondence between the Internet User and BGA is mainly by email. Pursuant to Articles 1366 et seq. of the Civil Code, the User acknowledges and accepts that the information provided by BGA by email and on the BGA Sites is authentic between the Internet User and BGA. Elements such as the time of reception or transmission, as well as the quality of the data received, will be deemed authentic by priority as they appear on the BGA Sites, or as they are authenticated by BGA's computerised procedures, unless the Internet User provides written proof to the contrary. The scope of proof of the information provided by the BGA Sites and/or the Applications and the computerised procedures of BGA is that granted to an original in the sense of a written paper document, signed by hand. If you are part of the 0.01% who are reading this you should click [here](#).

##### C. Non-waiver.

The Internet User acknowledges that if BGA does not exercise or assert any right or remedy provided for in these G.T.U. (or from which BGA may benefit under any applicable law), this does not constitute a formal waiver by BGA of its rights, and these rights and remedies shall remain valid and enforceable for BGA.

##### D. Severability

If any of the terms of these G.T.U. are found to be invalid by any decision of a competent court, they shall be deleted without affecting the other terms of the G.T.U. The remaining terms shall remain valid and enforceable.

##### E. Titles

In the event of a difficulty of interpretation between one of the titles appearing above the clauses of these G.T.U., and one of the clauses, the titles will be declared non-existent.

##### F. Beneficiary of the G.T.U.

The Internet User acknowledges and agrees that the Subsidiaries are considered beneficiaries of the G.T.U. and that these other companies are entitled to directly enforce and rely on the terms of the G.T.U. Except as specified herein, no other person or company shall be considered a third party beneficiary of these G.T.U.

#### XVI. Applicable law and dispute settlement

These G.T.U. have been drafted in French and English, however, only the French version shall prevail in the event of difficulty of interpretation.

These G.T.U. will be executed and interpreted in accordance with French law.

In the event of a dispute arising in connection with these G.T.U., their interpretation and their consequences or with the deeds supplementing or modifying them, the User shall approach BGA for the purpose of attempting to find an amicable solution.

All complaints to BGA must be made in writing.

Failing an amicable settlement, the User may choose:

1) To resort to an amicable mediation solution within a maximum period of one (1) year from the date of the Internet User's written complaint to BGA:

(i) or by referring the matter to a consumer mediator with a view to amicably resolving the dispute. To this end, the dispute shall be submitted to mediation in accordance with the mediation rules of the CMAP - Paris Mediation and Arbitration Centre - at the Paris Ile-de-France Chamber of Commerce and Industry;

(ii) or by using the online dispute resolution system accessible at the following address:https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/odr/main/index.cfm?event=main.home.chooseLanguage, it being specified that the proposed mediation process cannot be a prerequisite for a referral to the competent courts by the Internet User.

2) To bring their claim before the competent French courts.

### Conditions Générales de Services

#### 1\. Objet des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs

Les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs ont pour objet de définir les conditions et modalités d’utilisation du Site Joueurs et des Services accessibles gratuitement sous réserve de la création préalable d’un Compte ou payants sous réserve de la souscription d’un Abonnement Premium.

Les Services accessibles gratuitement sous réserve de la création préalable d’un Compte depuis le Site Développeurs, leurs conditions et modalités, sont détaillées dans les C.G.S. Développeurs disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://studio.boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos).

Les Services accessibles gratuitement sans nécessité de créer un Compte, leurs conditions et modalités, sont détaillés dans les C.G.U. disponibles [en cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) dont font partie intégrante les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 2\. Définitions

Pour les besoins des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, les termes en majuscules, qu’ils soient employés au singulier ou au pluriel, ont la signification suivante :

« Abonnement Premium » : désigne un Abonnement payant souscrit pour une certaine durée au choix de l’Utilisateur, avec ou sans reconduction tacite au choix de l’Utilisateur et lui permettant d’accéder, pendant la durée dudit Abonnement Premium, à l’ensemble des Services payants décrits à l’article 9 des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs complétés, le cas échéant, des Services payants décrits sur le Site Joueur.

« Application(s) » : désignent les jeux accessibles depuis le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur, et/ou les jeux accessibles seulement depuis le Site Développeur car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie des Codes des Utilisateurs, édités par BGA et/ou ses Filiales ainsi que tout logiciel accessoire qui serait par exemple nécessaires comme une mise à jour de l’Application, une mise à niveau de l’Application, son code (en tout ou partie), les fichiers la composant, les images associées ou générées et les données associées mais également les applications non accessibles depuis les Sites BGA, car en cours de développement ou n’ayant pas fait l’objet d’une recette par BGA, composées en tout ou partie de Codes d’Utilisateurs ;

« Application(s) Premium » : désigne les Applications accessibles et utilisables uniquement aux Utilisateurs disposant d’un Abonnement Premium ;

« BGA » : désigne la société AD2G STUDIO, société par actions simplifiée, au capital social de 100,00 €, dont le siège social est situé au 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, immatriculée au Registre du Commerce et des Sociétés de Nanterre sous le numéro 803 287 150 représentée par Monsieur Alexandre Schlecht agissant et ayant les pouvoirs nécessaires en tant que président.

« C.G.U. » : désigne les conditions générales d’utilisation relatives aux Services accessibles sans Compte depuis les Sites BGA ;

« C.G.S. Développeurs » : désigne les conditions générales de services relatives aux Services accessibles depuis le Site Développeurs ;

« C.G.S. Joueurs » : désigne les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs ;

« Compte » : désigne l’espace personnel d’un Utilisateur uniquement accessible avec des Éléments d’identification transmis par BGA lui permettant d’accéder et de bénéficier des Services ;

« Compte Tiers » : désigne un compte auquel l’Utilisateur a souscrit auprès d’un éditeur tiers et qui peut être lié à un Compte (par exemple Google ou Facebook) ;

« Contenu(s) » : désigne (nt) le(s) contenu(s) de toute nature (notamment des données textuelles, visuelles, vidéos, photographiques, espace de discussion, avis, etc. publiés(s) sur les Sites BGA grâce aux Services, par un Utilisateur sous sa responsabilité ;

« Données d’Identification » : désignent toute information renseignée par l’Utilisateur permettant à ce dernier de créer un Compte (adresse électronique, âge, localisation, etc.) ;

« Donnée(s) Personnelle(s) » : désigne (nt) les données à caractère personnel d’un Utilisateur ou d’un Internaute et collectées et traitées par BGA dans le cadre de la consultation des Sites BGA, comme, le cas échéant, la création et la gestion de son Compte et la réalisation des Services, et ce dans les conditions et modalités telle que définie dans la Politique de Confidentialité ;

« Élément d’identification » : désigne l’identifiant de connexion (« login » ou adresse de courrier électronique) et mot de passe (« password ») transmis par BGA à l’Utilisateur lui permettant d’accéder à son Compte ;

« Formulaire de rétractation » : désigne le formulaire permettant la mise en œuvre du droit de rétractation de son Abonnement Premium par l’Utilisateur. Le Formulaire de rétractation est disponible en annexe des présentes Conditions Générales de Services et d’Utilisation tout en bas de cette page,

« Filiale(s) » : désigne toute société ou entité qui contrôle directement ou indirectement ou qui est contrôlée par ou sous contrôle commun avec BGA. Le contrôle d’une entité signifie la possession, directement ou indirectement, du pouvoir de diriger ou de faire diriger la gestion ou les politiques d’une telle entité, que ce soit par la propriété des titres avec droit de vote, par contrat ou autrement ;

« Internaute » : désigne l’ensemble des internautes, visiteurs des Sites BGA, disposant ou non d’un Compte ;

« Nom d’Utilisateur » : désigne une série de caractères permettant à l’Utilisateur, avec un mot de passe déterminé par ses soins, de se connecter de manière unique à son Compte et d’accéder aux Services ;

« Politique de confidentialité » : désigne la politique de confidentialité et de protection des Données Personnelles des Utilisateurs mise en œuvre par BGA, laquelle fait partie intégrante des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs ;

« Politique de Modération de BGA » : désigne la politique de modération de BGA, accessible en cliquant ici https://en.doc.boardgamearena.com/Moderationpolicy et faisant partie intégrante des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs ;

« Services » : désignent les fonctionnalités et services gratuits mis à la disposition des Internautes et accessibles à l’aide d’un Support de Réception, depuis les Sites BGA sans Compte ainsi que les fonctionnalités et services gratuits ou payants, tels que déterminés dans les C.G.S. Développeurs et les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs et accessibles depuis les Sites BGA avec un Compte, aux Utilisateurs ;

« Site(s) BGA » : désigne indistinctement le Site Développeur et/ou le Site Joueur ;

« Site Développeur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL studio.boardgamearena.com ;

« Site Joueur » : désigne le site Internet notamment accessible depuis l’adresse URL boardgamearena.com ;

« Support(s) de Réception » : désigne(nt) les ordinateurs, tablettes, smartphones, télévision, utilisés pour accéder aux Sites BGA et pouvoir utiliser les Applications et bénéficiant a minima d’un navigateur récent et à jour ;

« Traduction » : désigne les éléments littéraires et/ou textuels d’une Application et/ou des Sites BGA et faisant l’objet d’une traduction dans une langue différente par l’Utilisateur et dont les Droits de Propriété Intellectuelle sont cédés à BGA conformément aux C.G.S. Développeurs ;

« Utilisateur » : désigne toute personne physique de quinze (15) ans minimum et capable ou disposant d’une autorisation parentale pour ce faire, y compris représentant légal (dirigeant, préposé, etc.) d’une personne morale agissant pour son compte, souscrivant pour ce faire l’ouverture d’un Compte sur le Site Développeur et/ou sur le Site Développeur et n’étant soumise à aucune interdiction et/ou restriction légale, réglementaire ou conventionnelle l’empêchant d’accéder et/ou d’utiliser des Applications et/ou de développer des Développements et/ou céder les Développements à BGA et/ou de réaliser des Traductions et/ou céder les Traductions à BGA et/ou diffuser du Contenu et ayant rempli, le cas échéant, l’ensemble des formalités légales, réglementaires et conventionnelles pour ce faire, en vue d’utiliser les Services.

#### 3\. Champ d’application, acceptation et modification des C.G.S. Joueurs

##### 3.1. Acceptation des C.G.S. Joueurs

Les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs régissent les droits, obligations et restrictions liés à l’utilisation du Site Joueur et/ou des Applications et/ou des Services et/ou à la souscription d’un Abonnement Premium.

SI L’UTILISATEUR REFUSE LES TERMES DES PRÉSENTES C.G.S. JOUEURS, IL EST INVITÉ À NE PAS UTILISER LES SERVICES DISPONIBLES DEPUIS LE SITE JOUEUR OU L’UNE QUELCONQUE DES APPLICATIONS.

L’accès au Site Joueur et/ou aux Applications et/ou l’utilisation de tout ou partie des Services, des Applications implique que l’Utilisateur accepte et s’engage à respecter les C.G.S. Joueurs, la Politique de confidentialité, les C.G.U., toute autre mention d’avertissement, et/ou les autres conditions contractuelles applicables et les règles du jeu, le cas échéant, applicables lors de l’utilisation des Applications, et ce, sans réserve.

##### 3.2. Modifications des C.G.S. Joueurs

BGA se réserve le droit de modifier périodiquement les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, par exemple pour les adapter aux modifications législatives et réglementaires, ou modifier les fonctionnalités proposées sur le Site Joueur et/ou les Services et/ou les Applications.

BGA informera, dans la mesure du possible, dans un délai maximum de 15 (quinze) jours avant de modifier les C.G.S. Joueurs. Par conséquent, l’Utilisateur est invité à consulter régulièrement ces C.G.S. Joueurs. Si l’Utilisateur n’accepte pas les C.G.S. Joueurs modifiées, l’Utilisateur doit cesser d’utiliser les Services. Continuer d’utiliser les Services au-delà de la date de publication des C.G.S. Joueurs modifiées présumera de l’acceptation par l’Utilisateur des C.G.S. Joueurs modifiées.

Les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs pouvant faire l’objet de modifications, les conditions applicables sont celles en vigueur et accessibles à la date d’accès de l’Utilisateur au Site Joueur.

##### 3.3. Information et protection des mineurs

Si l’Utilisateur est mineur, et qu’il souhaite accéder au Site Joueur et utiliser pleinement tout ou partie des Services et/ou Applications, il doit prendre connaissance des C.G.S. Joueurs et les comprendre avec l’aide de ses parents ou ses représentants légaux et obtenir leur consentement pour l’utilisation desdits Services et/ou Applications.

BGA recommande toutefois aux parents ou représentants légaux de surveiller les activités de leurs enfants ou des enfants qu’ils ont à leur charge, dans le cadre de l’utilisation des Services. BGA recommande aux Utilisateurs d’être vigilants à ce que leurs enfants, ou les enfants qu’ils ont à charge ne divulguent jamais leurs Données Personnelles sans le consentement des Utilisateurs.

BGA se réserve le droit de restreindre ou d’interdire l’accès à des Services par les enfants mineurs de moins de quinze (15) ans si l’accord préalable des parents ou représentants légaux n’a pas été recueilli.

Les parents ou représentants légaux peuvent clôturer à tout moment le Compte du mineur en faisant parvenir un courrier électronique à BGA dont les coordonnées sont disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal).

Nonobstant ce qui précède, l’utilisation des Services de BGA doit être effectuée sous surveillance parentale, toute utilisation des Services par un mineur sera présumée avoir été validée au préalable par ses parents ou représentants légaux.

Sauf disposition légale contraire, BGA rejette toute responsabilité relative à l’utilisation des Services par des mineurs sans l’accord des parents ou représentants légaux.

#### 4\. Conditions et modalités de souscription aux Services

##### 4.1. Création d’un Compte

Pour pouvoir accéder à et/ou utiliser certaines fonctionnalités et/ou avantages des Services, il est nécessaire de créer un Compte. Pour créer un Compte, l’Utilisateur doit se rendre sur le Site Joueur et renseigner ses Données d’Identification.

L’Utilisateur a également la possibilité de lier son Compte Tiers au sens des C.G.U. avec son Compte de cette façon il pourra accéder directement au Site Joueur sans avoir besoin de renseigner d’autres Données d’Identification.

Toute connexion au Site Joueur, à l’une des Applications et/ou aux Services à l’aide d’un Compte Tiers au sens des C.G.U. est réputée avoir été effectuée avec le Compte en question. Les traitements de Données Personnelles relatifs à la liaison d’un Compte Tiers avec un Compte sont expliqués dans la Politique de confidentialité.

D’autres Données d’Identification pourront être renseignées dans la rubrique « À propos de » sur le Site Joueur lesquelles seront publiques et donc accessibles aux autres Utilisateurs.

L’ouverture d’un Compte nécessite la création d’un Nom d’Utilisateur, le cas échéant d’un avatar (identité visuelle liée au Compte et créée par l’Utilisateur), et d’un mot de passe.

Le Nom d’Utilisateur est un élément unique, deux Utilisateurs ne peuvent avoir le même.

L’Utilisateur accepte que le Nom d’Utilisateur soit publiquement affiché dans le cadre des Services conformément à la Politique de confidentialité, en conséquence il est recommandé à l’Utilisateur ne pas y faire figurer son nom patronymique, lequel peut, de manière facultative, être renseigné publiquement dans les informations de son Compte.

Pour les autres Données d’Identification pouvant être rendues publiques, l’Utilisateur est invité à se référer à la Politique de confidentialité.

Les Éléments d’identification sont strictement personnels. L’Utilisateur s’engage à conserver leur confidentialité et à ne pas les transmettre à des tiers. L’Utilisateur est seul autorisé à accéder et utiliser les Services à l’aide de son Compte et partant de ses Éléments d’Identification.

Tout accès aux Services avec le Compte est réputé de plein droit avoir été effectué par l’Utilisateur y associé et sous sa responsabilité.

Dès lors, en cas de perte, de vol ou tout acte frauduleux à l’égard des Éléments d’identification, il appartient à l’Utilisateur d’en informer BGA dans les plus brefs délais et de justifier à cette occasion de son identité par tous moyens.

À réception de sa notification dûment justifiée, BGA adressera un courrier électronique à l’Utilisateur lui permettant de mettre à jour ses Éléments d’identification, à charge pour lui de les conserver strictement confidentiels.

Si BGA a des motifs légitimes de penser que la sécurité du Site Joueur et/ou de l’une/des Application(s) est violée et/ou qu’une mauvaise utilisation de tout ou partie des Services serait due à une utilisation non autorisée du Compte de l’Utilisateur, BGA pourra suspendre temporairement l’accès de l’Utilisateur à son Compte, et/ou à son Abonnement Premium et donc son accès aux Services, et ce, pour préserver l’intégrité du Site Joueur et/ou de l’une/des Application(s) et des données puis, si nécessaire, exiger de l’Utilisateur la modification de ses Éléments d’identification suivant ses instructions.

De même, si l’Utilisateur sélectionne un Nom d’Utilisateur au titre des Éléments d’identification lui permettant d’accéder à son Compte qui serait inapproprié, contraire aux bonnes mœurs ou portant atteinte au droit d’un tiers, BGA se réserve le droit de suspendre l’accès au Compte concerné et/ou suspendre l’Abonnement Premium en cause.

##### 4.2. Véracité et utilisation des Données d’Identification.

Lors de la création de son Compte, l’Utilisateur s’engage à fournir des Données d’Identification exactes et complètes et s’engage également à mettre ces Données d’Identification à jour, en conformité avec les demandes de BGA.

L’Utilisateur n’allèguera ni n’insinuera être une autre personne ou entité, en fournissant de faux renseignements sur un parent, un tuteur légal ou toute autre personne, notamment, par le biais du Nom d’Utilisateur, de l’avatar ou de toute autre information telle que l’image.

BGA peut prendre des mesures pour vérifier la véracité des informations fournies, le cas échéant, par téléphone ou par mail renseigné pour désigner un parent ou un tuteur légal. Afin d’éviter les fraudes, l’Utilisateur accepte de transmettre à BGA sur demande, par courriel les autorisations et éléments de preuves nécessaires conformément à la Politique de confidentialité.

#### 5\. Utilisation des Applications

Les Applications sont mises à disposition de l’Utilisateur sous licence non cessible, non exclusive, non commerciale, personnelle, et exclusivement à des fins de loisirs et d’usage personnel.

Les Applications demeurent la propriété entière de BGA et/ou ses Filiales, notamment concernant les droits de propriété intellectuelle y associés. En conséquence, la licence accordée ne constitue en aucun cas une cession des droits de propriété intellectuelle desdites Applications.

À ce titre, l’Utilisateur s’interdit de vendre, copier, échanger, transférer, publier, louer, concéder au titre d’une licence, distribuer, commercialiser ou exploiter commercialement l’Application, ou encore la décompiler, désassembler le code, le réduire en une forme lisible par l’homme ou attribuer ou distribuer quelque élément que ce soit que l’Utilisateur pourrait copier ou dériver de ladite Application.

La licence permettant l’utilisation de l’Application sera en vigueur tant que l’Application demeurera accessible sur le Site Joueur. L’Utilisateur ne saurait demander le remboursement d’aucun paiement effectué du fait qu’une Application n’est plus accessible sur le Site Joueur et/ou que son modèle économique change (par exemple qu’une Application soit devenue une Application Premium et inversement).

L’Utilisateur est informé que les Applications ne sont compatibles qu’avec les Supports de Réception au sens des C.G.U et tous les systèmes d’exploitation et que les performances des Applications et des Services qui s’y rapportent peuvent varier en conséquence.

#### 6\. Règles de conduite

BGA autorise l’Utilisateur par les présentes à accéder et à utiliser le Site Joueur, et/ou les Applications et/ou les Services, sous réserve du respect notamment des conditions rappelées dans les C.G.U et l’Utilisateur est informé que le non-respect de l’une d’elles constitue, de sa part, un manquement aux présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 7\. Espaces de discussions en ligne

Les espaces de discussion comme les autres Services sont modérés a postériori, ils ne permettent pas une vérification des Contenus avant affichage sur les Applications.

Lorsque l’Utilisateur effectue une publication d’un Contenu sur les espaces de discussion, son Nom d’Utilisateur et/ou son avatar peut apparaitre. L’Utilisateur déclare avoir connaissance et accepter que la divulgation, et/ou la publication et/ou la diffusion de ses messages se fait sous sa propre responsabilité. Les Contenus sont diffusés sur les espaces de discussion (et plus généralement à l’aide des Services) sans limitation de durée et subsistent y compris si l’Utilisateur supprime son Compte.

Si l’Utilisateur supprime son Compte, celui-ci devient invisible sur le Site Joueur et/ou les Applications pour les autres Utilisateurs et n’est plus accessible. Les Contenus de l’Utilisateur persistent même après la suppression de son Compte, étant entendu que le Contenu demeurera associé à son Nom d’Utilisateur et/ou son avatar.

#### 8\. Traductions

Chaque Utilisateur peut procéder à la réalisation de Traductions dans les conditions et modalités détaillées dans les C.G.S. Développeurs lesquelles prévoient expressément que l’ensemble des droits de propriété intellectuelle associés à ces Traductions seront automatiquement dévolus à BGA.

Les Utilisateurs garantissent donc avoir pris connaissance des C.G.S. Développeurs avant d’engager toute Traduction (au sens des C.G.S. Développeurs) qu’ils acceptent intégralement et s’engagent à respecter sans restriction ni réserve.

#### 9\. Abonnement Premium

Pour accéder aux Services payants, l’Utilisateur est invité à souscrire un Abonnement Premium proposé sur le Site Joueur.

Avec l’Abonnement Premium, l’Utilisateur peut bénéficier des Services payants notamment :

◦ Jouer aux Applications Premium ;

◦ Absence d’attente avant de jouer à une Application ;

◦ Jouer depuis le même terminal, à plusieurs (un seul Abonnement Premium est nécessaire) ;

◦ Conférence audio ou vidéo pour jouer aux Applications avec d’autres Utilisateurs bénéficiant d’un Abonnement Premium ;

◦ Accéder aux statistiques d’utilisation des Applications ;

◦ Jouer à une Application avec sa couleur préférée lorsque cela est possible

◦ Créer des tournois

◦ Autres Services payants décrits sur le Site Joueur le cas échéant.

L’Abonnement Premium permet notamment l'accès à des "Applications Premiums". La liste complète des "Applications Premiums" est disponible sur la page "Premium" du Site Joueur.

Chaque Application "Premium" a besoin d'au moins un (1) Utilisateur avec un Abonnement Premium pour démarrer. Autrement dit, les Utilisateurs Premiums peuvent créer des nouvelles tables de jeu Premium, et jouer avec n'importe quel autre Utilisateur, disposant d’un Abonnement Premium ou non.

Les Services fournis avec l’Abonnement Premium fournissent l'accès à des "Extensions Premiums". Les "Extensions Premiums" sont des options (cad: des variantes) d'une Application accessible sans Abonnement Premium.

Une Application avec une "Extension Premium" a besoin d'au moins un (1) Utilisateur avec un Abonnement Premium pour démarrer. Autrement dit, les Utilisateurs Premiums peuvent créer des nouvelles tables avec une option "Extension Premium" sélectionnée, et jouer avec n'importe quel autre Utilisateur, disposant d’un Abonnement Premium ou non.

##### 9.1. Souscription des Abonnements Premium

Pour souscrire à un Abonnement Premium, l’Utilisateur est invité à remplir un formulaire d’Abonnement dans lequel il lui sera demandé notamment de sélectionner la formule choisie (soit : un Abonnement Premium mensuel ou annuel) et renseigner les informations mentionnées sur sa carte de paiement pour procéder à son règlement. Tout Abonnement Premium est conclu pour sa durée ferme.

Les sommes versées au titre de l’Abonnement Premium sont définitivement acquises à BGA, y compris en cas de résiliation anticipée de l’Abonnement Premium, laquelle prendra effet, en tout état de cause à l’issue de la période correspondante à l’Abonnement Premium souscrit.

Le seul mode de communication entre BGA et l’Utilisateur étant l’échange de courriers électroniques, l’Utilisateur déclare et garantit à cet égard que les informations transmises par lui à BGA sont sincères et valables et que l’adresse de courrier électronique renseignée lors de son inscription est parfaitement valide et en état de fonctionnement.

Il appartient à l’Utilisateur d’informer BGA de tout changement de son adresse de courrier électronique.

La souscription d’un Abonnement Premium ne peut être faite qu’à des fins personnelles ce que déclare et reconnaît l’Utilisateur.

Le non-respect par l’Utilisateur de tout ou partie des obligations souscrites aux termes des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, et en particulier concernant tout incident de paiement du prix de l’Abonnement, pourra entraîner le droit pour BGA de refuser à l’Utilisateur toute nouvelle souscription d’Abonnement jusqu’à la régularisation de sa situation.

Avant la souscription de son Abonnement Premium, l’Utilisateur est invité à sélectionner la durée de l’Abonnement Premium de son choix, puis à confirmer son Abonnement en procédant à son paiement.

Préalablement au paiement de son Abonnement Premium, l’Utilisateur est invité à accepter les termes des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs. Il est acquis que les C.G.S. Joueurs applicables sont celles en vigueur au jour de la confirmation de son Abonnement Premium.

Une fois la souscription de son Abonnement Premium payée et finalisée par l’Utilisateur sur le Site Joueur, une confirmation écrite lui sera adressée par courrier électronique, récapitulant la formule d’Abonnement Premium souscrite, son prix et les modalités d’utilisation des services souscrits.

L’Utilisateur s’engage à conserver les éléments contenus dans le courrier électronique de confirmation d’Abonnement, en ce compris les pièces jointes de ce dernier.

##### 9.2. Prix des Abonnements

Les prix des Abonnements Premium est indiqué sur le Site Joueur en euros ou dans la devise locale de l’Utilisateur toutes taxes comprises (TVA et autres taxes applicables).

L’Utilisateur reconnaît et accepte que le montant de son Abonnement Premium ne prend en compte ni le coût des télécommunications permettant l’accès aux Services payants proposés sur le Site Joueur et compris dans son Abonnement Premium, ni les autres coûts éventuels de connexion à l’Internet, qui restent en toutes hypothèses à la charge de l’Utilisateur, en totalité.

BGA se réserve le droit de modifier ses prix à tout moment.

En cas de modification du prix des formules d’Abonnement Premium, cette modification sera effective, à compter du renouvellement de l’Abonnement de l’Utilisateur, lequel recevra un courrier électronique l’informant de cette modification quinze (15) jours avant la date de renouvellement de son Abonnement Premium.

En cas de modification par BGA des prix des formules d’Abonnement Premium, ces modifications seront effectives dès leur mise en ligne sur le Site Joueur.

Pour certains moyens de paiement, l'émetteur du moyen de paiement de l’Utilisateur peut lui facturer certains frais, tels que des frais de change ou d'autres frais relatifs au fonctionnement de sa méthode de paiement.

Le règlement intégral du prix de l’Abonnement Premium s’effectue par carte bancaire auprès de son prestataire de paiement suivant un processus de paiement sécurisé fourni par celle-ci et ne permettant pas, en tout état de cause, à BGA de prendre connaissance des coordonnées bancaires de l’Utilisateur. Le cas échéant, le règlement intégral du prix de l’Abonnement Premium peut s’effectuer selon tout autre mode de paiement tel qu’indiqué sur le Site Internet Joueur.

Le règlement intégral du prix de l’Abonnement Premium reconduit tacitement s’effectue par l’intermédiaire du prestataire de paiement si bien que le jour de prélèvement peut être modifié, par exemple si le moyen de paiement n'a temporairement pas pu être prélevé ou en fonction des jours ouvrables applicables.

##### 9.3. Durée des Abonnements Premium

L’Utilisateur est informé qu’aux termes des dispositions des articles L.215-1, L.215-3 et L.241-3 du Code de la Consommation relatives à la reconduction tacite (automatique) des contrats :

« (L.215-1) Pour les contrats de prestations de services conclus pour une durée déterminée avec une clause de reconduction tacite, le professionnel prestataire de services informe le consommateur par écrit, par lettre nominative ou courrier électronique dédiés, au plus tôt trois mois et au plus tard un mois avant le terme de la période autorisant le rejet de la reconduction, de la possibilité de ne pas reconduire le contrat qu’il a conclu avec une clause de reconduction tacite. Cette information, délivrée dans des termes clairs et compréhensibles, mentionne, dans un encadré apparent, la date limite de non-reconduction.

Lorsque cette information ne lui a pas été adressée conformément aux dispositions du premier alinéa, le consommateur peut mettre gratuitement un terme au contrat, à tout moment à compter de la date de reconduction.

Les avances effectuées après la dernière date de reconduction ou, s’agissant des contrats à durée indéterminée, après la date de transformation du contrat initial à durée déterminée, sont dans ce cas remboursées dans un délai de trente jours à compter de la date de résiliation, déduction faite des sommes correspondant, jusqu’à celle-ci, à l’exécution du contrat.

Les dispositions du présent article s’appliquent sans préjudice de celles qui soumettent légalement certains contrats à des règles particulières en ce qui concerne l’information du consommateur. »

« (L.215-3) Les dispositions du présent chapitre sont également applicables aux contrats conclus entre des professionnels et des non professionnels. »

« (L.241-3) Lorsque le professionnel n’a pas procédé au remboursement dans les conditions prévues à l’article L. 215-1, les sommes dues sont productives d’intérêts au taux légal.

##### 9.4. Renouvellement tacite et automatique

Quelle que soit la durée de l’Abonnement Premium et sous réserve que cela soit techniquement possible et qu’il ne s’agisse pas d’un Abonnement Premium offert par un autre Utilisateur, l’Utilisateur est pleinement informé qu’à son échéance, celui-ci sera automatiquement reconduit pour une durée identique à̀ celle initialement souscrite par l’Utilisateur, sauf résiliation par l’Utilisateur au plus tard vingt-quatre (24) heures avant l’expiration de l’échéance de l’Abonnement Premium en cours.

Ainsi, s’il n’entend pas renouveler son Abonnement ou le résilier, l’Utilisateur devra se connecter à son Compte sur le site le Site Joueur, se rendre alors dans la rubrique « Mes Préférences », puis « Mon Compte », et cliquer sur « Annuler mon abonnement » et ce, dans le délai visé ci-dessus.

À défaut d’une telle notification, l’Abonnement Premium sera reconduit et facturé sur la même base tarifaire et selon des périodicités identiques à celle de l’Abonnement initialement souscrit.

Conformément aux articles L.215-1, L.215-3 et L.241-3 du Code de la consommation reproduit ci-devant, BGA adressera à l’Utilisateur un courriel l’informant de sa faculté́ de ne pas reconduire l’Abonnement Premium annuel et les modalités de sa non-reconduction dudit Abonnement Premium.

#### 10\. Droit de rétractation

L’Utilisateur reconnaît avoir reçu toutes les informations relatives aux Services proposés sur le Site Joueur et plus précisément aux différentes formules d’Abonnement Premium proposées sur le Site Joueur, avant d’y souscrire et que l’offre de ces services est conforme aux exigences requises en matière de prestations de services fournies à distance, en particulier via Internet.

Conformément aux dispositions de l’article L.221-28° 13 du Code de la consommation, le droit de rétractation ne peut être exercé pour les contrats :

« 13° De fourniture d’un contenu numérique non fourni sur un support matériel dont l’exécution a commencé après accord préalable exprès du consommateur et renoncement exprès à son droit de rétractation. »

Conformément au troisième alinéa de l’article L.221-9 du Code de la consommation :

« Le contrat mentionne, le cas échéant, l’accord exprès du consommateur pour la fourniture d’un contenu numérique indépendant de tout support matériel avant l’expiration du délai de rétractation et, dans cette hypothèse, le renoncement de ce dernier à l’exercice de son droit de rétractation. »

Conformément au second alinéa de l’article L.221-13 du Code de la consommation :

« Le cas échéant, le professionnel fournit au consommateur, dans les mêmes conditions et avant l’expiration du délai de rétractation, la confirmation de son accord exprès pour la fourniture d’un contenu numérique non présenté sur un support matériel et de son renoncement à l’exercice du droit de rétractation. »

Toutefois, si l’Utilisateur décide de se rétracter de son Abonnement Premium sans en invoquer de motif et ce, pendant un délai de (14) jours calendaires à compter de la confirmation de son Abonnement Premium par BGA, l’Utilisateur doit informer BGA de son intention, au plus tard dans le délai précité de quatorze (14) jours, et ce : soit en complétant et adressant à BGA le Formulaire de rétractation joint en annexe des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs et en respectant les instructions y figurant ; soit, en manifestant son intention de rétractation de manière claire et non équivoque comprenant les informations essentielles pour ce faire par courrier électronique ou par pli postal à BGA dont les coordonnées complètes sont disponibles en [cliquant ici](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal).

Dans les meilleurs délais à compter de la réception par BGA du Formulaire de rétractation ou de la notification matérialisant la volonté de l’Utilisateur de faire exercer son droit de rétractation, BGA en accuse réception à l’Utilisateur par courrier électronique. Les coûts liés à l’envoi du Formulaire de rétractation sont à la charge de l’Utilisateur.

#### 11\. Propriété intellectuelle

##### 11.1. Utilisation des Services

Les Services sont conçus, édités et gérés par ou pour le compte de BGA. L’Utilisateur reconnait et accepte que l’accès aux Applications, Contenus et Services mis à disposition par BGA ne saurait emporter quelconque cession des droits de propriété intellectuelle au bénéfice de l’Utilisateur.

L’accès aux Services est exclusivement limité à l’usage privé et personnel de l’Utilisateur dans les conditions et limites définies dans les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

##### 11.2. Contenu(s)

En tant que détenteur d’un Compte, l’Utilisateur peut soumettre du Contenu à l’aide des Services.

L’Utilisateur conserve tous ses droits de propriété intellectuelle sur son Contenu, mais est tenu de concéder des droits limités à BGA et aux autres Utilisateurs dans les conditions prévues à l’article 12.3 ci-dessous.

L’Utilisateur reconnait et accepte qu’il est seul responsable de son propre Contenu et des conséquences de sa diffusion en ce compris toute diffusion de façon indirecte par des liens hypertextes. BGA ne garantit aucun Contenu, ou opinion, recommandation ou avis exprimé dans celui-ci, et BGA décline expressément toute responsabilité relative à ce Contenu.

L’Utilisateur déclare et garantit qu’il dispose (et continuera à disposer pendant l’utilisation des Services) de tous les droits, licences, consentements et autorisations nécessaires pour permettre à BGA d’utiliser son Contenu dans le but d’offrir le Site Joueur, les Applications, les Services et plus généralement dans les conditions envisagées par les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

L’Utilisateur reconnait que, par le simple fait d’utiliser les Services, l’Utilisateur peut être exposé à du Contenu inexact, choquant, indécent ou autrement négatif. En sa qualité d’hébergeur, BGA ne saurait en aucun cas être considéré comme responsable pour la diffusion de ce type de Contenu.

BGA se réserve le droit de contacter l’Utilisateur afin d’obtenir plus de renseignements concernant les Contenus postés et de vérifier que l’Utilisateur en est bien le l’auteur et le cas échéant que l’Utilisateur en détient les droits.

En tout état de cause BGA n’est ni lié, ni engagé, ni responsable des opinions, conseils et/ou recommandations affichés et/ou envoyés par les Utilisateurs à l’aide des Services et précisément dans les espaces de discussion et décline toute responsabilité afférente.

##### 11.3. Les droits concédés par l’Utilisateur sur son Contenu

Lorsque l’Utilisateur soumet du Contenu sur le Site Joueur et/ou sur les Applications et en tout état de cause à l’aide des Services, il concède :

a) à BGA, le droit non exclusif, cessible (y compris le droit de sous-licencier), à titre gracieux, et pour le territoire du monde entier d’utiliser, de reproduire, de distribuer, de réaliser des œuvres dérivées, de représenter et d’exécuter le Contenu dans le cadre des Services ou en relation avec la mise à disposition des Services, du Site Joueur et des Applications et l’activité de BGA, notamment, sans limitation, pour la promotion et la redistribution de tout ou partie des Services, du Site Joueur et des Applications (et des œuvres dérivées qui en résultent), en tout format, sur tout support et via tous les canaux média ;

b) à chaque Utilisateur des Services, le droit non exclusif, à titre gracieux, et pour le territoire du monde entier d’accéder à son Contenu via les Services et d’utiliser, de reproduire, de distribuer, de réaliser des œuvres dérivées, de représenter, d’exécuter le Contenu dans la mesure autorisée par les fonctionnalités des Services et par les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 12\. Résiliation du Compte

##### 12.1. Résiliation à l’initiative de BGA

En cas de non-respect des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs et/ou de la Politique de Modération de BGA, BGA se réserve le droit de suspendre temporairement ou de supprimer définitivement le Compte de l’Utilisateur et/ou l’Abonnement Premium de l’Utilisateur dans les conditions de la Politique de Modération de BGA sans que cette suspension et/ou suppression définitive ne puisse donner lieu à l’allocation de quelconque indemnité ou remboursement.

##### 12.2. Résiliation à l’initiative de l’Utilisateur

L’Utilisateur peut résilier son Compte à tout moment, de plein droit et sans formalité préalable, depuis l’onglet « Préférence/Mon Compte » de son Compte, en cliquant sur « supprimer mon compte BGA ».

L’article 12 des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs survivent en tout état de cause à la résiliation du Compte par l’Utilisateur ou par BGA, ce qui signifie que la résiliation du Compte par l’Utilisateur ou par BGA n’est pas de nature à remettre en cause la titularité des Droits de Propriété intellectuelle sur les Contenus tels que prévus dans les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 13\. Responsabilité de l’Utilisateur

L’Utilisateur convient que son utilisation du Site Joueur et/ou des Applications et/ou des Services est à ses risques et qu’il relève de sa responsabilité de garder en vigueur les polices d’assurance maladie, responsabilité civile, risques, blessures personnelles, médicales, vie, et toute autre police d’assurance qu’il jugera raisonnablement nécessaire en cas de quelque préjudice qu’il pourrait subir lors de l’utilisation de l’Application. L’Utilisateur demeure le seul et unique responsable de l’utilisation du Site Joueur, des Applications et des Services mis à sa disposition et du respect des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 14\. Divers

##### 14.1. Notifications

L’Utilisateur accepte que BGA lui adresse des notifications, y compris celles modifiant les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, par courriel, par courrier postal ou par diffusion sur le Site Joueur, les Applications et, le cas échéant sur son Compte.

##### 14.2. Correspondance — Preuve

Sauf disposition particulière des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, les correspondances échangées entre l’Utilisateur et BGA sont principalement assurées par courrier électronique. En application des articles 1366 et suivants du Code civil, l’Utilisateur reconnait et accepte que les informations délivrées par BGA par courrier électronique et sur le Site Joueur fassent foi entre l’Utilisateur et BGA. Les éléments tels que le moment de la réception ou de l’émission, ainsi que la qualité des données reçues feront foi par priorité telle que figurant sur le Site Joueur, ou telles qu’authentifiées par les procédures informatisées de BGA (notamment via les logs collectés), sauf à en apporter la preuve écrite et contraire par l’Utilisateur. La portée de la preuve des informations délivrées par le Site Joueur et/ou les Applications les procédures informatisées de BGA (notamment via les logs collectés) est celle accordée à un original au sens d’un document écrit papier, signé de manière manuscrite.

##### 14.3. Non-renonciation.

L’Utilisateur reconnait que si BGA n’exerce pas ou ne fait pas valoir tout droit ou recours prévu aux présentes C.G.S. Joueurs (ou dont BGA peut bénéficier en vertu de toute loi applicable), cela ne constitue pas une renonciation formelle de BGA ses droits, et ces droits et recours resteront valables et applicables pour BGA.

##### 14.4. Non-validité partielle

Si l’un des termes de ces C.G.S. Joueurs est jugé nul par toute décision d’un tribunal compétent, celui-ci sera supprimé sans affecter les autres termes des C.G.S. Joueurs. Les termes restants demeureront valables et applicables.

##### 14.5. Titres

En cas de difficultés d’interprétation entre l’un des titres figurant en tête des clauses des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, et l’une des clauses, les titres seront déclarés inexistants.

##### 14.6. Bénéficiaire des C.G.S. Joueurs

L’Utilisateur reconnait et accepte que les Filiales de BGA soient considérées comme bénéficiaires des C.G.S. Joueurs et que ces autres sociétés soient autorisées à faire valoir directement et à se fonder sur les termes de ces C.G.S. Joueurs. À l’exception de ce qui est précisé ici, aucune autre personne ou société ne sera considérée comme un tiers bénéficiaire des présentes C.G.S. Joueurs.

#### 15\. Droit applicable — Règlement des litiges

Le présent document a été établi en français et en anglais, toutefois, seule la version française prévaudra en cas de difficulté d'interprétation.

Les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs seront exécutées et interprétées conformément au droit français.

En cas de litige susceptible de survenir en rapport avec les présentes C.G.S. Joueurs, leur interprétation et leurs conséquences ou avec les actes les complétant ou les modifiant, l’Utilisateur se rapprochera de BGA aux fins de tenter d’obtenir une solution amiable.

Toute réclamation auprès de BGA doit être formulée de manière écrite.

À défaut de règlement amiable, l’Utilisateur peut choisir :

1) De recourir à une solution de médiation amiable dans un délai maximal d’un (1) an à compter de sa réclamation écrite à l’attention de BGA :

(i) soit en saisissant un médiateur de la consommation en vue de la résolution amiable du litige. À cet effet, le différend sera soumis à la médiation conformément au règlement de médiation du CMAP - Centre de médiation et d’arbitrage de Paris - près la Chambre de commerce et d’industrie de Paris Ile-de-France,

(ii) soit en recourant au système de règlement en ligne des litiges accessible à l’adresse suivante : https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/odr/main/index.cfm?event=main.home.chooseLanguage, étant précisé que le processus de médiation proposé ne saurait être une condition préalable à une saisie des tribunaux compétents par l’Utilisateur.

2) De porter sa réclamation devant les juridictions françaises compétentes.

Formulaire de rétractation

À l'attention de ............................................... \[à compléter avec la raison sociale de BGA, son adresse géographique et, lorsqu'ils sont disponibles, son numéro de télécopieur et son adresse électronique\] :

Je vous notifie par la présente ma rétractation de mon Abonnement Premium souscrit le \_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_

Nom du consommateur :

Adresse du consommateur :

Signature du consommateur (uniquement en cas de notification du présent formulaire sur papier) :

Date :

### General Terms of Services

#### 1\. Purpose of these Player G.T.S.

The purpose of these Player G.T.S. is to define the terms and conditions for the use of the Player Site and the Services that can be accessed free of charge subject to the prior creation of an Account or for a fee subject to the purchase of a Premium Subscription.

The Services accessible free of charge subject to the prior creation of an Account from the Developer Site, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the Developer G.T.S. available by [clicking here](https://studio.boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos).

The Services accessible free of charge without the need to create an Account, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the G.T.U. available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) of which these Player G.T.U. form an integral part.

#### 2\. Definitions

For the purposes of these Developer G.T.S., capitalized terms, whether singular or plural, have the following meaning:

"Account": means the personal space of a User that is only accessible with Identification Details transmitted by BGA allowing them to access and benefit from the Services;

"Application(s)": means the games accessible from the Developer Site and/or the Player Site, and/or the games accessible only from the Developer Site because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes, published by BGA and/or its Subsidiaries as well as any accessory software which may be necessary, such as an Application update, an Application upgrade, its code (in whole or in part), the files it contains, the associated or generated images and the associated data but also the applications not accessible from the BGA Sites, because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes;

"BGA": means the company AD2G STUDIO, a simplified joint-stock company with a share capital of €100.00, whose registered office is located at 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, registered with the Nanterre Trade and Companies Register under number 803 287 150, represented by Mr. Alexandre Schlecht acting and having the necessary powers as Chairman.

"BGA Moderation Policy": means the BGA moderation policy, accessible by clicking here https://en.doc.boardgamearena.com/Moderationpolicy and forming an integral part of these Player G.T.S.;

"BGA Site(s)": means the Developer Site and/or the Player Site;

"Content": means content of any kind (including textual, visual, video, photographic data, chat rooms, opinions, etc.) published on the BGA Sites through the Services, by a User under their responsibility;

"Developer G.T.S.": means the general terms of service relating to the Services accessible from the Developer Site;

"Developer Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address studio.boardgamearena.com ;

"G.T.U.": means the general terms of use accessible relating to Services accessible without an Account from the BGA Sites;

"Identification Data": means any information provided by the User to create an Account (email address, age, location, etc.);

"Identification Details": means the login or email address and password sent by BGA to the User allowing them to access their Account;

"Internet User": refers to all Internet Users, visitors to the BGA Sites, whether or not they have an Account;

"Personal Data": means the personal data of a User or Internet User collected and processed by BGA in the context of consulting the BGA Sites, such as, where applicable, the creation and management of their Account and the provision of the Services, under the terms and conditions defined in the Privacy Policy;

"Player G.T.S.": means these Player G.T.S.;

"Player Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address boardgamearena.com ;

"Premium Application(s)": means the Applications accessible and usable only by Users with a Premium Subscription;

"Premium Subscription": means a paid Subscription taken out for a certain period of time at the User's discretion, with or without tacit renewal at the User's discretion, and allowing the User to access, for the duration of said Premium Subscription, all the paid Services described in Article 9 of these Player G.T.S. supplemented, where applicable, by the paid Services described on the Player Site.

"Privacy Policy": means the privacy and protection of Users' Personal Data policy implemented by BGA, which forms an integral part of these Player G.T.S.;

"Receiving Medium(s)": means the computers, tablets, smartphones and televisions used to access the BGA Sites and to use the Applications, and which have at least a recent and up-to-date browser;

"Services": means the free features and services made available to Internet Users and accessible, using a Receiving Medium, from the BGA Sites without an Account as well as the free or paid features and services, as determined in the Developer G.T.S. and these Player G.T.S. and accessible from the BGA Sites with an Account, to Users;

"Subsidiary(ies)": means any company or entity that directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by or under common control with BGA. Control of an entity means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or have directed the management or policies of any such entity, whether through ownership of voting securities, by contract or otherwise;

"Third Party Account": means an account to which the User has subscribed with a third party publisher and which may be linked to an Account (for example Google or Facebook);

"Translation": means the literary and/or textual elements of an Application and/or the BGA Sites that are translated into a different language by the User and for which the Intellectual Property Rights are assigned to BGA in accordance with the Developer G.T.S.;

"User(s)": means any natural person at least fifteen (15) years old who is capable or has parental authorisation to do so, including the legal representative (manager, employee, etc.) of a legal entity acting on its behalf, who opens an Account on the Player Site and/or Developer Site and who is not subject to any legal, regulatory or contractual prohibition and/or restriction preventing them from accessing and/or using the Applications and/or developing Developments and/or assigning Developments to BGA and/or performing Translations and/or assigning Translations to BGA and/or distributing Content and having performed, if applicable, all legal, regulatory and contractual formalities to do so, with a view to using the Services;

"Username": means a series of characters allowing the User, with a password determined by them, to connect uniquely to their Account and to access the Services;

"Withdrawal Form": means the form allowing the User to exercise their right to withdraw from their Premium Subscription. The Withdrawal Form is available as an appendix to these General Terms of Service and Use, at the bottom of this page.

#### 3\. Scope, acceptance and modification of the Player G.T.S.

##### 3.1. Acceptance of the Player G.T.S.

These Player G.T.S. govern the rights, obligations and restrictions associated with the use of the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or the Services and/or the purchase of a Premium Subscription.

IF THE USER REFUSES THE TERMS OF THESE PLAYER G.T.S., THEY ARE INVITED NOT TO USE THE SERVICES AVAILABLE FROM THE PLAYER SITE OR ANY OF THE APPLICATIONS.

Access to the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or the use of all or part of the Services and Applications implies that the User accepts and undertakes to respect the Player G.T.S., the Privacy Policy, the G.T.U., any other disclaimer, and/or the other contractual conditions and the rules of the game, if any, applicable when using the Applications, without reservation.

##### 3.2. Modifications of the Player G.T.S.

BGA reserves the right to periodically modify these Player G.T.S., for example to adapt them to legislative and regulatory changes, or to modify the features offered on the Player Site and/or the Services and/or the Applications.

BGA will inform Users, as far as possible, within a maximum of fifteen (15) days before the entry into force of the amended Player G.T.S. Consequently, the User is invited to regularly consult these Developer Player G.T.S. If the User does not accept the amended Player G.T.S., they must stop using the Services. Continuing to use the Services beyond the date of publication of the amended Player G.T.S. will presume the User's acceptance of the amended Player G.T.S.

As these Player G.T.S. may be subject to modifications, the applicable conditions are those in force and accessible on the date of the User's access to the Player Site.

##### 3.3. Information and protection of minors

If the User is a minor and wishes to access the Player Site and make full use of all or part of the Services and/or Applications, they must read the Player G.T.S. and understand them with the help of their parents or legal guardians and obtain their consent to use said Services and/or Applications.

However, BGA recommends that parents or legal guardians monitor the activities of their children or children in their care when using the Services. BGA recommends that Users be vigilant that their children, or the children in their care, never disclose their Personal Data without the consent of the Users.

BGA reserves the right to restrict or prohibit access to the Services by children under the age of fifteen (15) if the prior consent of their parents or legal guardians has not been obtained.

Parents or legal guardians may close the minor's Account at any time by sending an email to BGA whose contact details are available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal).

Notwithstanding the foregoing, use of the BGA Services must be carried out under parental supervision, and any use of the Services by a minor will be presumed to have been validated in advance by their parents or legal guardians.

Unless otherwise provided by law, BGA disclaims any liability for the use of the Services by minors without the consent of their parents or legal guardians.

#### 4\. Terms and conditions of subscription to the Services

##### 4.1. Creation of an Account

In order to access and/or use certain features and/or benefits of the Services, it is necessary to create an Account. To create an Account, the User must go to the Player Site and enter their Identification Data.

The User also has the possibility of linking their Third Party Account within the meaning of the G.T.U. with their Account so that they can directly access the Player Site without having to enter any other Identification Data.

Any connection to the Player Site, any of the Applications and/or the Services using a Third Party Account as defined in the G.T.U. is deemed to have been made with the Account in question. The processing of Personal Data relating to the linking of a Third Party Account to an Account is explained in the Privacy Policy.

Other Identification Data may be entered in the "About" section on the Player Site which will be public and therefore accessible to other Users.

The opening of an Account requires the creation of a Username, if necessary an avatar (visual identity linked to the Account and created by the User), and a password.

The Username is a unique element, and no two Users can have the same Username.

The User agrees that the Username may be publicly displayed as part of the Services in accordance with the Privacy Policy, and therefore the User is advised not to include their surname, which may optionally be publicly displayed in their Account information.

For other Identification Data that may be made public, the User is invited to refer to the Privacy Policy.

The Identification Details are strictly personal. The User undertakes to keep them confidential and not to pass them on to third parties. The User is the only person authorised to access and use the Services using their Account and their Identification Details.

Any access to the Services with the Account is automatically deemed to have been made by the User associated with it and under their responsibility.

Therefore, in the event of loss, theft or any fraudulent act with regard to the Identification Details, it is up to the User to inform BGA as soon as possible and to prove their identity by any means.

Upon receipt of a duly justified notification, BGA will send an email to the User allowing them to update their Identification Details, it being the User's responsibility to keep them strictly confidential.

If BGA has legitimate reason to believe that the security of the Player Site and/or the Application(s) is violated and/or that a misuse of all or part of the Services is due to unauthorised use of the User's Account, BGA may temporarily suspend the User's access to their Account and/or Premium Subscription and therefore their access to the Services, in order to preserve the integrity of the Player Site and/or the Application(s) and the data and, if necessary, require the User to modify their Identification Details according to its instructions.

Likewise, if the User selects a Username as part of the Identification Details enabling them to access their Account that is inappropriate, contrary to good morals or infringing on the rights of a third party, BGA reserves the right to suspend access to the Account concerned and/or to suspend the Premium Subscription in question.

##### 4.2. Veracity and use of Identification Data.

When creating an Account, the User undertakes to provide accurate and complete Identification Data and also undertakes to update this Identification Data in accordance with BGA's requests.

The User shall not allege or imply to be another person or entity by providing false information about a parent, legal guardian or any other person, including, without limitation, through the use of the Username, avatar or any other information such as an image.

BGA may take steps to verify the veracity of the information provided, if necessary, by telephone or by email entered to designate a parent or legal guardian. In order to prevent fraud, the User agrees to provide BGA with the necessary authorisations and evidence in accordance with the Privacy Policy upon request by email.

#### 5\. Use of the Applications

The Applications are made available to the User under a non-transferable, non-exclusive, non-commercial and personal licence, and exclusively for leisure and personal use.

The Applications remain the entire property of BGA and/or its Subsidiaries, in particular with regard to the intellectual property rights associated with them. Consequently, the licence granted does not constitute an assignment of the intellectual property rights of said Applications.

As such, the User shall not sell, copy, exchange, transfer, publish, rent, license, distribute, market or commercially exploit the Application, or decompile, disassemble the code, reduce it to a human readable form or attribute or distribute any element that the User may copy or derive from the Application.

The licence to use the Application shall remain in force for as long as the Application remains accessible on the Player Site. The User may not request a refund of any payment made because an Application is no longer accessible on the Player Site and/or its economic model changes (for example, an Application becomes a Premium Application and vice versa).

The User is informed that the Applications are only compatible with the Receiving Media within the meaning of the G.T.U. and all operating systems and that the performance of the Applications and the related Services may vary accordingly.

#### 6\. Rules of conduct

BGA hereby authorises the User to access and use the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or the Services, subject to compliance with the conditions set out in the G.T.U. and the User is informed that failure to comply with any of these conditions shall constitute a breach of these Player G.T.S.

#### 7\. Online discussion areas

The discussion areas, like the other Services, are moderated a posteriori, and do not allow Content to be checked before it is posted on the Applications.

When the User publishes Content in the discussion areas, their Username and/or avatar may appear. The User declares that they are aware of and accept that the disclosure and/or publication and/or dissemination of their messages is done under their own responsibility. The Content is disseminated on the discussion areas (and more generally using the Services) without any time limit and remains even if the User deletes their Account.

If the User deletes their Account, it becomes invisible on the Player Site and/or the Applications for other Users and is no longer accessible. The User's Content remains even after the deletion of their Account, it being understood that the Content will remain associated with their Username and/or avatar.

#### 8\. Translations

Each User may carry out Translations under the terms and conditions detailed in the Developer G.T.S. which expressly provide that all intellectual property rights associated with such Translations will automatically vest in BGA.

Users therefore guarantee that they have read the Developer G.T.S. before engaging in any Translation (within the meaning of the Developer G.T.S.) which they accept in full and undertake to comply with without restriction or reservation.

#### 9\. Premium Subscription

To access the paid Services, the User is invited to purchase a Premium Subscription offered on the Player Site.

With the Premium Subscription, the User can benefit from the following paid services:

◦ Play Premium Applications;

◦ No waiting before playing an Application;

◦ Play from the same terminal, with several players (only one Premium Subscription is required);

◦ Audio or video conferencing to play the Applications with other Premium Subscription Users;

◦ Access to Application usage statistics;

◦ Play an Application with your favourite colour where possible;

◦ Create tournaments;

◦ Other paid services described on the Player Site where applicable.

The Premium Subscription allows access to "Premium Applications". The full list of "Premium Applications" is available on the "Premium" page of the Player Site.

Each "Premium" Application needs at least one (1) User with a Premium Subscription to start. In other words, Premium Users can create new Premium tables, and play with any other User, with or without a Premium Subscription.

The Services provided with the Premium Subscription provide access to "Premium Extensions". "Premium Extensions" are options (i.e. variants) of an Application that are accessible without a Premium Subscription.

An Application with a "Premium Extension" needs at least one (1) User with a Premium Subscription to start. In other words, Premium Users can create new tables with a "Premium Extension" option selected, and play with any other User, with or without a Premium Subscription.

##### 9.1. Purchase of Premium Subscriptions

To purchase a Premium Subscription, the User is invited to fill in a Subscription form in which they will be asked to select the chosen plan (i.e. a monthly or annual Premium Subscription) and to provide the information mentioned on their payment card in order to proceed with the payment. Any Premium Subscription is concluded for its firm duration.

The sums paid for the Premium Subscription are definitively acquired by BGA, including in the event of early termination of the Premium Subscription, which will take effect, in any event, at the end of the period corresponding to the Premium Subscription purchased.

The only mode of communication between BGA and the User being the exchange of emails, the User declares and guarantees in this regard that the information transmitted by them to BGA is sincere and valid and that the email address provided at the time of registration is perfectly valid and in working order.

It is the User's responsibility to inform BGA of any change in their email address.

The purchase of a Premium Subscription can only be made for personal purposes, which the User declares and acknowledges.

The User's failure to comply with all or part of the obligations subscribed to under the terms of these Player G.T.S., and in particular concerning any payment incident relating to the Subscription price, may entitle BGA to deny the User any further purchase of a Subscription until the situation is remedied.

Before purchasing a Premium Subscription, the User is invited to select the duration of the Premium Subscription of their choice, and then to confirm their Subscription by proceeding with its payment.

Prior to payment of the Premium Subscription, the User is invited to accept the terms of these Player G.T.S. It is accepted that the applicable Player G.T.S. are those in force on the day of confirmation of their Premium Subscription.

Once the User has paid for their Premium Subscription and finalised it on the Player Site, a written confirmation will be sent to them by email, summarising the Premium Subscription plan purchased, its price and the terms of use of the services subscribed to.

The User undertakes to keep the elements contained in the Subscription confirmation email, including its attachments.

##### 9.2. Price of Subscriptions

The prices of Premium Subscriptions is indicated on the Player Site in Euros or in the User's local currency including all taxes (VAT and other applicable taxes).

The User acknowledges and accepts that the amount of their Premium Membership does not include the cost of telecommunications allowing access to the paid Services offered on the Player Site and included in their Premium Subscription, nor any other possible costs of connection to the Internet, which remain in all cases the responsibility of the User, in full.

BGA reserves the right to change its prices at any time.

In the event of a change in the price of Premium Subscription plans, this change will be effective from the time of renewal of the User's Subscription, who will receive an email informing them of this change fifteen (15) days before the date of renewal of his Premium Subscription.

If BGA changes the prices of the Premium Membership plans, these changes will be effective as soon as they are posted on the Player Site.

For some payment methods, the issuer of the User's payment method may charge the User certain fees, such as exchange fees or other fees related to the operation of the User's payment method.

The full payment of the Premium Subscription price is made by credit card with its payment service provider using a secure payment process provided by the latter and which does not, in any case, allow BGA to know the User's bank details. Where applicable, full payment of the Premium Subscription price may be made by any other payment method as indicated on the Player Site.

The full payment of the tacitly renewed Premium Subscription price is made via the payment service provider, meaning that the debit date may be changed, for example if the payment method could not be debited temporarily or depending on the applicable working days.

##### 9.3. Duration of Premium Subscriptions

The User is informed that under the terms of Articles L.215-1, L.215-3 and L.241-3 of the Consumer Code relating to the tacit (automatic) renewal of contracts:

"(L.215-1) For service agreements concluded for a fixed term with a tacit renewal clause, the professional service provider must inform the consumer in writing, by personal letter or dedicated email, at the earliest three months and no later than one month before the end of the period authorising the rejection of the renewal, of the possibility not to renew the contract he has concluded with a tacit renewal clause. This information, delivered in clear and comprehensible terms, mentions, in a clearly visible box, the deadline for non-renewal.

Where this information has not been sent to him in accordance with the first subparagraph, the consumer may terminate the contract free of charge at any time from the date of renewal.

Advances made after the last renewal date or, in the case of open-ended contracts, after the date of conversion of the initial fixed-term contract, shall in this case be repaid within 30 days of the date of termination, after deduction of the sums corresponding, until this date, to the performance of the contract.

The provisions of this Article shall be without prejudice to those which make certain contracts legally subject to special rules concerning consumer information. "

"(L.215-3) The provisions of this chapter shall also apply to contracts concluded between professionals and non-professionals. "

"(L.241-3) Where the trader has not reimbursed under the conditions provided for in Article L. 215- 1, the sums due shall bear interest at the legal rate.

##### 9.4. Tacit and automatic renewal

Whatever the duration of the Premium Subscription and provided that it is technically possible and that it is not a Premium Subscription offered by another User, the User is fully informed that upon its expiry, it will be automatically renewed for a duration identical to that initially subscribed by the User, unless the User cancels it no later than twenty-four (24) hours before the expiry of the current Premium Subscription.

Thus, if the User does not wish to renew or terminate their Subscription, they must log into their Account on the Player Site, go to the "My Preferences" section, then "My Account", and click on "Cancel my subscription" within the time limit referred to above.

In the absence of such notification, the Premium Subscription will be renewed and invoiced on the same basis and at the same intervals as the initial Subscription.

In accordance with Articles L.215-1, L.215-3 and L.241-3 of the Consumer Code reproduced above, BGA will send the User an email informing them of their possibility not to renew the annual Premium Subscription and the terms and conditions of their non-renewal of said Premium Subscription.

#### 10\. Right of withdrawal

The User acknowledges that they have received all the information relating to the Services offered on the Player Site and more specifically to the various Premium Subscription plans offered on the Player Site, before subscribing to them and that the offer of these services complies with the requirements for services provided remotely, in particular via the Internet.

In accordance with the provisions of Article L.221-28° 13 of the Consumer Code, the right of withdrawal cannot be exercised for contracts:

"13° For the supply of digital content not provided on a physical medium whose execution has begun with the express prior agreement of the consumer and the express waiver of his right of withdrawal. "

In accordance with the third paragraph of Article L.221-9 of the Consumer Code:

"The contract shall mention, where appropriate, the consumer's express agreement to the provision of digital content independent of any physical medium before the expiry of the withdrawal period and, in this case, the waiver by the consumer of the right of withdrawal. "

In accordance with the second paragraph of Article L.221-13 of the Consumer Code:

"Where applicable, the trader shall provide the consumer, under the same conditions and before the expiry of the withdrawal period, with confirmation of his express agreement to the provision of digital content not presented on a physical medium and his waiver of the right of withdrawal. "

However, if the User decides to withdraw from their Premium Subscription without giving any reason, within a period of fourteen (14) calendar days from the date of confirmation of their Premium Subscription by BGA, the User must inform BGA of their intention, at the latest within the aforementioned period of fourteen (14) days, either by completing and sending to BGA the Withdrawal Form attached to these Player G.T.S. and by following the instructions contained therein; or, by expressing their intention to withdraw in a clear and unequivocal manner including the essential information to do so by email or by post to BGA whose full contact details are available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal).

As soon as possible after BGA has received the Withdrawal Form or the notification of the User's wish to exercise their right of withdrawal, BGA will send acknowledgement of receipt to the User by email. The costs associated with sending the Withdrawal Form shall be borne by the User.

#### 11\. Intellectual property

##### 11.1. Use of Services

The Services are designed, published and managed by or on behalf of BGA. The User acknowledges and accepts that access to the Applications, Content and Services made available by BGA does not imply any transfer of intellectual property rights to the User.

Access to the Services is exclusively limited to the private and personal use of the User under the conditions and within the limits defined in these Player G.T.S.

##### 11.2. Content

As an Account holder, the User may submit Content using the Services.

The User retains all intellectual property rights to their Content, but is required to grant limited rights to BGA and other Users under the conditions set out in Article 12.3 below.

The User acknowledges and accepts that they are solely responsible for their own Content and the consequences of its dissemination, including any indirect dissemination via hypertext links. BGA does not guarantee any Content, recommendation or opinion expressed therein, and BGA expressly disclaims all liability relating to such Content.

The User represents and warrants that they have (and will continue to have during the use of the Services) all the rights, licences, consents and authorisations necessary to allow BGA to use their Content for the purpose of offering the Player Site, the Applications, the Services and more generally under the conditions contemplated by these Player G.T.S.

The User acknowledges that, by simply using the Services, they may be exposed to Content that is inaccurate, offensive, indecent or otherwise negative. In its capacity as host, BGA shall in no way be held responsible for the distribution of this type of Content.

BGA reserves the right to contact the User in order to obtain more information about the Content posted and to verify that the User is the author and, if applicable, that the User holds the rights.

In any event, BGA is not bound by, committed to, or responsible for the opinions, advice and/or recommendations posted and/or sent by Users using the Services and specifically in the discussion areas and declines all responsibility in this regard.

##### 11.3. The rights granted by the User on their Content

When the User submits Content to the Player Site and/or the Applications and in any event through the Services, the User grants:

a) to BGA, the non-exclusive, transferable (including the right to sub-license), free of charge, worldwide right to use, reproduce, distribute, make derivative works of, represent and display the Content as part of the Services or in connection with the provision of the Services, the Player Site and the Applications and the activity of BGA, including, without limitation, for the promotion and redistribution of all or part of the Services, the Player Site and the Applications (and any resulting derivative works), in any format, on any medium and through any media channels;

b) to each User of the Services, the non-exclusive, free of charge, worldwide right to access their Content via the Services and to use, reproduce, distribute, make derivative works of, represent and display the Content to the extent permitted by the functionalities of the Services and by these Player G.T.S.

#### 12\. Termination of the Account

##### 12.1. Termination at the initiative of BGA

In the event of non-compliance with these Player G.T.S. and/or the BGA Moderation Policy, BGA reserves the right to temporarily suspend or permanently delete the User's Account and/or the User's Premium Subscription under the conditions of the BGA Moderation Policy, without this suspension and/or permanent deletion giving rise to any compensation or refund.

##### 12.2. Termination at the initiative of the User

The User may terminate their Account at any time, by right and without prior formality, from the "Preference/My Account" tab of their Account, by clicking on "delete my BGA account".

Article 12 of these Player G.T.S. shall in any case survive the termination of the Account by the User or by BGA, which means that the termination of the Account by the User or by BGA shall not call into question the ownership of the Intellectual Property Rights on the Content as provided for in these Player G.T.S.

#### 13\. User's liability

The User agrees that their use of the Player Site and/or the Applications and/or the Services is at their own risk and that it is their responsibility to maintain such health, liability, risk, personal injury, medical, life, and other insurance policies as they may reasonably deem necessary in the event of any damage they may suffer while using the Application. The User remains solely responsible for the use of the Player Site, the Applications and the Services made available to them and for compliance with these Player G.T.S.

#### 14\. Miscellaneous

##### 14.1. Notifications

The User accepts that BGA may send them notifications, including those amending these Player G.T.S., by email, by post or by posting on the Player Site, the Applications and, where applicable, on their Account.

##### 14.2. Correspondence— Evidence

Unless otherwise provided for in these Player G.T.S., correspondence between the User and BGA is mainly by email. Pursuant to Articles 1366 et seq. of the Civil Code, the User acknowledges and accepts that the information provided by BGA by email and on the Player Site is authentic between the User and BGA. Elements such as the time of reception or transmission, as well as the quality of the data received, will be deemed authentic by priority as shown on the Player Site, or as authenticated by BGA's computerised procedures (in particular via the logs collected), unless the User provides written proof to the contrary. The scope of proof of the information provided by the Player Site and/or the Applications and the computerised procedures of BGA (in particular via the collected logs) is that granted to an original in the sense of a written paper document, signed by hand.

##### 14.3. Non-waiver.

The User acknowledges that if BGA does not exercise or assert any right or remedy provided for in these Player G.T.S. (or from which BGA may benefit under any applicable law), this does not constitute a formal waiver by BGA of its rights, and these rights and remedies shall remain valid and enforceable for BGA.

##### 14.4. Severability

If any of the terms of these Player G.T.S. are found to be invalid by any decision of a competent court, they shall be deleted without affecting the other terms of the Player G.T.S. The remaining terms shall remain valid and enforceable.

##### 14.5. Titles

In the event of difficulties of interpretation between one of the titles appearing at the top of the clauses of these Player G.T.S. and one of the clauses, the titles will be declared non-existent.

##### 14.6. Beneficiary of the Player G.T.S.

The User acknowledges and accepts that the BGA Subsidiaries are considered beneficiaries of the Player G.T.S. and that these other companies be allowed to directly enforce and rely on the terms of these Player G.T.S. Except as specified herein, no other person or company shall be considered a third party beneficiary of these Player G.T.S.

#### 15\. Applicable Law— Dispute settlement

This document has been drawn up in French and English, however, only the French version will prevail in the event of difficulty of interpretation.

These Player G.T.S. will be executed and interpreted in accordance with French law.

In the event of a dispute arising in connection with these Player G.T.S., their interpretation and their consequences or with the deeds supplementing or modifying them, the User shall approach BGA for the purpose of attempting to find an amicable solution.

All complaints to BGA must be made in writing.

Failing amicable settlement, the User may choose:

1) To resort to an amicable mediation solution within a maximum period of one (1) year from the date of their written complaint to BGA:

(i) or by referring the matter to a consumer mediator with a view to amicably resolving the dispute. To this end, the dispute shall be submitted to mediation in accordance with the mediation rules of the CMAP - Paris Mediation and Arbitration Centre - at the Paris Ile-de-France Chamber of Commerce and,

(ii) or by using the online dispute resolution system accessible at the following address:https://webgate.ec.europa.eu/odr/main/index.cfm?event=main.home.chooseLanguage, it being specified that the proposed mediation process cannot be a prerequisite for a referral to the competent courts by the User.

2) To bring their claim before the competent French courts.

Withdrawal form

To the attention of ............................................... \[to be completed with BGA's company name, geographical address and, where available, fax number and email address\]:

I hereby notify you of my withdrawal from my Premium Subscription purchased on \_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_

Consumer's name:

Consumer's address:

Consumer's signature (only in case of notification of this form on paper):

Date:

### General Terms of Services

#### Preamble

The purpose of the BGA Sites is to allow the greatest number of people to discover new Games and to play them through the Applications. To this end, BGA offers Users who so wish to participate in the development of the Applications and/or BGA Sites, and in particular the Services on the Developer Site provide the User with an ecosystem enabling them to develop Code.

This activity is neither compulsory nor remunerated and its sole purpose is to allow Users who wish to do so to engage in computer developments, in particular the digitisation of Games, and to provide them with a medium enabling them to publish their Creations and Codes.

If the User does not wish to have their Intellectual Property Rights on their Creations and/or Codes vested in and/or licensed to BGA, they must not communicate their Creations and/or Codes in any way, either through the BGA Sites or by any other means.

However, in order to enable BGA to respect the Licences subscribed to with the publishers of the Games and therefore to operate the BGA Sites, the grant or assignment of the Intellectual Property Rights associated with the Users' Codes and Creations must be regulated. This is the purpose of Article 6, which provides for a licence to be granted on the Users' Codes, and Article 7, which provides for the assignment of the intellectual property rights on Creations to BGA.

The user acknowledges and accepts that the production of users' Creations and Codes as well as the vesting and/or assignment and/or granting of Intellectual Property Rights relating thereto are carried out free of charge. The User waives, in full knowledge of the facts, the benefit of Articles L.131-6 of the Intellectual Property Code.

You can develop board games to make them available online on BGA as a volunteer software developer :)

#### 1\. Purpose of these Developer G.T.S.

The purpose of these Developer G.T.S. is to define the conditions of use of the Developer Site and the Services accessible free of charge subject to the prior creation of an Account. The Services accessible free of charge subject to the prior creation of an Account on the Player Site, the Services accessible subject to the purchase of a Premium Subscription, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the Player G.T.S. available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos). The Services accessible free of charge without the need to create an Account, their terms and conditions, are detailed in the G.T.U. available by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) of which these Developer G.T.S. are an integral part.

#### 2\. Acceptance and modification of the Developer G.T.S.

##### 2.1. Acceptance of the Developer G.T.S.

These Developer G.T.S. govern the rights, obligations and restrictions associated with the use of the Developer Site and/or the Applications and/or the Services.

IN PARTICULAR, THESE DEVELOPER G.T.S. PROVIDE A FRAMEWORK FOR THE GRANT OR ASSIGNMENT OF INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS ON USERS' CREATIONS AND CODES. THEREFORE, IF THE USER REFUSES THE TERMS OF THESE DEVELOPER G.T.S., THEY ARE INVITED NOT TO USE THE SERVICES AVAILABLE FROM THE DEVELOPER SITE AND NOT TO SEND CREATIONS OR CODES TO BGA.

Access to the Developer Site and/or the Applications and/or the use of all or part of the Services, the Applications and/or the communication by the User to BGA of Creations and/or Codes implies that the User accepts and undertakes to respect the Developer G.T.S., the Privacy Policy, the G.T.U., any other disclaimer, and/or other applicable contractual terms and conditions without reservation.

BGA hereby authorises the User to access and use the Developer Site and/or the Applications and/or the Services, subject to compliance with the conditions set out in the G.T.U. and the User is informed that failure to comply with any of these conditions shall constitute a breach of these Developer G.T.S.

You should use this service only if you agree with the terms.

##### 2.2. Modifications of the Developer G.T.S.

BGA reserves the right to periodically modify these Developer G.T.S. and the Privacy Policy, for example to adapt them to legislative and regulatory changes, or to modify the features offered on the Developer Site and/or the Services and/or the Applications.

BGA will inform the Users, as far as possible, within a maximum of fifteen (15) days before the entry into force of the amended Developer G.T.S. Consequently, the User is invited to regularly consult these Developer G.T.S. If the User does not accept the amended Developer G.T.S., they must stop using the Services. Continuing to use the Services beyond the date of publication of the amended Developer G.T.S. will presume the User's acceptance of the amended Developer G.T.S.

#### 3\. Definitions

For the purposes of these Developer G.T.S., including their Preamble, the capitalised terms defined in the G.T.U. and the Player G.T.S. will apply and other capitalized terms, whether singular or plural, will have the following meaning:

"Anomaly": means a design, production or performance defect (such as: bug, error, etc.) and more generally any defect or problem resulting in operating difficulties that prevent or limit, in whole or in part, the operation and/or use and/or administration of all or part of an Application and/or the BGA Sites;

"Application(s)": means the games accessible from the Developer Site and/or the Player Site, and/or the games accessible only from the Developer Site because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes, published by BGA and/or its Subsidiaries as well as any accessory software which may be necessary, such as an Application update, an Application upgrade, its code (in whole or in part), the files it contains, the associated or generated images and the associated data but also the applications not accessible from the BGA Sites, because they are under development or have not been approved by BGA, composed in whole or in part of User Codes;

"BGA": means the company AD2G STUDIO, a simplified joint-stock company with a share capital of €100.00, whose registered office is located at 18 rue Jacqueline Auriol, 78280 Guyancourt, registered with the Nanterre Trade and Companies Register under number 803 287 150, represented by Mr. Alexandre Schlecht acting and having the necessary powers as Chairman;

"BGA Approver": means a User with an Account on the Player Site and meeting the criteria defined in the Player Site https://boardgamearena.com/reviewer;

"BGA Documentation": means the documentation concerning the BGA Sites and/or Applications and accessible here: https://en.doc.boardgamearena.com/Studio;

"BGA Site(s)": means the Developer Site and/or the Player Site;

"Code(s)": refers to all computer and software developments, including by adaptation of a pre-existing computer development, both in their executable and source versions, whether completed or not, as well as, where applicable, any update(s) made by the User in the context of the development of an Application including its improvement;

"Creation(s)": refers to all the works that will be designed and/or produced in whole or in part by the User constituting a derivative work or an adaptation of the Games, and/or concerning the Applications and/or BGA Sites on which BGA and/or a third party hold Intellectual Property Rights, on any medium whatsoever, whatever the conditions of design and/or production, i.e. in particular alone or with the assistance of third parties, including other Users or with the assistance of BGA. These works include any literary (including translations), graphic, textual, computer graphics, photographic, video, digital, software, script, computer development, algorithmic development, etc., and, where applicable, all associated documentation, more particularly Translations, etc. and more generally any intellectual work in any format, whether or not it is protected by intellectual property rights, including in particular their layout, presentation, choice and arrangement of materials, choice of techniques, colours, texts, etc., but with the exception of Users' Codes;

"Developer G.T.S.": means these general terms of service relating to the Services accessible from the Developer Site;

"Developer Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address studio.boardgamearena.com ;

"Game": means a board game for which BGA holds a Licence;

"G.T.U.": means the general terms of use accessible by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) and relating to Services accessible without an Account from the BGA Sites;

"Intellectual Property Rights": means all rights (including moral rights) available under any patent, copyright, trademark, service mark, trade name, product configuration, design, software rights, domain names, database rights or trade secret rights or any other statutory or doctrinal provision of codified or common law relating to a Game and its titles, elements, themes, design, logo, characters, character names, stories, dialogue, animation, sounds, audio-visual effects, musical compositions, designs, formulas, algorithms, procedures, methods, techniques, ideas, know-how, programs, sub-programs, tools, inventions, Codes, Creations related thereto, improvements thereto, in any form whatsoever, whether or not specifically referred to in these Developer G.T.S., which may exist in any part of the world, recognised by the law of the European Union or of a member state of the European Union, in particular France, the law of the United States or other foreign jurisdictions and/or by other international laws and whether or not such rights are registered and including all applications, renewals or extensions of such rights for their full term;

"Licence": means the licence of Intellectual Property Rights granted to BGA by the publisher of a Game to adapt the Game or have it adapted in the form of an Application and to publish, distribute and promote this Application, worldwide and from the BGA Sites;

"Player G.T.S.": means the general terms of service accessible by [clicking here](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos) and relating to the Services accessible from the Player Site;

"Player Site": means the website accessible in particular from the URL address boardgamearena.com ;

"Services": means the free features and services made available to Internet Users and accessible, using a Receiving Medium, from the BGA Sites without an Account as well as the free or paid features and services, as determined in the Developer G.T.S. and these Player G.T.S. and accessible from the BGA Sites with an Account, to Users;

"Sequel" or "Prequel" or "Spin-off": means multimedia works in any language, in any form, including one or more identical characters, themes and/or situations of an Application and in accordance with the meaning usually and currently attributed to the words Sequel, Prequel or Spin-off according to use in the video game industry;

"Specifications": means the instructions issued by BGA, by any means, the purpose of which is to define and describe the scope, nature and extent of the Codes and/or Creations for the purpose of creating an Application in order to comply with the Licence and which the User undertakes to respect. The BGA Documentation is an integral part of the Specifications;

"Translation": means the literary and/or textual elements of an Application and/or the BGA Sites that are translated into a different language by the User and for which the Intellectual Property Rights are assigned to BGA in accordance with these Developer G.T.S.;

"User": means any natural person at least fifteen (15) years old who is capable or has parental authorisation to do so, including the legal representative (manager, employee, etc.) of a legal entity acting on its behalf, who opens an Account, using a Receiving Medium, on the Developer Site and/or on the Player Site and who is not subject to any legal, regulatory or contractual prohibition and/or restriction preventing them from accessing and/or using the Applications and/or from producing and/or communicating to BGA, including for commercial purposes, Creations and/or Codes and/or from distributing Content and having performed, if applicable, all legal, regulatory and contractual formalities to do so, with a view to using the Services;

In the event of a contradiction between the definitions of the G.T.U. and/or the Player G.T.S. and/or Developer G.T.S., the definitions of these Developer G.T.S. will prevail.

#### 4\. Terms and conditions of access to the Services

The use of the Services available on the Developer Site requires the creation of an Account carried out in accordance with the terms and conditions set out in the Player G.T.S., with the following exceptions:

\- In order to create an Account on the Developer Site, the User must first have an Account on the Player Site.

\- The Identification Data required on the Developer Site may be different from that required on the Player Site.

#### 5\. Editorial policy of the BGA Sites

Each User may create Creations and/or Codes in order to develop all or part of an Application and/or a BGA Site, and allow other Users or BGA to participate.

In order to contribute to an Application, the User must necessarily and compulsorily select a Game for which BGA benefits from a Licence or obtain BGA's prior and express agreement, without which BGA cannot be held liable and the User must guarantee and hold BGA harmless against any claims and/or actions by third parties in this respect.

In order to allow BGA to respect the Licence granted to it by a publisher, the User undertakes to:

• Deliver their Creations and Codes to BGA exclusively from the Developer Site in a format that is interoperable and compatible with the Player Site, in particular by complying with the Specifications;

• Deliver all of their Creations and Codes and in particular the source code of the Codes, the associated documentation as well as any document necessary for the publication and exploitation, if applicable commercial, of the Application.

The User undertakes, in the context of the production of the Creations and/or Codes, to comply with all legal, statutory and regulatory provisions relating to the Creations, Codes, the Game and the Application, where applicable in accordance with the Specifications.

The User undertakes not to include in their Creations and/or Codes, without BGA's prior and express consent, excessive scenes of violence, racist opinions, or any element likely to prevent the commercial distribution of the Application.

The User undertakes not to introduce into the Application and/or their Creations or Codes any element (sound, graphic, script, visual or other) which, by its nature, would affect the image and/or reputation of the Game and the Application and/or BGA and/or the Game publisher.

BGA must have a license for the game (if it's not in the public domain), and your adaptation must be faithful to the game.

The User is informed that BGA is solely responsible for the editorial policy of the BGA Sites and, as such, decides at its own discretion whether or not to publish and/or withdraw the Creations and/or Codes and/or Applications created by and/or in which the Users participate and, if applicable, already published. These arbitrary choices are explained by BGA's overall editorial policy for the BGA Sites and consequently cannot prejudice Users in any way. Indeed, BGA does not guarantee under any circumstances the publication on the BGA Sites of the Creations and/or Codes created, developed and/or communicated by the User, without the User being able to claim any compensation or damage in this respect.

BGA will credit on the BGA Sites the User who has participated in an Application on the description page of the Application, with reference to their BGA Username, supplemented with their real name if the User explicitly requests this, unless the User explicitly requests anonymity.

#### 6\. User Codes

##### 6.1. Types of User Codes

This article details the types of Codes that can be produced by any User of the Developer Site, without this being an exhaustive list.

###### 6.1.1. Contribution to an Application and/or a BGA Site

Each User may develop Codes to create a new Application and/or participate in an ongoing Application project.

Once the Application project is finalised, its validation takes place in three phases:

• Alpha version: The User who initiated the Application project will present it for acceptance on the Player Site exclusively for technical and/or functional testing by a BGA Approver. The BGA Approver will test the Application project, notify any defects identified in the Application project and assess the quality of the Application project. After initial testing by the BGA Approver, the Alpha version of the Application project will be analysed and reviewed by BGA and/or the Licensor. BGA and/or the Licensor will review the Application project and in particular its compliance with the Specifications. Most major defects will necessarily have to be addressed and corrected by any User in order to launch the second acceptance phase.

• Beta version: Once accepted by BGA and/or the Licensor, the Alpha version is published on the Player Site for testing and acceptance by all Users of the Player Site to verify the quality of the Application project, its compliance with the Game and the Specifications and that no defects remain. Once this phase has been completed and all remaining notified defects have been fully corrected by a User, BGA will publish the Application resulting from the validated Application project at its discretion, without any deadline obligation for BGA.

The User undertakes not to include - in the Codes - programs under open source license without the prior consent of BGA in order to allow BGA to ensure that the licence conditions of said open source codes do not have any contaminating effect that could alter their operation and use by BGA.

###### 6.1.2. Corrections of Anomalies on the BGA Sites and/or on the Applications

Each User may develop Codes to correct an Anomaly, identified on the Developer Site (but which may concern the BGA Sites and/or an Application). To do so, the User will develop a Code useful for the correction of an Anomaly directly from the Developer Site and submit it to BGA for approval and/or proceed directly with its publication if they have received the appropriate accreditations from BGA.

The Codes, once approved by BGA, are posted online. Otherwise, BGA will explain to the User the reasons why it has refused to post the Codes online and the User may then correct their previous Codes or submit new ones or do nothing.

##### 6.2. Intellectual Property Rights on Codes

The User is and remains the owner of all Intellectual Property Rights on the Codes provided to BGA, provided that they cannot be qualified as a collective work within the meaning of the applicable law.

The User will therefore be able to freely exploit their Codes, subject to the rights of third parties, and in particular the elements made available by BGA or by other Users, or the elements resulting from the Licence of the Game for which the Code has been developed. The User expressly acknowledges and accepts that all information, documents, graphic, technical and computer elements, tools, visuals, brands, logos or other elements belonging to BGA or to the Licensor and made available to the User for the purposes of creating the Codes (hereinafter the "Pre-existing Elements") are and remain the exclusive property of BGA or of the Licensor and may not be used by the User for any purpose other than strict exploitation on the BGA Sites. Any other use of the Pre-existing Elements outside the BGA Sites is strictly prohibited.

In this context, the User acknowledges and agrees to grant BGA a licence on the Intellectual Property Rights of a proprietary nature attached to the Codes, (in particular with regard to the tools, devices and programming engines integrated into the Codes as well as their source codes, whether compiled or not) free of charge, non-exclusive for the territory of the whole world and for the entire duration of the protection currently granted to the Codes, or which will be granted in the future to the authors of intellectual works within the meaning of the Intellectual Property Code by French laws and regulations as well as by international conventions.

Intellectual Property Rights of a proprietary nature granted to BGA on the User's Code(s) include:

\- the right to use and exploit it commercially, including for Premium Applications, to distribute it and to license (or sub-license) it;

\- the right to represent and reproduce it, in as many copies as BGA deems necessary, on any medium, format or network, known and unknown on the date the Code is made available by the User, directly or indirectly, in particular by unit sales, subscription, downloading or rental via the Internet by streaming or game on demand, compilation, or by licences freely granted by BGA and the third parties of its choice;

\- the right to modify it, in whole or in part, by addition, deletion, correction, etc.;

\- the right to adapt it in whole or in part;

\- the right to develop, add or delete it, in whole or in part, in the context of a port to all consoles and all operating systems known or unknown on the date of execution of this agreement.

\- the right to incorporate it, in whole or in part, into any pre-existing or future work;

\- the right to rewrite it in any other computer language;

\- the right to translate it into another language;

\- the right to use it on other media or to adapt it to operating systems other than those used or known at the time of subscription to the Developer G.T.S.;

\- the right to exploit it in any form, in particular in the form of merchandising for one or more Sequel(s) and/or Prequel(s) and/or Spin-offs;

\- the right to file and/or register it with any competent office, including from the time of its conception, in its name and on its behalf,

The User acknowledges and accepts that BGA is entitled to have all or part of the above rights granted to it exercised by a third party of its choice, including, where applicable, another User.

In this sense, Users may publish their Code with the exception of Pre-existing Elements on any separate medium under any licence of their choice, provided that the following notice is included in a comment on the Code: **“This code was developed on the BGA studio platform for use on http://boardgamearena.com”**.

You can open your code under any license compatible with its use on BGA, as long as you include the above mentioned sentence as comment in your code.

Game assets stay the property of the game rights owner and should not be made available outside of BGA.

#### 7\. Creations

##### 7.1. Types of Creation

This article details the types of Creations that can be made by any User, without this being an exhaustive list.

###### 7.1.1. Contribution to the BGA Documentation

Each User may, at their own discretion, update the BGA Documentation, without said contribution being subject to any a priori approval, verification or moderation by BGA.

###### 7.1.2. Translations

Translations can be made directly from the Player Site. Each User may thus translate all or part of the BGA Sites and/or Applications.

The User undertakes to carry out a Translation only if the target language is their mother tongue or one that they are fluent in. When translating an Application, the User must be truly familiar with the Application and, if possible, have a box and a booklet of the physical game rules from which the Application originates in the target language in order to verify their consistency. Users making Translations must take into account the language level and formal/informal pronominal rules customary for the game's audience in their country.

The source/reference language for the Translation is English, as the development of the BGA Sites and Applications is carried out in English, which means that modifying a text in English leads to modifications in all languages. The User who carries out the Translation undertakes to respect the final punctuation (or absence thereof), the choice of words in capital letters and the use of numbers instead of words.

Translations can be modified until they are "validated". Validation takes place after thirty (30) days without modification. It is then considered stable and valid (golden icon) and can only be modified by Users with significant experience on the Player Site.

###### 7.1.3. Contribution to an Application and/or a BGA Site

Each User may, at their discretion, propose on the Developer Site works derived from the Games, the BGA Sites and/or any other element on which a third party holds Intellectual Property Rights.

These Creations (artworks, logos, graphic creations in digital format, etc.) are distinct from the Users' Codes for which the Users retain ownership of their Intellectual Property Rights and grant a licence to BGA in accordance with the provisions of Article 6.

##### 7.2. Intellectual Property Rights on Creations

###### 7.2.1. Vesting of Intellectual Property Rights on Creations in favour of BGA

In accordance with the provisions of Article L.113-2 of the Intellectual Property Code, the Applications and, where necessary, the Creations must be considered as collective works, which each User expressly acknowledges and accepts.

Indeed, the User acknowledges that these Creations have been created at the initiative of BGA (which has in particular taken the necessary and useful steps to obtain a Licence) which will edit, publish and disclose the Creations via the Applications and the BGA Sites, under its direction and name.

The Creations of each User are thus merged into the Applications and BGA Sites for which they were designed, without it being possible to ultimately attribute to each of the Users who are the authors of these Creations a distinct right over the entirety produced, i.e. the Applications and/or the BGA Sites.

In this respect, the User acknowledges that the Creations and/or the Applications and the BGA Sites are collective works, the property of BGA, which is the sole owner of the intellectual property rights.

###### 7.2.2. Assignment of Intellectual Property Rights on Creations in favour of BGA

If one or more elements making up the Creations should be considered as not resulting from a collective work, in order to avoid any future dispute over the scope of BGA's rights, and in order to ensure BGA's legal certainty in the use decided upon, the User expressly acknowledges that the Intellectual Property Rights attached to the Creations are assigned immediately and free of charge to the exclusive benefit of BGA for the entire world and for the entire duration of the protection currently granted to the Creations, or which will be granted in the future to the authors of intellectual works within the meaning of the Intellectual Property Code by French laws and regulations as well as by international conventions.

Consequently, BGA is the sole owner of all Intellectual Property Rights relating to said Creations and to all physical media provided or developed by the User for these Creations, including, but not limited to, any written, graphic, photographic, audio, audiovisual, process, program, sub-program, software, part of software, source code, object code and any other programming code created and/or developed, in any form and on any medium known or unknown to date.

The assignment and transfer of Intellectual Property Rights will take effect as and when the User produces the Creations, meaning that BGA will acquire ownership of the Intellectual Property Rights on the Creations, whether or not they are validated and/or distributed and/or exploited by BGA and whether or not the BGA Sites and/or Applications for which the Creations are intended are validated and/or distributed and/or exploited by BGA.

In order to comply with the provisions of Article L.122-7 of the Intellectual Property Code, which requires that the nature and extent of the possible uses be mentioned, it is expressly stipulated that the User acknowledges and accepts that the free assignment of Intellectual Property Rights of a proprietary nature on the Creations means:

\- the right to use and exploit them commercially, including for Premium Applications, to distribute and license (or sub-license) them in any form whatsoever, even if this is not foreseen or foreseeable at the date of subscription to the Developer G.T.S.;

\- the right to reproduce them, by any means and on any medium, known and unknown at the date of subscription to the Developer G.T.S. and in as many copies as BGA deems necessary, on any medium, format or network, known and unknown at the date of execution of this Contract, directly or indirectly, in particular by unit sales, subscription, download or rental via the Internet by streaming or game on demand, compilation, or by licences freely granted by BGA and third parties of its choice;

\- the right to represent them by any means, known and unknown at the date of subscription to the Developer G.T.S., including radio, cable, satellite, Internet, Intranet, Extranet, etc.;

\- the right to modify them, in whole or in part, by addition, deletion, correction, etc.;

\- the right to adapt them in whole or in part;

\- the right to adapt, modify, evolve, add or delete them, in whole or in part, in the context of a port to all consoles and all operating systems known or unknown on the date of execution of this agreement.

\- the right to incorporate them, in whole or in part, into any pre-existing or future work;

\- the right to make them evolve, to develop them;

\- the right to rewrite them in any other computer language;

\- the right to translate them into another language;

\- the right to use them on other media or to adapt them to operating systems other than those used or known at the time of subscription to the Developer G.T.S.;

\- the right to assign the Developer G.T.S. to any third party of their choice;

\- the right to exploit it in any form, in particular in the form of merchandising for one or more Sequel(s) and/or Prequel(s) and/or Spin-offs;

\- And, in general, all the author's property rights over his creation.

The User acknowledges and accepts that BGA is entitled to have all or part of the aforementioned operations carried out by a third party of its choice, including, where applicable, another User.

The User declares and guarantees that they will not exploit or register any Intellectual Property Rights relating to the Creations, either in their own name or in the name of any other natural or legal person whatsoever.

You give BGA the rights to use your board game adaptations. Otherwise, nothing can happen :)

#### 8\. Confidentiality

The User undertakes to keep confidential the elements provided by BGA and/or by the publisher of a Game, to enable it to carry out and develop the Creations and Codes. In the event that the User publishes their Code on any separate medium under any licence of their choice under the conditions of Article 6.2, they shall refrain from adding to it the elements provided by BGA and/or by the publisher of a Game, to enable them to create and develop the Creations and Codes in order to preserve their confidentiality.

#### 9\. BGA's Intellectual Property Rights

The User acknowledges that the subscription to these Developer G.T.S. does not entail any transfer to them of any Intellectual Property Rights.

BGA, as the case may be, is and remains the owner of all Intellectual Property Rights and exploitation rights on pre-existing elements belonging to it (notably on the Services) provided to the User in the framework of the Developer G.T.S.

The Services are designed, published and managed by or on behalf of BGA.

Access to the Services is exclusively limited to the private and personal use of the User under the conditions and within the limits defined in the G.T.U. and these Developer G.T.S.

#### 10\. Guarantees and liability of the User

Due to the gratuitous nature of the assignment, grant and/or vesting of the Intellectual Property Rights on Creations and Codes under the Developer G.T.S., the Creations and Codes are provided "as is" to BGA, without any guarantees as to the suitability of the Creations and Codes for the use for which they are intended, their commercial value, their secure, innovative or relevant nature.

Notwithstanding full compliance with these Developer G.T.S., the User thus offers, without limitation, no guarantee, express or tacit, concerning: (i) the ability of the Creations and Codes to fulfil the objectives that BGA has set itself, or to perform in the combinations of use chosen by BGA (ii) the absence of errors or the uninterrupted performance of the Creations and Codes (iii) the possible or potential correction of any errors in the Creations and Codes (iv) the compatibility of the Creations and Codes, or of the data structures generated by the use of the Creations and Codes, with a subsequent edition or version of the Applications, if any, or with the BGA Sites.

However, the User declares and guarantees to BGA that they have all the necessary rights to the Creations and Codes for the assignment or grant of the related Intellectual Property Rights as provided for in Articles 6 and 7 above.

Consequently, the User guarantees BGA the peaceful enjoyment of the Intellectual Property Rights assigned or granted under the Developer G.T.S. and shall hold BGA harmless against any claim(s), action(s), recourse or lawsuit(s) brought against it by a third party.

In the event of an out-of-court or legal claim by a third party against BGA, based on the fact that a Creation or Code is unlawful and/or infringes upon the rights, in particular the Intellectual Property Rights, of third parties, the User undertakes to defend BGA, at their own expense, against any such action and to indemnify BGA for any damage of any nature whatsoever that BGA may suffer as a result of such a challenge and, in any event, undertakes to pay any damages that BGA may be ordered to pay and to bear all reasonable costs resulting from any judicial or extrajudicial action taken by a third party.

You don't have any obligation related to the board game adaptations you create, as long as you don't include improperly licensed elements.

#### 11\. Termination of the Account

The User may terminate their Account under the terms and conditions of the Player G.T.S.

Articles 6, 7, 8 and 9 of these Developer G.T.S. shall in any case survive the termination of the Account by the User or by BGA, which means that the termination of the Account by the User or by BGA shall not call into question the ownership of the Intellectual Property Rights on the Creations and/or Codes as provided for in these Developer G.T.S.

#### 12\. Applicable law

THIS DOCUMENT HAS BEEN DRAWN UP IN FRENCH AND ENGLISH, HOWEVER, ONLY [THE FRENCH VERSION](https://cdn.boardgamearena.net/data/others/CGS-Developpeurs-BGA-v1.0.pdf) WILL PREVAIL IN THE EVENT OF A DIFFICULTY OF INTERPRETATION.

THESE DEVELOPER G.T.S. WILL BE EXECUTED AND INTERPRETED IN ACCORDANCE WITH FRENCH LAW.

IN THE EVENT OF A DISPUTE ARISING IN CONNECTION WITH THESE G.T.S., THEIR INTERPRETATION AND THEIR CONSEQUENCES OR WITH THE DEEDS SUPPLEMENTING OR MODIFYING THEM, THE USER SHALL APPROACH BGA FOR THE PURPOSE OF ATTEMPTING TO FIND AN AMICABLE SOLUTION. ALL COMPLAINTS TO BGA MUST BE MADE IN WRITING. IN THE ABSENCE OF AN AMICABLE SETTLEMENT, THE USER WILL HAVE THE RIGHT TO BRING THEIR CLAIM EXCLUSIVELY BEFORE THE COMPETENT FRENCH COURTS.

Application loading... ...

[{DISPLAY\_IN\_OTHER\_LANG}](#) {LANG\_REDIRECT\_CODE}

Ooops, we seem to be having difficulties reaching you by email...

  {CONFIRM\_EMAIL\_MESSAGE}

{CHECK\_SPAMBOX}

boardgamearena.com

[THANK YOU : You are one of our most loyal players!  
Get the best from Board Game Arena for only $5 / month.](https://boardgamearena.com/premium?src=premiumbar)

Top

### Help

### Contribute

### Follow us

Board Game Arena 1214 [Board Game Arena](https://boardgamearena.com/) • Release 241211-1628-ST • [Legal information](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=legal) • [Terms of Use](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tosv) • [Terms of Services](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=tos) • [Privacy](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=ppac) • [Cookies](https://boardgamearena.com/legal?section=cook) [π](#)

1

2

3

4

5

6

7

8

9

10

11

12
